<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dillon Creedon - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 03:30:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Dillon Creedon - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Article / Saving the Rhino: At What Cost?</title>
		<link>./../../../saving-the-rhino/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=saving-the-rhino</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2020 15:14:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Dillon Creedon]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=265</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> If you have ever seen a conservation advert on TV, chances are<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> it was either of a cute panda, a sad donkey or a rhino with its horn cut off<span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4>. These are the images that big conservation organisations show us in order to get money out of our wallets and into their bank accounts ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../saving-the-rhino/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Saving the &lt;br&gt;Rhino: At What Cost?&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="616" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rhino6-1-1024x616.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-565" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rhino6-1-1024x616.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rhino6-1-768x462.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rhino6-1-1536x925.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/rhino6-1-2048x1233.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>If you have ever seen a conservation advert on TV,&nbsp;chances are&nbsp;it was either a cute panda, a sad donkey, or a rhino with its horn cut off. These are the images that big conservation&nbsp;organisations&nbsp;show us in order to get money out of our wallets and into their bank accounts.&nbsp;Although&nbsp;scientific evidence supporting&nbsp;much of their conservation&nbsp;work&nbsp;is somewhat lacking,&nbsp;their marketing is spot on. The&nbsp;world’s&nbsp;biggest conservation&nbsp;organisation, for example, is now worth $6.5 billion.&nbsp;Academics have voiced their concerns over&nbsp;conservationists&nbsp;primary focus shifting from preserving biodiversity, to acquiring funding; regardless, they continue to grow.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Poaching is one key area&nbsp;conservationists&nbsp;are focusing on. The ‘poaching crisis’ is&nbsp;affecting&nbsp;species globally &#8211; but&nbsp;particularly&nbsp;in&nbsp;sub-Saharan Africa,&nbsp;black&nbsp;rhinos, which&nbsp;have dwindled from millions to thousands&nbsp;in the past century.&nbsp;The driving force behind the unprecedented increase in poaching is the&nbsp;ever-expanding illegal wildlife trade. At&nbsp;$65,000 per kilogram, rhino horn is worth more than both gold and heroin on the Vietnamese black market.&nbsp;Organised criminals&nbsp;have responded accordingly and&nbsp;are now&nbsp;using&nbsp;novel techniques to capture and traffic wildlife&nbsp;to the&nbsp;region.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="817" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pleftfinal7-817x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-553" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pleftfinal7-817x1024.jpg 817w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pleftfinal7-768x962.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pleftfinal7-1226x1536.jpg 1226w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pleftfinal7-1634x2048.jpg 1634w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/pleftfinal7.jpg 1987w" sizes="(max-width: 817px) 100vw, 817px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>So, what’s the best solution we have&nbsp;to curb the wildlife trade? Green&nbsp;militarisation. This involves arming park rangers, increasing military style surveillance, and incorporating AI and global communications systems into park security. If this all sounds quite dramatic, that’s because it is. In Kruger National Park, South Africa, the rhino poaching crisis reached a tipping point in 2012. An increase from 13 rhinos killed in 2008 to over 1200 in 2012 provoked a reaction from South Africa.</p>



<p>Former Major General&nbsp;Johan&nbsp;Jooste&nbsp;was appointed to the position of anti-poaching coordinator in 2012. Jooste’s&nbsp;long history in the armed forces and critical – if troubling – role in the&nbsp;‘apartheid&nbsp;wars’ secured him the role. His anti-poaching mantra was obvious from the outset: violence first, negotiation later.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
</div>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Jooste&nbsp;quickly&nbsp;bolstered&nbsp;defences and&nbsp;framed poaching as&nbsp;“a declaration of war against South Africa by armed foreign criminals”. Fences were erected, armed rangers were&nbsp;employed&nbsp;and surveillance planes scrambled.&nbsp;Ex-veterans from&nbsp;the global north flocked to the country to scratch their violent itch&nbsp;under the guise of&nbsp;conservation work.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Across the border in Mozambique, large tracts of land adjacent to Kruger National Park began to be bought or leased by South African businesses, foreign NGO’s, nation-states (Germany, the Netherlands, South Africa) and philanthropists. A new national park, the Greater Lebombo Conservancy, was created and swiftly militarised. Those who lived within this area, roughly the size of Dorset, where forcibly relocated to its borders, and subsistence hunting was outlawed. These people now join the 1 million+ other victims of biodiversity protection as ‘conservation refugees’. The park would act as a ‘buffer’ to the Kruger Park, discouraging Mozambicans from poaching and extending South Africa’s power beyond its borders. </p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="638" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/finalrightcrop3-1-638x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-549" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/finalrightcrop3-1-638x1024.jpg 638w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/finalrightcrop3-1-768x1233.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/finalrightcrop3-1-957x1536.jpg 957w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/finalrightcrop3-1-1276x2048.jpg 1276w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/finalrightcrop3-1.jpg 1551w" sizes="(max-width: 638px) 100vw, 638px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>Despite this mega-militarisation, the year following Jooste’s appointment saw a record-breaking number of rhinos killed and de-horned within Kruger Park. The consequences, however, were not restricted to the animal kingdom. Since the Lebombo Conservancy was created in 2012, over 300 (suspected) poachers have been killed. This forces us to question how effective ‘green&nbsp;militarisation’ really is, and raises some poignant moral dilemmas: is a rhino’s life, or the assurance of a rhino’s life, worth more than a human’s? Why is wildlife more valuable than human life in Africa, but not in the UK or the global north more generally? Perhaps it’s because we don’t have any spectacular wildlife worth protecting. Or, is it because poaching is a&nbsp;racialised&nbsp;crime in Africa, that a legacy of colonialism facilitates?&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interestingly, poaching rhinos is legal in South Africa for those rich white men who can afford the hunting licenses. The fatal consequences for some, and simple monetary exchange for others, is seen as cultural imperialism at its best, and a new form of colonialism at worst. Perhaps next time&nbsp;you see the rhino advert on TV you will question the agenda more critically. Are we saving rhinos, or are we exercising control comparable to that of colonists just 120 years ago?&nbsp;</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Writing by
<a href="./../../../index.html?tag=dillon-creedon" data-type="URL">Dillon Creedon</a> and illustrations by
<a href="./../../../index.html?tag=james-farrant" data-type="URL">James Farrant</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../saving-the-rhino/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Saving the &lt;br&gt;Rhino: At What Cost?&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
