<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Grace King - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 May 2021 15:42:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Grace King - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Short Story /  Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.2)</title>
		<link>./../../../birds-two/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=birds-two</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 15:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grace King]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Like most Londoners, Gary the pigeon held a permanent expression of being<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> mildly pissed off. To maintain his persona of relentless irritability </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4>, there was an abundance of things to be pissed off about ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../birds-two/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Short Story &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.2)&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-above-right">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Achingly tender, Stella was a star among seagulls. There were no words to describe the beauty she possessed. Her feathers were still damp from the fountain. She was all white apart from a line of feathers down by her neck that faded from white to grey. A sexy, discreet shade of grey. She stretched out her wings with a flirtatious flutter. She hadn’t imagined the first day after moving to the city would result in meeting a handsome stranger. He was gentle and introspective, qualities Stella admired in a bird. Not like all the cocks she’d met back in Brighton.</p>



<p>Gary had invited her on a tour of London and Stella felt like the unassuming star of a new Netflix rom-com.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3412" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-768x768.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-200x200.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1320x1320.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.sumweekly.com/birds-of-a">(Part 1 here)</a></p>
</div>
</div>



<p>The scope possibility was more tangible than ever. Her life was about to reach new heights and if the early bird gets the worm, Gary was ready to make this flighty decision for good.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>The number 24 floated north at a pleasantly drowsy speed. London was fully awake, but as Gary and Stella sat on the roof of the bus heading out of London’s epicentre, they were not overwhelmed by noise and flashing lights. Instead, skyscrapers turned to houses and businessmen to shop owners. Trafalgar became Oxford Circus which became Warren Street which morphed into Camden High Street. While they sat, they began to chat. They talked about home and about family. Stella was originally from Brighton. Raised as seaside gulls, London was an unfamiliar place to them. Stella told Gary about her dad who’d left for Devon when she was young for better chips. She told him about this guy she dated a year before you decided to leave for London. He was a pelican called Nigel who’d spent too many years alone at sea that he’d completely forgotten what commitment meant.</p>



<p>Gary listened enchanted. The inconsistencies, slurs and sloppiness of her speech was so endearing. He told her about his own family. His New York cousins, Berkshire Grandparents, Camden lads and Percy, the grime artist gone cuckoo. They talked about government, global ethics, whether the Marxist revolution will ever happen and if it will solve the problem of the bin strikes.</p>



<p>“I just sometimes feel as though everyone is forgetting how big the world actually is, and we just need to start being a bit more Bon Jovi, you know what I mean? It’s like what my nan used to say, God bless her, ‘Don’t be a tit, but have the courage of an eagle and eyes like a hawk’. She was right you know, I wish there were more birds like her in our skies. Have you ever been to New York to visit your cousins? I’d love to go to America! Heck of a long flight though! That’s another thing about my nan, that is, she never flew outside of Brighton. Not once. I don’t think that’s right, Gary. I mean, like, today. I came to London to take hold of my future and my music and here I am with you. Crazy, isn’t it?! S But anyway Gary, I really like you, I do. Not everyday you meet a pigeon who can show you around London on the top of the bus! Is this our stop?”</p>



<p>“Yeah,” Gary said.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>Finally, they arrived at the top of Primrose Hill. Before him Gary saw a city so full of colours his tiny pigeon head nearly exploded. Never had everything been in such high definition. People walking, sitting, running, talking, laughing, feeling. Gary wasn’t just some passive spectator, watching the world unfold around him, he was here with Stella under his wings, real and alive.</p>



<p>“Why do you think we met, Gary?” Stella asked, her question assuming a philosophical edge that Gary was uncertain of.</p>



<p>“I don’t know, Stella. But I’m happy we did. Whatever cosmic force is bringing us together, I’m grateful. If it’s just fate, then perhaps my opinion of determinism has brightened.”</p>



<p>“Oh Gary, you’re such a romantic! I wish I didn’t have to say goodbye.”</p>



<p>“Why do you mean?” Gary hadn’t meant for his voice to be so panicky, but as soon as the words were said, the air changed.</p>



<p>“I’m a seagull Gary! I eat candy floss 4 times a day, is candy floss even vegan?! You’re a city bird, a high-flying Londoner. This wouldn’t work.”</p>



<p>At that point, 16:32 Wednesday afternoon, Gary realised the meaning of life. The world is full of impossibilities, but we can choose to stay perched on our fears forever or we can spread our wings and fly straight through them. Some birds we’re willing to risk our lives for. Others fly right by. Gary knew he’d found the Robin to be his Batman.</p>



<p>“Stella, today has been the best day of my life. I don’t want it to end. You’re so beautiful and funny and kind and the way you pronounce ‘almond’ makes me laugh. I woke up this morning after an evening of sitting on a lamppost. Now I don’t ever want to sit down again! I want to fly everywhere, see everything! Come fly with me, Stella. What do you say?”</p>



<p>“Yeah, ok.” said Stella.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>Unlike most pigeon-seagull relationships, Gary and Stella find their differences bring them closer together rather than further apart. Gary migrated to Brighton and has enjoyed pioneering the gentrification of Brighton’s pier. Percy did not continue in the music industry and now lives in Waterloo station. Kelly died of a heart attack and Danny drank himself to death after having a nasty accident with a British Airways plane on his way home and falling, mouth open into the Atlantic.</p>



<p>London and Brighton are both places spilling with colours, without a dash of grey to be seen. This means for Gary that each morning when he wakes up, still with an expression of being mildly pissed off, he turns and sees Stella. She is a painting, iridescent with colour. She is hope, she is tomorrow.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Part 2 coming next week! To keep up with Graces&#8217;s work, follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gracelouiseking/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>, illustration by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sketchbook_of_verity/" data-type="URL">Verity Hayhow</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../birds-two/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Short Story &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.2)&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short Story / Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.1)</title>
		<link>./../../../birds-of-a/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=birds-of-a</link>
					<comments>./../../../birds-of-a/index.html#comments</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 10 Apr 2021 16:14:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grace King]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2892</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Like most Londoners, Gary the pigeon held a permanent expression of being<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> mildly pissed off. To maintain his persona of relentless irritability </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4>, there was an abundance of things to be pissed off about ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../birds-of-a/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Short Story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.1)&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-above-right">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Like most Londoners, Gary the pigeon held a permanent expression of being mildly pissed off. To maintain his persona of relentless irritability, there was an abundance of things to be pissed off about. The weather, Southern Rail, everything being expensive, immigrants, Southern Rail &#8211; the list continues. It was with this frame of mind that Gary reluctantly spread his wings, welcoming a new day already dry with disappointment. It was 7:23 on Wednesday morning and the air was soggy and smelt of petrol. Gary could hear the C2 bus rumble across the road, London remerging from what was probably an eventful night yet not in Gary’s memory. His night had involved sitting on top of a lamppost for five hours straight. It was a stale one-dimensional shade of grey.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="818" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/birb-818x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2896" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/birb-818x1024.jpg 818w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/birb-768x961.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/birb-1227x1536.jpg 1227w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/birb-1320x1652.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/birb.jpg 1637w" sizes="(max-width: 818px) 100vw, 818px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>Gary was born here, and he knew he’d die here. Only tourists truly believed London was this grand metropolis brimming with opportunity and cosmopolitan commercialism. London now was struggling to find its voice in a post-Brexit world and with a new Pret on every corner, things were looking hopeful. However, Gary knew otherwise. London was shedding a new skin, but no one knew if the beast beneath would be wonderful or monstrous. Gary remembered discussing the current political climate when his cousins from New York came and visited last summer. Arrogant, obnoxious birds, tweeting whatever came into their heads, he thought to himself. Yet even those Trans-Atlantic upstarts recognised the problems facing our world.</p>



<p>“Kelly will have KFC eight times a day if we let her!” cousin Danny remarked. His girlfriend Kelly stood aghast, her mouth full of skinny fries.</p>



<p>“Pigeon obesity has been on the rise ever since the 70s but no one is treating this as a national health risk. I think this is one of the biggest problems facing our world right now” Danny continued, “I noticed when we flew in the number of chicken shops around here has increased.”</p>



<p>“You know, actually, perhaps we should start taking control of our own diets. I mean, don’t you think it’s kind of psychopathic eating another species of bird, not miles unlike your own, that’s been deep fried, left for hours and then dumped on the pavement?” Gary questioned Danny with the thinly veiled judgment that all vegans inherently possess.</p>



<p>“Chickens are nothing like us, Gary, don’t act all high and mighty. Humans do it all the time. Rich and poor, ain’t the same brand of people. Democrats and Republicans, hardly the same species.”</p>



<p>Can’t disagree with that. Gary left Danny and Kelly outside of Chicken Cottage and took a 5-minute flight to the Hampstead Heath Farmers’ Market. He found a leftover apple and kale muffin, pecking it with a slightly deflated self-righteousness.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>It was 7:45 when Gary began to make his way to Trafalgar Square. He transcended the green expanses of Regents Park, briefly losing sight of Mornington Crescent’s dingy side alleys. With the sun peeking over the tops of buildings, the grey sky momentarily looked promising. However, Gary was a pigeon with poor imagination. His stubborn bird brain was unable to imagine a future with anything more glorious in it, than an Arsenal win over Tottenham in the greatest derby of all time. Instead, Gary was aware of how crap everything is. He wore the mantle of being so woke, life had become meaningless. He was disillusioned rather than revolutionary. He knew he was more spiritually, politically and educationally enlightened than most other pigeons, and this made him feel sad.</p>



<p>Gary’s social commentary continued as he flew solo through TheatreLand. Show after show promised dazzling sets and enchanting stories, enough to convince the most sombre of pigeons that life could be magical. But, Gary was flying low at 8:09 and there was nothing magical about London on its groggy wake up call.</p>



<p>Finally, Gary began his descent into Trafalgar Square. Each morning he would take a bird’s eye view of London situated upon the 169 feet and 3 inches of Nelson’s Column. And there he would offer his oblation to the Empire. He would crap on Nelson’s head. Bloody colonialism.</p>



<p>From that great height Gary could see from Big Ben to the London Eye to Buckingham Palace. Beneath him was the usual bustle of commuters crawling out of Charing Cross tube station. One or two buskers were setting up for the morning, checking guitar strings, warming their voices. It was 8:26 now. Gary, no longer astride Nelson’s head but firmly rooted on the ground, arched his neck back, distractedly rearranging his feathers. He realised he hadn’t had breakfast yet and so decided to amble along in search for any puddles of spilt coffee or the odd piece of sourdough toast. He hadn’t gone far when an incredibly offensive sound pierced the morning air. It was his least favourite musical collective: ‘Urban Vermin’.</p>



<p>“Oi Percy!” Gary yelled at the late pubescent pigeon named Percy. “Give it a rest, alright! Take a ride to Croydon, I’d love to see what the real birds of grime think of your bars.”</p>



<p>“Hello Gary!” Percy cheerily replied, enthusiastically waving his left wing over towards Gary. He was well-meaning, but more entitled than the peacocks of Holland Park. Everything had changed when he took a trip to Peru, met a free-thinking blue-and-gold macaw and totally found himself. Gary despised this kind of imported consciousness. His own awakening was home-grown and therefore much more genuine than this flight-risk tourist’s attitude.</p>



<p>“Whatever,” Gary answered. “Could you give it rest though mate?”</p>



<p>“I know you might not yet be a fan yet,” Percy acknowledged, “but as music evolves so does the pigeon. It started with 90s hip-hop, R+B, the spoken word poetry of London’s lowliest and now grime’s hit the scene and the channels between back garden and parliament have never been so accessible.”</p>



<p>“Fabulous. Sure. Whatever. ‘This is a movement not a moment’. Great. You’re from Haywards Heath, mate. Just calm down.”</p>



<p>Gary had been scanning his surroundings, not really looking at Percy at all during this little conversation when suddenly his eyes stopped as they reached the fountain. Then at 8:34 on Wednesday morning, Gary’s life changed forever.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>He remembered as a young pigeon visiting his paternal Grandparents in Berkshire on bank holiday weekends. His family were fortunate enough not to feel threatened by the mass shootings of rich men in tweed who still indulged in Tudor-esque delicacies, so these childhood memories always stayed pure in Gary’s mind. In fact, Gary remembered watching the sunrise on a clear Sunday morning across the wide-open fields and thinking this was the most beautiful thing he would ever see. But it turns out he was mistaken.</p>



<p>The sunlight glistened on the water in the fountain, full classical elegance. There in the centre of the foundation emerged a figure in white, beads of water cascading down her back. As David gazed upon Bathsheba, Gary became transfixed by this angelic creature. A rush of warmth flooded through his body like nothing he’d experienced before. She was divine. She was glowing. She was a seagull.</p>



<p>“Wow&#8230;she is a fit bird!” Percy wasn’t a feminist. “Hey Gary, be my wingman mate. “No.”</p>



<p>Gary stuck out a wing to stop the eager pigeon. This opportunity was too precious to let fly away. His Wednesday morning had just begun to open up. So, Gary stuck out a foot and made his way across Trafalgar Square.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>She was mid bird bath when Gary reached the fountain.“Respectful yet speak with initiative. Women don’t want to be told what they like and they</p>



<p><em>will </em>like someone who knows that. Just be intentionally nonchalant and don’t overthink.” This was Gary’s inner dialogue whilst he fluffed his feathers and sauntered over.</p>



<p>“Right, listen, I’ve had enough. You know this is a tough day for me and I deserve something to take my mind off things as much as anyone else. You’re supposed to be supporting me, not criticising my life choices!”</p>



<p>“Darling, you need to stop making such a fuss. If you need to go and make your break in the city, sobeit, just don’t blame me when it all goes south.”</p>



<p>“MUM! Honestly, you’re upsetting my aura and I cannot be dealing with this much negative energy so close to a Cancer full moon.”</p>



<p>Gary tried his best not to look too obvious as he listened over his shoulder to this mother and daughter spat. It appeared the angel of the fountain was facing a duel with her less liberal mother about flying the nest. Gary was not usually one to throw around gender stereotypes but it had often been the case that mother birds were guilty of suffocating their poor chicks with a constant clucking that would drive any woman insane.</p>



<p>“I actually can’t deal with this right now.” “Oh honestly, stop being so dramatic!”</p>



<p>“No, mum, I need some space. I’ll meet you back on the hospital roof later but right now I need to explore my journey without your toxic energy.”</p>



<p>“If you say so, dear.”</p>



<p>With an unflattering grunt, the old bird lifted into the sky and made her way to goodness knows where.</p>



<p>The younger seagull sat whimsically by the water. It was now or now or never for Gary and he felt his chances for an introduction growing smaller and smaller. With a flash he saw himself tomorrow morning, Thursday, the same stale air, the same bleak prospects. This future was not what Gary envisioned. Life could not be so cruel. He had to make his dreams come because if not, who would?</p>



<p>“Hey, I heard you’ve come to the city for your big break? Would you be happy with me asking exactly what you’re hoping to pursue?”</p>



<p>Was that too forward? Confident or creepy? Gary could never tell.</p>



<p>“Oh, yeah, I’m a singer-songwriter originally from Brighton. I’m kinda on a R’n’B, gospel, indie, alt slightly punk with soft jazzy undertones kinda vibe. But I’m also experimenting with freestyle grime. Do you want to hear some?”</p>



<p>The deja vu sent shivers down Gary’s spine. He quickly glanced to see if Percy was still in his eyeline but ‘Urban Vermin’ had finally dispersed. The dream was beginning to shatter but being British he felt compelled to smile and say “sure!” with perfectly fake enthusiasm.</p>



<p>The sound that came out of the angel’s beak was not what Gary expected. When humans hear seagulls singing they usually wince at the high pitched wail but when the seagull song reaches a pigeon’s eardrum, something magical happens.</p>



<p>Gary firmly did not believe in love at first sight. But the sound of this song changed everything he knew to be real. Love was pumping through his little pigeon veins. It was as if the world stopped spinning.</p>



<p>Hordes of foreign exchange students milled around the Square, some draping themselves across the Lions, others obnoxiously using selfie sticks, or watching street entertainers not quite entertain the crowds. They had come to London to see if it was like in the movies. Hard and gritty, but full of adventures and romance. Gary realised that for London to appear to be all these things, there must be something behind it. Something real to make the fiction believable. And for these happy endings to exist, pigeons like Gary must make them.</p>



<p>“It’s just a demo but what do you think?”“I love you. It! I love IT! Great! Amazing! Such depth! What’s your name by the way?” If seagulls could blush, this one was.“Stella. I’m Stella”.“Hi Stella, I’m Gary.”&#8230;</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Part 2 coming next week! To keep up with Graces&#8217;s work, follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gracelouiseking/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>, illustration by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sketchbook_of_verity/" data-type="URL">Verity Hayhow</a>.
</div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../birds-of-a/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Short Story&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.1)&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>./../../../birds-of-a/feed/index.html</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>1</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
