<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Yusuf Ali - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 27 Apr 2021 12:22:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Yusuf Ali - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Food / When the Maql&#173;ouba is Flip&#173;ped</title>
		<link>./../../../maqlouba/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=maqlouba</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yusuf Ali]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> When the Maqlouba is flipped, you will almost always let out a cheer of joy<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>. The large silver pot is turned upside down on the table and everyone</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> gathers round eagerly waiting for the reveal. Will the shape of the rice hold together? What has the cook put inside this particular ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../maqlouba/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Food &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;When the Maql&shy;ouba is Flip&shy;ped&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3242" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-768x768.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-200x200.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1320x1320.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>When the Maqlouba is flipped, you will almost always let out a cheer of joy. The large silver pot is turned upside down on the table and everyone gathers round eagerly waiting for the reveal. Will the shape of the rice hold together? What has the cook put inside this particular version? The pot is lifted and the beautiful dish is revealed. There are different variations of maqlouba, but to describe it simply, it is a dish of Palestinian origin (which is also found across the Levant) consisting of rice, vegetables, and often meat. </p>



<p>It is arranged in layers and steamed to create a beautiful mould inside the pot. It is then flipped to serve, with the key ingredients cooked at the bottom to then appear at the top for the guests to marvel at. There are a few main variations of Maqlouba; chicken, lamb, fish and also vegetarian. The differences will appear with their own array of vegetables that pair well, as well as being dependent on its region. For instance, Maqlouba with fish is most commonly served in the south of Palestine due to the abundance of fish on the coast. This is similar to many regional dishes such as Jollof rice which will be prepared using different ingredients depending on the country you eat it in.</p>



<p>When the Maqlouba is flipped, we see the layers of its history, layers which have dated back to around the 12th Century. A popular story of its origin refers to the conquest of Jerusalem by Salaheddin Al Ayubbi. A very significant figure in the 12th Century, he was the founder of the Ayubbid empire, which at the height of its power ruled over large parts of the Levantine region. When he entered Jerusalem, he was greeted by the locals with the dish. </p>



<p>At the time it was referred to as ‘bazenjaniyah’, coming from the root word of ‘Bazenjan’ which means Aubergine in classical Arabic, a key ingredient in the dish. When Salaheddin saw the theatrical motion of the pot being flipped, he renamed the dish ‘Maqlouba’ which literally means inverted/upside down. Naturally, this dish has grown to mean more than the ingredients it contains. People of all faiths who have descended from centuries of lineage in Jerusalem will view Maqlouba as a symbol of their right to the city.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When the Maqlouba is flipped, it exudes an energy of defiance and symbolism which is unparalleled. During the Trump presidency, he recognised Jerusalem as the capital of Israel, a decision which was heavily contested in the region. Jerusalem is a heavily controlled region and so while physical protests would be strongly controlled, Maqlouba was used as a symbolic form of protest. Women sat outside of the walls of the Al-Aqsa mosque, flipping pots of maqlouba and serving it to the demonstrators. In any other circumstance this may be seen as a very common practice of support.</p>



<p>However, knowing the history of this dish we can see that they were using Maqlouba as a metaphor, serving the dish as it was served to their historical leader Salaheddin. A subtle but powerful message that they will always hold the city to be theirs. Maqlouba isn’t the only food which is used as a form of protest; watermelons have also been used in opposition to the IDF soldiers. Palestinians have previously walked the streets of Jerusalem with watermelons cut open. The vibrant reds, blacks and greens of the watermelon bearing the colours of the flag which is disallowed from being raised in certain areas.</p>



<p>While the issues between Palestine and Israel have remained a subject of the highest controversy in society&#8217;s discourse, it does not take away from the main messages raised in this piece. As I mentioned in <a href="https://www.sumweekly.com/fried-chicken">‘The Fried Chicken Stereotype’</a>, food holds the value it does because of our personal connection to it. Through the African Americans, fried chicken meant survival, and was one of the only forms of economic growth immediately after the emancipation. For the Palestinians, Maqlouba is a physical representation of their right to their home. The knowledge that a dish which you hold central to your identity, outlives modern conflicts by centuries is a tool more powerful than any signed law.</p>



<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1gjhocgQ5Wc" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Yusufs Maqlouba Recipe:</span></p>



<ul class="marginbottom"><li>600 bone-in chicken pieces</li><li>2 Tbspn Salt</li><li>1 Tbspn Black Pepper</li><li>1 Tbspn Cumin</li><li>1 Tbspn Cardamom Powder</li><li>1 Tbspn Pimento Powder</li><li>1 Tbspn Cinnamon Powder</li><li>1 Tbspn Coriander Powder</li><li>1 Head of Cauliflower</li><li>500g Potatoes</li><li>3 Medium Carrots</li><li>300g Basmati Sella Rice</li><li>2 tbsp toasted pine nuts</li></ul>
</div>
</div>



<p>1. Season your chicken using all the spices and fry in a large pot before covering with water and allowing it to boil.</p>



<p>2. Soak the rice in cold water for 25 mins</p>



<p>3. Whilst the chicken is boiling, cut up your veg into small pieces, fry until gold.</p>



<p>4. Remove the chicken from the water and cook the rice 75% of the way in the same water. Drain the rice and reserve half a glass of the stock.</p>



<p>5. Layer a wide pot with the veg at the bottom, chicken, and then sprinkle the rice on top, packing down. Cover with a small amount of stock so the bottom doesn’t stick and simmer for 20 minutes.</p>



<p>6. LET IT REST for 10-15 mins before flipping onto a plate or tray, carefully lifting the pot and garnishing with pine nuts.</p>



<div id="footer">Yusuf makes fantasic, insightful videos on the art of cooking, recipes and the history behind food, which you can find on his YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaPzQQzAG_dXEDXNxbfAPsA" data-type="URL">&#8216;Sliced&#8217;</a>. You can also follow him on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sliced_yt/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagam</a> to keep updated with his work.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../maqlouba/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Food &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;When the Maql&shy;ouba is Flip&shy;ped&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / The Fried Chicken Stereo&#173;type</title>
		<link>./../../../fried-chicken/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=fried-chicken</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 28 Jan 2021 00:54:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yusuf Ali]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=974</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap>Imagine if I were to ask you to compare any dish from your ancestral<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> homeland, to a similar dish from a nearby region, country, or even city. I am sure that you<span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> you would jump to say with an utmost certainty that the food hailing from your region is superior. Is it because you have ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../fried-chicken/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;The Fried Chicken Stereo&shy;type&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="697" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/chichenimg1-1024x697.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1035" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/chichenimg1-1024x697.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/chichenimg1-768x523.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/chichenimg1-1536x1046.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/chichenimg1.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Imagine if I were to ask you to compare any dish from your ancestral homeland, to a similar dish from a nearby region, country, or even city. I am sure that you would jump to say with&nbsp;utmost certainty that the food hailing from your region is superior. Is it because you have objectively compared the methods of preparation, seasoning, textures and aromas that have gone into each of the dishes? Of course not. We love the food that we do because at its core, the value of food isn’t within the physical preparation, but in the centuries of culture, struggle, and beauty that manifests itself within each dish. &nbsp;</p>



<p>This thought is one of the inspirations behind my YouTube series:&nbsp;<em>The Origin of Food</em>. I believe that if we use food as a common ground point of discussion, we can achieve a far more effective and positive way of educating people about cultures.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The fried chicken stereotype: a stereotype so common that we were all aware of it growing up. The stereotype that&nbsp;Black&nbsp;people, specifically African Americans, love eating fried chicken. On the surface, there doesn’t seem to be any negative connotations with this statement. However, we all know that it is generally said with a condescending and derogatory tone. So how did this stereotype come about? Furthermore, what if I told you that if you read into the history of fried chicken, you would actually come to see it as a remarkable symbol for resistance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Going back over excerpts from African American slave journals, we can gather a fair image of the type of diet they were fed by the slave owners. Most of the meat which they would have been given would be discarded from the main cuts that the owners would eat. Undesirable cuts such as entrails of pigs, neck and rear cuts of cattle etc. Chickens would be the best chance of having a decent cut of meat as they were the cheapest animals for the plantation owners to discard.&nbsp;Enslaved people that were&nbsp;given such a lowly ration would have to do a lot to it&nbsp;in order to&nbsp;make it both palatable, and highly calorific. This is where frying comes into it. By taking pieces of seasoned, breaded chicken and frying them in cauldrons of hot oil over fires, they were able to increase the value of this and aid their chances of survival. While this may seem like a strong form of survival on their plantation, it is important to remember that many cooking techniques which the&nbsp;enslaved Africans&nbsp;had learnt, was not from the US, but from their motherland. West Africans already had a tradition of frying meat in hot oil, cooking with yams and native greens etc.  &nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns" id="fcsmidcol">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>We can see through this that no matter how much of their identity the slave owners tried to strip away, the core elements of their culture could never be removed. Where they used yams in Africa, they found sweet potatoes in America, and collard greens became their newfound plant. The resilience of African Americans was so powerful that they created an entire cuisine off the back of the oppression which they faced. &nbsp;</p>



<p>Fast forward to the days of emancipation and African Americans were faced with the challenge of surviving in a country which still didn’t view them as free. While they may have been able to walk freely, they were restricted from certain rights such as owning cattle.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="975" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lickinchickin-1-1024x975.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1022" title="fcsblock" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lickinchickin-1-1024x975.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lickinchickin-1-768x731.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lickinchickin-1-1536x1462.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/lickinchickin-1.jpg 1772w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>
</div>
</div>



<p>This meant&nbsp;that&nbsp;many&nbsp;entrepreneurs raised chickens on farms, selling their meat&nbsp;and also&nbsp;frying chicken as a means of business. In the face of oppression, the success grew within the African American community, something which was met with resistance from the right wing. There were many attempts to paint this narrative that African Americans had better lives as slaves, and as freed individuals were lazy and uncouth. </p>



<p>In 1915, a film called ‘Birth of a Nation’ was released; a film which came from the minds of the KKK and which was pivotal in the creation of the fried chicken stereotype.&nbsp;There is a scene within it which features ‘The Negro party in control of the State House of Representatives’. Through this, the viewer sees an awful depiction of African Americans with their bare feet up over court room desks, eating greasy fried chicken with their bare hands, and behaving in an&nbsp;‘uncivilised’&nbsp;way. It is important to note that the average&nbsp;white&nbsp;American during this time had not owned slaves and were simply forming their understanding of&nbsp;Black&nbsp;people through the way in which they were being depicted by the elite class of the US. This film would go on to undermine the success of African Americans and create a vilifying caricature which would go on for over a century. A food which was so powerful and significant, completely flipped around to become a negative stereotype which bears significance even today.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is not enough for us to teach the next generation the simple lesson, ‘don’t be racist’, simply because it does not erase these latent stereotypes that exist within us all. Instead,&nbsp;we must look into the stories surrounding these misconceptions, and not just unlearn them, but to relearn the true history.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The truth is that soul food is one of the greatest acts of defiance and resilience in the face of oppression. Where African Americans had no voice, no freedom, and no power; soul food existed as the steppingstone to freedom, with fried chicken at the forefront.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="998" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/boilingpot-2-998x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1037" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/boilingpot-2-998x1024.jpg 998w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/boilingpot-2-768x788.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/boilingpot-2-1497x1536.jpg 1497w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/boilingpot-2.jpg 1666w" sizes="(max-width: 998px) 100vw, 998px" /></figure>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Yusuf&#8217;s Fried Chicken Burger&nbsp;Recipe:&nbsp;</span></p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<ul><li>8 Boneless Chicken Thighs</li><li>1&nbsp;Tbsp&nbsp;Salt</li><li>1&nbsp;Tbsp&nbsp;Black Pepper</li><li>1&nbsp;Tbsp&nbsp;Cayenne Pepper</li><li>1&nbsp;Tspn&nbsp;Garlic Powder</li><li>1&nbsp;Tspn&nbsp;Onion Powder</li><li>3&nbsp;Tbspn&nbsp;Mayo</li><li>1 Tbspn&nbsp;Siracha</li><li>1&nbsp;Tbspn&nbsp;Honey</li><li>500ml Buttermilk</li><li>250g Plain Flour&nbsp;</li><li>Brioche Buns</li><li>Gherkins</li><li>Baby Gem Lettuce</li><li>1L Vegetable Oil&nbsp;</li></ul>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column"></div>
</div>



<ol><li>&nbsp;Mix the mayo, sriracha, and&nbsp;honey together to form a sweet and spicy mayo.</li><li>Add half the dry rub to the chicken thighs and mix half in with the flour. </li><li>Once marinated, add the chicken into buttermilk. Once coated it can be used straight away or left to tenderise overnight</li><li>Coat the chicken pieces in flour, making sure that it is thoroughly covered.</li><li>Heat the oil to a medium high heat, and drop the chicken in, in small batches. Fry until golden on both sides and the chicken is thoroughly cooked.</li><li>Toast the brioche buns and spread with an even layer of mayo on both sides.</li><li>Slice the gherkins lengthways and layer on the buns along with the lettuce. Add the chicken on top and serve.&nbsp;</li></ol>



<div id="footer">Yusuf makes fantasic, insightful videos on the art of cooking, recipes and the history behind food, which you can find on his YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaPzQQzAG_dXEDXNxbfAPsA" data-type="URL">&#8216;Sliced&#8217;</a>. You can also follow him on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sliced_yt/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagam</a> to keep updated with his work.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../fried-chicken/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;The Fried Chicken Stereo&shy;type&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
