<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Jacob May - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Nov 2021 20:27:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Jacob May - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Music / Jacob May</title>
		<link>./../../../jacob-may/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=jacob-may</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2021 22:47:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jacob May]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=4811</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> From popping up at jazz jams with his trombone to keeping the rhythm section tight <span id=span1>...</span><span id=span2>. with his bass guitar, multi-instrumentalist Jacob seems to be </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> everywhere at the moment. In between showcasing his impressive array …<span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../jacob-may/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Music&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Jacob May&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure id="inlinevideo" class="wp-block-video marginbottom"><video controls src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacobsumsite.mp4"></video></figure>



<p>From popping up at jazz jams with his trombone to keeping the rhythm section tight with his bass guitar, multi-instrumentalist Jacob seems to be everywhere at the moment. In between showcasing his impressive array of beats and giving his best blue-steel impression, he gave us an insight into life as a musician…</p>



<p><strong>Introduce yourself, who are you and what do you do?</strong></p>



<p>My name is Jacob May. I am an 18 year old vocalist, multi-instrumentalist and producer.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-above-right">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>What are your aspirations as a musician and how are you going to get there?</strong></p>



<p>Eventually I want to sell my own music in my own name, or as a group amongst friends if I’m lucky enough. The perfect example would be Ezra Collective.</p>



<p>You see people like <em>Joe Armon-Jones</em> in the group who is also killing it with his own personal projects, not to mention <em>Femi Koleoso</em>, who was previously <em>Jorja Smith</em>’s drummer and is now part of<em> Gorillaz</em></p>



<p><strong>What was the last song you listened to that made you feel something?</strong></p>



<p>I can’t lie man, while having a proper dig back into some old <em>Alfa Mist</em>, there was something about<em> ‘Falling’ </em>featuring <em>Kaya Thomas-Dyke</em> on vocals, off his album ‘Structuralism’, that made me so emotionally attached to so many different things. </p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="683" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-6resized-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4813" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-6resized-683x1024.jpg 683w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-6resized-768x1152.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-6resized-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-6resized-1320x1980.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-6resized.jpg 1366w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>Whether that be the songwriting, the instrumentation or how the music was sonically. Whenever I listen to ‘Falling’ I get goosebumps every time, leaving me inspired to look more into sound design and have more of a range of instruments in my music.</p>



<p><strong>Give me a your ideal band, you&#8217;re playing bass, who are the others?</strong></p>



<p>I’ve been thinking about this a lot lately after numerous conversations with people who are keen to get writing and making some music. I’d look at my lineup in two ways. The way I’m looking to write music is both with my vocals and also instrumental. </p>



<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-above-left">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="683" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-10resized-1-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4819" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-10resized-1-683x1024.jpg 683w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-10resized-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-10resized-1-1024x1536.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-10resized-1-1320x1980.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-10resized-1.jpg 1366w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>This is heavily inspired by a saxophonist and producer named <em>Venna</em>. He has a project out which is part instrumental and part vocal. So, in an instrumental situation, I’d be on bass, my friend <a href="https://www.instagram.com/luciamusicc/">Lucia</a>, would be on keys, vocals and trumpet. I’d have my bro <a href="https://www.instagram.com/lox_drumz/">Ebz</a> on drums and then the one and only <a href="https://www.instagram.com/benglassermusic/">Ben Glasser</a> on electric guitar.</p>



<p>In a situation where I’d be on vocals, I’m absolutely spoiled for choice for a bassist. I could have <a href="https://www.instagram.com/kavitron.exe/">Kavi</a>, <a href="https://www.instagram.com/kobeheathngugi/">Kobe </a>or <a href="https://www.instagram.com/patchsawyer/">Patch</a> on bass, in a situation where they could all take part or have gigs at a time because they’re all killing bassists and amazing people.</p>



<p>This also made me think about how when I’m not singing, I could also hop on trombone, for a melody or when soloing. I feel like this group could really hold it down well. It gets me excited just speaking about it, let alone actually playing with them.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p><strong>Do you feel nervous before a gig? How do you cope?</strong></p>



<p>My honest answer is, no, not really. Since I’ve started doing gigs, I’ve kept this mentality of ‘treat it just like practice’ and I almost picture as if not a single person is there watching me, so I have nothing to worry about. While having good energy on stage is key, I‘ve really been working on holding it down and keeping things simple.</p>



<p><strong>How do you feel about the future?</strong></p>



<p>I’m quite excited about what the future holds. Every now and then it’s very easy to get ahead of myself and have flashes of seeing my name in shining lights, going on tour, the things you dream of as a musician. But, obviously, these things don’t come without grit, determination and hard work. So, right now I’m just trying my best to stay grounded, continuing to work hard, taking the right paths and guidance from people, with the hopes of achieving big and that good things come my way eventually.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-7resized-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4816" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-7resized-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-7resized-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-7resized-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-7resized-2048x1365.jpg 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacob-7resized-1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<div id="footer"> 
Keep track of Jacob via his <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jacobm4y/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>, Jacob will also be playing with rising Neo-soul star Saffiyah on the 28th of November.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../jacob-may/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Music&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Jacob May&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/jacobsumsite.mp4" length="30272532" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
