<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Thuli Jane Maseko - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 13:43:46 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Thuli Jane Maseko - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Article / Peak Privil&#173;ege</title>
		<link>./../../../peak-privilege/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=peak-privilege</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Jane Maseko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=4975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> There are just so many things in this single event that are almost inconceivable for a non-white person to<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>get away with. There are things the legal system afforded Kyle</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> that it would rarely extend to others. The response from police and a justice system that not only punishes POC perpetrators more harshly but goes so far...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../peak-privilege/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Peak Privil&shy;ege&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5001" width="823" height="548" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 823px) 100vw, 823px" /><figcaption><em>Rittenhouse during the court case (Nam Y. Huh via AP)</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>There are just so many things in this single event that are almost inconceivable for a non-white person to get away with. There are things the legal system afforded Kyle that it would rarely extend to others. The response from police and a justice system that not only punishes POC perpetrators more harshly but goes so far as to actively vilify these groups, even targeting the innocent, of letting off a man (with sympathy) after he killed two people is probably the starkest display of white privilege I’ve seen in a while.</p>



<p>Many of us were likely in that familiar mindset of being wholly unsurprised yet still feeling a painful sense of injustice. The verdict isn’t the (only) thing that triggers such feelings. It’s the entire system that enabled not only a not guilty verdict to be reached, but that also enabled Kyle to leave Kenosha alive after entering with a semi-automatic weapon and shooting three people.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="847" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1024x847.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4988" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1024x847.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-768x635.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1536x1271.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1320x1092.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2.jpg 1610w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption><em>Kyle Rittenhouse alongside another armed &#8220;Property Defender&#8221;  [Adam Rogan via AP]</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Probably the most obvious place to start in differentiating how law enforcement treats Black bodies and white bodies is Kyle Rittenhouse walking up to police with a rifle. It’s almost inconceivable that a Black person would make it past police officers carrying a gun, especially when Black people, younger and smaller than Kyle, have been killed by police who even just suspected they were armed. And when Black people are legally armed, their Second Amendment right is very rarely respected or defended with the same gusto (recall Philando Castile).&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Kyle’s not subject to profiling in the same way POC groups are, he’s therefore more humanised, more individualised, and thus, more sympathetic. That’s what allowed the defense to put him on the stand with confidence, what allowed him to be seen as a young man with a future etc etc…</p>



<p>why people will see him as someone who wanted to serve his community and not a violent, pesky instigator. Conservatism and white supremacy also play a role here, as the victims were white but not an “acceptable” whiteness by the conscious or unconscious standards of these groups.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4985" width="396" height="461"/><figcaption><em>Rittenhouse&#8217;s Mugshot [Antioch Police Department via AP]</em></figcaption></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>These were white people who had aligned themselves with Black Lives Matter and were threats to what white supremacy and the American system wants to uphold. Their rejection despite being white illustrates the institutional conservatism that permeates these systems along with the institutional racism. We saw this to the extent that Judge Bruce Schroeder didn’t allow those killed to be referred to as victims, because the term was considered too “loaded,” but said that they could be called “looters,” “rioters” and “arsonists”, as if these weren’t loaded terms that would influence a jury in any way.</p>



<p>The victims of the shootings are not offered the same grace as having acted in self-defence, either. After seeing someone kill a man, they pursued&nbsp; him, fired warning shots and attempted to disarm him, yet Kyle was seen as the party in danger. Compared to the actions of the protestors it’s Kyle’s that stand out as more unreasonable, violent and aggressive, but he has the armour of white boyhood and the status quo, so this was never going to be part of the narrative.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4992" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-768x432.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-1056x594.jpg 1056w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption><em>Whitewashing on Fox News</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The acceptance of Kyle in both mainstream and conservative circles also highlights the conservative context in which the killings and trial took place and how these add to Kyle’s privilege index. Republican senators are offering him jobs, Tucker Carlson did an interview, and far right groups are citing the case as setting a precedent for vigilante action. His attaining martyrdom status among Republican, mainstream and far right extremist groups, and that going largely unquestioned, is an important backdrop to Kyle&#8217;s acquittal.</p>



<p>Imagine if an official came out hailing the Nation of Islam or the Black Panthers as heroes… Attitudes towards non-white groups, extremist or otherwise, have historically been a lot more damning form law enforcement, government and society. Despite white supremacy and white supremacist groups being acknowldedged by the FBI as possibly the most dangerous domestic threat to the United States, a disproportionate amount of time and resources continue to be spent on the comparative over-policing and over-surveillance of non-white groups and individuals.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="695" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1024x695.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4994" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1024x695.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-768x521.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1536x1043.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1320x896.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy.jpg 1950w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption><meta charset="utf-8"><em>Judge Bruce Schroeder during the case [Pool via Getty Images]</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Kyle is given the benefit of the doubt. Instead of being considered a chaos tourist, right-wing counter protestor looking for trouble or even just someone who’s not where he was supposed to be, he’s seen as the victim who had to defend himself against looting aggressors. Black folk have been treated more suspiciously for being in their own neighbourhoods and colleges.</p>



<p>It’s that same benefit of the doubt that lets a mass shooter be bought Burger King or a rapist have their swim times published, because somewhere inside them people see a good young man with a future, a future white observers are invested in for one reason or another. The point is it’s their shared whiteness that forms the root of this investment, which factors into why we see disproportionate outcomes in the justice system, why Black men receive sentences up to 20 percent longer than whites for the same crimes, why Chrystul Kizer is still awaiting trial and facing life in prison.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are things Kyle gets because he’s white that other groups don’t, things that oftentimes the system is designed for POC not to get. Kyle can claim all he wants that this all has “nothing to do with race,” but that’s an ignorant position that itself comes from a place of privilege. He had told interviewers “part of my job is to protect people. If someone is hurt, I&#8217;m running into harm&#8217;s way.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="629" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1024x629.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4981" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1024x629.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-768x472.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1536x944.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1320x811.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1.jpg 1758w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>It could be said that the protestors were following a similar logic; running into harm&#8217;s way after seeing someone hurt, but neither them nor their cause are afforded the same level of sympathy or justice. They were looters, rioters and arsonists. Kyle was doing his duty, protecting private property (another ideal that’s politically, economically and racially loaded). He was helping others, supporting the blue badge, doing what a young American should. He was a white boy upholding whiteness, and he was most certainly not going to be punished for that.&nbsp;</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Thuli Jane Maseko, to keep up with her work follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thuliijane" data-type="URL">Intagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../peak-privilege/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Peak Privil&shy;ege&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Art / Nachael Catnott</title>
		<link>./../../../nachael-catnott/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=nachael-catnott</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 19:06:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Art]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Jane Maseko]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Nachael Catnott]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=4930</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[
<div id=spanwrap> Nachael Catnott is a Black British-Caribbean Artist and Experimental Filmmaker living in <span id=span1>...</span><span id=span2> South London. Nachael focuses on documenting historic and modern<span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> relationships between people and places, whilst conceptually evaluating the current …<span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../nachael-catnott/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Art&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Nachael Catnott&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="878" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved1final-878x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4939" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved1final-878x1024.jpg 878w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved1final-768x896.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved1final-1316x1536.jpg 1316w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved1final-1320x1540.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved1final.jpg 1756w" sizes="(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="878" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved2-final-2-878x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4940" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved2-final-2-878x1024.jpg 878w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved2-final-2-768x896.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved2-final-2-1316x1536.jpg 1316w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved2-final-2-1320x1540.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Evolved2-final-2.jpg 1756w" sizes="(max-width: 878px) 100vw, 878px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>Nachael Catnott is a Black British-Caribbean Artist and Experimental Filmmaker living in South London. Nachael focuses on documenting historic and modern relationships between people and places, whilst conceptually evaluating the current and evolving social-political landscape.</p>



<p>“I have a passion for producing dynamic and thought-provoking content that engages with diverse audiences. My practice is intent on addressing issues such as race, class, heritage and gender through a multitude of mediums namely, film, photography, performance and sculpture.”</p>



<p>We sat down with Nachael for an extended interview, exploring her work, accessibility and how a yam became a re-ocurring symbol in her work…</p>



<p><strong>Talk to me a bit about South London and your work</strong></p>



<p>I think in general a lot of my work is interested in giving a voice to underrepresented people and trying to find out stories or histories or identities that people might not have that much information about. That started during my BA where I started to look more into my own personal identity. I started using yam as a reference and a symbol of the black experience and the presence of multiculturalism in Britain.</p>



<p>Ultimately for me, coming from South London, that’s kind of my foundation; that’s where I had the experience of growing up with so many different people from different walks of life&#8230; predominantly in an area like Lewisham, you do have such a class spectrum as well and just so many different nationalities; I think that’s why it’s at the heart of a lot of what I do.</p>



<p>And I think it’s just a case of being from a place like south London, I feel like for me I’ve always been trying to sort of show what we can do.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="573" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour-1-2-1024x573.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4963" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour-1-2-1024x573.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour-1-2-768x430.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour-1-2-1536x860.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour-1-2-1320x739.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>How do you decide what goes into a piece?</strong></p>



<p>I guess it’s a feeling. The red puffer jacket series came about through my interest in fashion and the adaptation and appropriation of fashion items. Fast fashion especially has taken a lot from streetwear and what used to be associated with working class people. I just think it’s interesting with the flow of society how a lot of these references are now kind of everyday things. And you’re seeing references to different cultures in high fashion with what I feel like is not the right reference, which is where we lead into the exploitation and the appropriation side of things.</p>



<p>With Daughters of Hannah there’s references to my recent journey into spirituality. We went to that same church school &#8211; everyone thinks it’s really random but that was a journey going there! So there’s a lot of reference there to my personal journey with spirituality, also making references to different religions and how they combine, and using the yam as kind of this anchor.</p>



<p>I’m just interested in a lot of the conversations that I have and I think in the last year I’ve been more interested in trying to create a more positivity led black experience. Naturally lots of the documentaries I’ve worked on tend to have some references to the struggle because I think that’s kind of the start of a lot of people’s stories, especially people of colour, so I wanted to create a more positive outlook on blackness.</p>



<p>A big reference for me is, because I’ve lived and grown up here, being a third generation of migrants. A lot of my references can only come though second hand information, whether it’s those conversations I’m having with my granddad or when I go and visit the Caribbean when get to do so.</p>



<p>Also the internet or books, secondary sources really, so I guess I’m also interested in looking at those connections, whether it’s beach landscapes that I have access to in the UK versus, I guess, the Homeland. There’s a lot of trying to find those pockets of spaces in Britain.</p>



<p><strong>Do you find not having access to those ancestral spaces as a member of the diaspora something limiting or empowering in your work?</strong></p>



<p>I feel like there’s been this shift, especially with the rise in politics around BLM. I think there’s been this embracing, especially within the Caribbean community, of what is the wider diaspora and with African heritage. It feels like there’s more of a community coming together.</p>



<p>No one questions when I make reference to Africa in my work because I’ve always had the knowledge, whether that’s through my parents talking about the struggle, whether it’s slavery, whether it’s ancestry… I’ve always been very interested in my wider ancestry and heritages.</p>



<p>I definitely feel like since using predominantly yam as a medium I’ve been able to lean more into the diaspora and have my work feel like it has a presence within that community if you know what I mean.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection2-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4944" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection2-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection2-768x432.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection2-1536x864.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection2-1056x594.jpg 1056w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection2-1320x743.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>Do you ever feel that the discrimination that comes with being Black can hinder how freely you can express yourself in your work?</strong></p>



<p>That’s interesting because I had an ‘in conversation’ session with an artist called Janette Parris &#8211; she’s a Goldmiths alumni and a renowned artist, and she now lives and practices in the South London area &#8211; and she was speaking about how it’s almost like as soon as you’re a black artist, suddenly your work has to be hyper-political. Like you can’t just paint flowers, it suddenly becomes ‘black artist paints flowers’, and you become this political symbol, your art becomes this political symbol, just because you’re black.</p>



<p>Daniel Kaluuya said the same thing about just wanting to be an actor and I think he got dragged for that because people were like “oh you’re supposed to be this champion, you’re meant to stand for the black kings” and he wasn’t saying he’s not happy to do that…</p>



<p>When you look at so many shows I used to watch when I was younger in the black section of Netflix, and back in the day it would just be a rom-com but now it’s a ‘black’ love story. That’s what’s really interesting: it becomes quite hard to categorise, because obviously in one breath we’re advocating for more inclusivity and black stories but we don’t want to, within that, be marginalised and turned into this one trick pony.</p>



<p>And I think at the moment a lot of my work naturally has reference to race because at the moment I’ve used, or it’s been easier to use, my own identity to investigate what’s going on in the political climate. It just so happens that we’re going through another epidemic or continued epidemic when it comes to racism, so then the work becomes more poignant and it feels more political than it actually probably is. Whereas a lot of the work, especially for me recently, is becoming more like self-discovery.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="577" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection1-1024x577.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4943" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection1-1024x577.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection1-768x433.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection1-1536x865.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection1-1056x594.jpg 1056w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Recollection1-1320x743.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>You still do work in these institutions; have you seen any changes in the institutional landscape when it comes to art schools/the arts and diversity?</strong></p>



<p>It was quite interesting because there were points throughout my education here I could just count the black people or people of colour on my hand in spaces; I call it the Where’s Wally analogy, where you walk into a space and you start counting the black people. It almost starts as a joke but then you start doing it unconsciously and you’re like ‘oh snap, I’m doing that thing again.’ Throughout art school we were in the minority, and I remember having a conversation with someone being like ‘oh well, you know, they don’t apply’ and me thinking that’s not justification anymore&#8230;</p>



<p>Make yourselves known as an institution that is welcoming people – because that’s the problem. People don’t see themselves in those spaces, so they assume that it’s not for them, and that is the whole problem when it comes to representation. I think I’ve had one lecturer of colour that taught me throughout the whole of my university experience, then there was a black female lecturer that I didn’t have because I decided to study abroad that year. That’s literally throughout the whole of my university experience.</p>



<p>It’s not enough anymore for that to be the case. So when it comes to institutions, especially academic institutions, there’s so much work to be done in order to create representation that’s in the curriculum. There’s no reason for there not to be a black British art history curriculum, you know.</p>



<p>We can reel off so many names, and especially in contemporary art, so there’s no need. I think we’re in a stage now where as a community we’re tired of the lip service and we’re tired of the tick box notion, so we can only hope that there will be a change when it comes to, particularly for me, the curriculum… What was quite striking when I was doing my Battle of Lewisham job, when I was researching a lot for these different documentaries (whether it was about knife crime or policing), was how many people don’t know about our history when we spent countless years learning about Henry the 8<sup>th</sup>.</p>



<p>Henry the 8<sup>th</sup> isn’t going anywhere. There’s a whole, you know, Hampton Court that you can go visit. For me I did grow up knowing these stories but even then, only in a very word of mouth sort of way from my parents, maybe in passing. But the Battle of Lewisham more so because it directly affected my family. But yeah to have none of that referenced in the curriculum, even the Battle of Lewisham, is ridiculous to me.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still--1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4945" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still--1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still--768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still--1536x1024.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still--1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>I think at this present moment I’m kind of hitting this wall of questioning who the work’s for, thinking about exactly what you’re saying, how much to give into the subject. There’s the battle of Lewisham film, and my family is very much connected to that story and because of the traumatic nature of it the documentary’s actually a very different documentary than what it could have been, and I completely stripped my family’s direct involvement. And that was for two reasons; it was in one sense to protect my family and, again, like you mentioned, the trauma, but also because it was a bigger story at the time.</p>



<p><strong>You mentioned your family &#8211; your grandparents are of the Windrush generation, and your heritage works a lot into your practice; does it ever get too difficult when you’re getting very personal with it and telling these stories that are hard for not only yourself but for your family to relive?</strong></p>



<p>I’ve had quite a good experience. I’ve spent quite a lot of time speaking to and interviewing my granddad specifically and I think it’s been quite cathartic for him as someone who’s been through a lot of trauma, had a lot of experiences. He’s watched the documentary about knife crime, he’s watched the documentary about the New Cross Fire, and it’s interesting. When we’re doing the sessions and he’s relaying these things to me it can be quite difficult, to hear about the genuine struggle it was to be a black man in 1985. But I do genuinely think it’s important for me to be documenting these things or at least having that record of those conversations.</p>



<p>It was 40 years since the battle of Lewisham so it felt more like a story about the actual happening and the people, not just our separate family story, which would require a lot more sensitivity. I think naturally the closer you are to something the harder it can be, but I think that’s why using this recurring image of the yam allows me to be able to, you know, think about the topic in more of a nuanced and abstract way. Also, using the yam’s quite humorous.</p>



<p><strong>I’m glad we’re back with yam &#8211; when and how did it evolve from this food or everyday object into the symbol you make it in your work?</strong></p>



<p>It’s a weird one because I was studying abroad, during my BA, in Vancouver. I was in western Canada so there wasn’t a language barrier, so going into that space I didn’t expect to have this big culture shock. I didn’t expect to have this big cultural identity awakening. I got there and everyone was calling me African American. And I was like… I’m just confused! I’m here with what I believe is a very think South London accent, or at least a very British accent&#8230; Calling me African American?</p>



<p>And I had a task when I got back from studying abroad, we all had to do a show, and yam drew me in. I just felt… I’m going to put yam in a bag and make a few sculptures out of them because my mum used to have this running joke when we were younger: ‘if you don’t behave yourself I’ll send you back to the Caribbean to plant yam,’ and I just always thought that was quite interesting. And since then I’ve kind of stuck with it as a medium because I’m still not necessarily finished with it. Again, at the moment, at this specific time, I might be at a slight wall with it, and I’m thinking about how I want to refine using the medium.</p>



<p>The yam is very much linked to the experience of black people and them migrating into the landscape. It’s so interesting &#8211; the sculptures are quite tall and a lot of people ask me “where did you buy that material from?” or “what is it?” It was hilarious when I was at Goldmiths because people would ask where did you get it from and I was like across the road… literally across the road.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4946" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/The-Battle-of-Lewisham-Still-1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>When I was in Reading I started working with a girl who was from Poland and she one day said to me “I’m going to go get traditional polish food from a shop just across the road” and I was like “where?” At this point I’d lived there going on four years so I said oh okay I’ll come with you, very intrigued as to where I was going to find this shop… and it’s right in the centre of town, right between Burger King and Iceland or whatever. And I thought how have I never seen this place before?</p>



<p>When I think about that, that’s how I think maybe people see the yam. It almost just gets etched out because it’s not a cultural norm or necessity for them. So yeah, that’s kind of the story of me working with yam as a material. It’s interesting because I recently just started becoming a figure within the work. Prior it was more sculpture and other subjects that I’m interviewing. When you do performance art sometimes having to direct people, especially in an artistic way where it’s so abstract, it can be difficult. Whereas for me I knew what I was thinking in terms of style and actuality. I’m not behind the camera.</p>



<p><strong>When you insert yourself into your art how do you see yourself? What’s your relation to yourself and the art?</strong></p>



<p>That’s a good question. I guess I see myself as a subject but also kind of like an art medium, because, obviously, it’s performance so the art going on within the performance kind of becomes the artwork if you know what I mean. And a lot of the actual performances are very much to do with my own thought process at the time, they’re very much off the cuff because they’re meant to be live and in the moment.</p>



<p>I don’t want to have to sit and plan these really rigid routines or whatever. I think it’s all about the connection with the space and the audience in the specific time. It’s kind of hard to explain it. That’s a very interesting question because I’ve not thought about it in that way. I guess I found it quite liberating to be able to really, in the full sense, explore visually what I’m thinking. Using myself as a subject I’m able to do that.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>What was the pandemic like for you as an artist, from a creative perspective as well as personally and career-wise?</strong></p>



<p>I think it’s hit me in two different waves. When the pandemic first hit, I think it was actually an opportunity to be like well the only thing I do have is my art practice. Because before that I was spending a lot of time trying to develop in the television industry, an industry that’s very alien to me not coming from an Oxbridge background, which I didn’t even know was apparently the ticket into television, but it is apparently. I was always feeling like I had to beat down walls in that circle…</p>



<p>I kind of had the opportunity during the lockdown to really focus on the art that I had created previously and think about new ideas. I got lucky to have access to a window exhibition, that was for my Evolved piece, for three months. That was interesting; to be able to look at different ways of presenting work. Prior to that a lot of my work was more digital: this was now more print and sculpture, so that was really interesting.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="684" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-2-684x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4938" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-2-684x1024.jpg 684w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-2-768x1150.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-2-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-2-1320x1977.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-2.jpg 1368w" sizes="(max-width: 684px) 100vw, 684px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>I guess lockdown one felt quite productive in terms of “right, I have my art practice,” etc. etc. The only problem was, as we kept on waiting and waiting for things to open back up, that’s when it started stagnating for me in terms of what I can actually do moving forward. So now I’ve been in this situation where I’m contemplating freelance work and commission work, the realistic nature of being able to form a career in that way. This had been a big dent… I think a lot of us were just starting to get into our stride especially after university.</p>



<p>Just trying to find day to day jobs has been my focus rather than trying to find/run a platform for other people as well as trying to think about what you need to do to survive.</p>



<p>And then we had Black Lives Matter in the cocoon of a pandemic where everyone was inside and the news was just…every single day, you know what I mean. And that was a big hit on me because personally I wasn’t able to go to the protests as we were shielding at the time.</p>



<p>There was this pressure as well, especially as someone who makes work like what we were talking about &#8211; black, political art &#8211; so if you’re not in the frontline suddenly there’s all this pressure around what I should be doing or what as a community we should be doing. It was all task forces and letters and all this stuff, so that also had a hold. And I felt like in a way there was an element of me that wanted to put all that energy into artwork, but it was also exhausting and very traumatic.</p>



<p>So I think we’ve been hit with almost two main things: a pandemic in its natural form which shut down everything, and also what is the growing diversity issue and crisis that we have in this country. It’s been very intense to kind of just function. This time has also allowed me to experiment in ways that I wouldn’t have had access to or had the time to do, so that feels quite exciting and now it’s about trying to refine and think about developing the ideas.</p>



<p><strong>George Floyd &#8211; whenever these big racial incidents happen we always see this push for more black art, more exposure… what was your experience after the event?</strong></p>



<p>The funniest thing was, my phone has not stopped ringing. That space of time was the most calls I’ve gotten. Obviously in March, when no one had any work and with the art industry and television industry sort of crashing, people didn’t really have any sort of work &#8211; that was still going on in May/ June time of that year &#8211; so for me when I was getting all these calls, I can only put my finger on the fact that suddenly they want to draw out the diversity.</p>



<p>Personally, I had a very big problem with black out Tuesday, I did not, I do not support it, especially because it came from within these creative industries trying to boycott and have this kind of black, but that doesn’t actually address the issues. I think what’s been happening are these very quick responses, companies pledging a million this a million that, which doesn’t actually hone in on the heart of the issues, which is the lack of representation at the top. I think a lot of people think we want some of these big wig cis-white men to be kicked off their pedestals and to have to sign on at the job centre; that’s not what we’re saying (not that that wouldn’t be a good idea… but that’s not what we’re saying).</p>



<p>We’re just saying we also want to have a seat at the table. Also, I do think it’s been such a difficult one because there’s been so many interesting ways that people have been trying to think about diversity but also they all feel quite tick boxy. I think the struggle has been that when you do have these institutions that have been white washed trying to lead diversity, they’ll never understand.</p>



<p>It’s weird because it definitely feels like “our time” but at the same time I do think that’s damaging. Because we’re going through a period of trauma and then we’re expected to make work or have these ideas and I think when it first hit there were times when I was drawing a complete blank because I was so fixated on what was the change in the story that was unfolding at the time.</p>



<p>I definitely do think a change is coming, but what I’m worried about is the systematic interplays that it’s rooted in. I do feel there’s kind of like puppeteer elements, people who are holding the privilege in a lot of these institutions and who just want to be seen to be diverse so they don’t get dragged on Instagram and Twitter. So yeah it’s interesting… it’s hilarious actually.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="684" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-1-684x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4937" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-1-684x1024.jpg 684w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-1-768x1150.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-1-1025x1536.jpg 1025w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-1-1320x1977.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Daughters-of-Hannah-1.jpg 1368w" sizes="(max-width: 684px) 100vw, 684px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>Your latest piece was Daughters of Hannah; will you talk about that a bit</strong></p>



<p>Daughters of Hannah came from spirituality, and it’s kind of looking at the story of Hannah in the bible, in the Old Testament, which sees Hannah initially as barren, wanting a child. And predominantly, as traditional stories go, or biblical references and conventional stories, it’s this male figure that she’s granted with.</p>



<p>So I was interested in how initially she was tormented by that fact that she couldn’t have children, specifically because she was a second wife to someone who could, so I was just interested in those unborn initial female offspring, with a lower case <em>f</em>. I kind of wanted the yam to be this personification of those feelings and I was trying to embody the essence of Hannah in a creating a black female -again, lower case <em>f </em>&#8211; reference to that experience I guess.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>It’s filmed in several different locations, to make reference to placing black bodies in rural landscapes, and you see me walking through the landscapes with the yam. It’s very regal, there’re references to soldiers, and also in this very white pure garment which makes reference to Rastafarianism but also to priesthood… so there were a lot of different ideas in the piece. And it was actually interesting: because of time and because of just general life the work became quite different to what is was meant to be.</p>



<p>It was meant to be this kind of five-part film with me walking through all these different landscapes, and we’ve got all those pieces filmed, but due to time we exhibited for the show still photography and the sculptures, which was interesting because it allowed to me to see each section as separate. I also created this garden piece, which I’d always wanted to create.</p>



<p>I merged poetry and sound and had a lot of collaboration. It was a piece in which I was able to collaborate and really think about my personal journey. There’re references to mental health, references to my own spirituality&#8230; The piece is still developing and evolving. I’m currently in the process of trying to find to an editor to work with to edit the film. I’m thinking around a five to seven minute film, maybe a split screen composition. There’re a lot of ideas and like I said it’s still being developed so it’s an ongoing piece. But there was a lot of collaboration and a lot of montage and working with a lot of different people.</p>



<p><strong>Do you have a piece of art or a project that you’re most proud of?</strong></p>



<p>I’m pretty proud of my degree show piece. That was probably one of the first times my ideas came together because it was actually quite a struggle. It’s interesting, I spoke to my lecturer the other day; I’m still quite good friends with her because I guest lecture back at Reading. My lecturer, Christine Ellison, she was quite tough and I chose her on purpose because you can very much coast by thinking you’ve got great ideas and you get to results day and you’re like huh? She really pushed me and was very much like “there’s something missing, there’s something missing.”Tthere was always something missing, it was very intense.</p>



<p>I think because that was the first time I started experimenting with the yam specifically it was nice to see all the ideas come together. It was kind of like a two-part film where I interview both my granddad and my aunt, who’s from Birmingham. They were both talking about their journeys through Windrush, and I merged that with different experiments I was doing with the yam. It was a powerful way for me to really start thinking about the ideas I was interested in. Technically it wasn’t 100% there, but in terms of all the separate elements I think I’m still trying to work on refining those.</p>



<p>There’s a contrast between that piece, or a connection between that piece, and Daughters of Hannah, and that’s something I find quite interesting as well.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="575" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour--1024x575.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4941" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour--1024x575.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour--768x431.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour--1536x863.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour--1056x594.jpg 1056w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Few-Stains-of-Colour--1320x741.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><strong>What’s your advice for young artists?</strong></p>



<p>I spent so many years doing a lot of joint things: my degree was art and philosophy, when I was at Goldsmiths I was doing documentary film but I was really trying to keep that foot in the art world, and even now with television because there’re are many different routes you kind of start off trying to do as much of everything as you can and you get yourself at a point where you’re just like… AAAH.</p>



<p>So I think it’s important, and I’ve actually never said this, to just go towards where your passion takes you and try lead that into something you can specialise in. Just be mindful of juggling too many plates because I think they will come crashing down.</p>



<p>A friend of mine also mentioned something to me recently about saying no. As someone who doesn’t come from a space where daddy’s going to give me a job or daddy’s friend’s going to give me a job, I came from this space where you had to say yes to everything, to every opportunity. And then you get to a point where halfway through said opportunity you’re like I don’t know if this is for me but you’re not really from a privileged position where you can say no.</p>



<p>So that’s the other thing, get to a space where if someone might offer you an opportunity to do something but that’s not in your actual plan for yourself or what you want to do, you say no. And I definitely think there’s sometimes more power in saying no, especially if it’s for the sake of the direction in which you want to go.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
To see see more of Nachael&#8217;s work, check out her <a href="https://nachealcatnott.org/" data-type="URL">Website</a>, and follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nachealcatnott/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../nachael-catnott/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Art&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Nachael Catnott&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / “Any Black doctors avail&#173;able?”</title>
		<link>./../../../medical-racism/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=medical-racism</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 19:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Jane Maseko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> The historical anatomical othering of Black people has created healthcare services that are ill-equipped to care for Black patients <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2></span><span id=span3> The “race awakening” brought about by the murder of George Floyd last year ...</span><span id=span4></span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../medical-racism/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;“Any Black doctors avail&shy;able?”&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The historical anatomical othering of Black people has created healthcare services that are ill-equipped to care for Black patients, and yet another area of life where race is inescapable.</p>



<p>The “race awakening” brought about by the murder of George Floyd last year and the disparities in the Covid-19 impact between whites and BAME communities has, for some, spotlighted how Black people are let down by and systematically excluded from society’s institutions.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>One I find particularly disturbing is healthcare. Racism and the historical medical mistreatment of Black bodies have upheld ideas of Blackness as not only culturally other but humanly other altogether.</p>



<p>Black people experience higher levels of neglect and mistreatment by medical professionals, are haunted by erroneous anatomical beliefs fabricated by racists that still find their way into medical practice today, and, to make this game even more despicable, are put at increased health risk by the very same racism that makes seeking out healthcare so much harder for us.Black people know this, and medicine’s bright white history has left many mistrustful. So many of us are always ready for the potential awkwardness from the receptionist when we ask “do you have any Black doctors available?”</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="564" height="794" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/j.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4041"/></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>It shouldn’t be surprising that Black folks face discrimination and neglect when it comes to health services. The history of western medicine is white, male and riddled with atrocities committed on Black bodies. And the legacy of this history, as with all institutions in society, is still very much alive, still perpetuating the racism that’s been inherent in medicine since the colonisers colonised. There isn’t sufficient knowledge among healthcare workers in diseases like sickle cell, which predominantly affects those of African and Caribbean descent.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="782" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2-782x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3965" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2-782x1024.jpg 782w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2-768x1006.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2.jpg 1063w" sizes="(max-width: 782px) 100vw, 782px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Medical schools aren’t training doctors to know how some illnesses present in people with Black skin, with some doctors going through their entire training without seeing examples of how common skin conditions like eczema appear on non-white skin.</p>



<p>One that’s been headlining recently is how pulse oximeters are more likely to miss low levels of oxygen in people with Black skin, resulting in Black patients being sent home when they should be hospitalised. “Historically medical education was designed and written by white middle-class men, and so there is an inherent racism in medicine that means it exists to serve white patients above all others,” leaving Black patients subjected to higher levels of neglect, mistreatment and death.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>A recent and tragic case involving a sickle cell patient is that of Evan Smith, who died after calling 999 from inside the hospital when he was denied oxygen after being told his blood saturation levels were healthy. The coroner ruled that the cause of Smith’s death was not receiving “a timely exchange transfusion”. A significant factor in the delay was “a lack of understanding of sickle cell disease in the medical and nursing staff looking after Mr Smith.” An alarming finding was that “nurses did not have specific training in managing sickle cell disease, despite serving an area with a large African and Caribbean community.” The coroner did not make a ruling of neglect.</p>



<p>There was a case at my local hospital, also in an area with a large population of African and Caribbean people, where a woman took herself with her new-born to A&amp;E and was sent home by hospital staff on a bus. It turned out she had developed sepsis a week after giving birth. A Black nurse who later heard about this said she immediately knew the woman was Black because such treatment was so commonplace.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Black people are mistreated and under-served in healthcare. This is a direct result of medicine’s racist history, for which not enough has been done to undo, and the subsequent implicit biases held by medical professionals and healthcare workers. As recently as the 1970s there were medical text books that stated Black people have a higher pain threshold than whites.</p>



<p>And as recently as 2016 a study from the United States found that many medical students “believed that black people’s nerve endings are less sensitive than white people and that black people’s blood coagulates quicker.” </p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="881" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-881x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4072" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-881x1024.jpg 881w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-768x893.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-1322x1536.jpg 1322w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-1320x1534.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7.jpg 1516w" sizes="(max-width: 881px) 100vw, 881px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>There have been other studies showing that “black patients are often prescribed less pain relief than other people, despite having the same conditions, and that applies to children too.” There are countless cases of Black patients being denied the care they need and are entitled to or having to fight a lot harder to receive it.</p>



<p>It was hard not to think about my own experiences and those of people close to me as I went through these stories of mistreatment and learnt even more about how deeply race impacted medicine and healthcare provision. When I hear that there are medical workers out there who think our blood coagulates quicker I can’t help wonder about a time I went to A&amp;E and instead of leaving with stitches I got a dodgy tape up that had reopened by the time I got home. I had to buy my own supplies and take care of the dressing myself.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="884" height="758" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pelwis8ioho.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4046" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pelwis8ioho.jpg 884w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pelwis8ioho-768x659.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 884px) 100vw, 884px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>When I hear that our pain is perceived differently I can’t help think about the time when a doctor wouldn’t prescribe me pain medication for migraines. Maybe the hospital staff there were bad at their jobs, maybe it was an accident. Maybe that doctor genuinely thought I’d be fine if I watched my caffeine intake and tried to take paracetamol as early on as possible. The fact is I can’t not wonder if race played a part in these events. Especially when stories of Black people being treated differently are so widespread and seen in all areas of healthcare.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>An area that’s been receiving particular attention recently, also with a long history of neglecting Black people, is mental health care. In school, I saw white students getting access to services and being treated with more sympathy than my Black peers and myself. Even once in the system I’ve had friends report also feeling gaslit and treated with blatant disregard at points. Medication reviews feel one sided, symptoms are questioned and ignored, problematic behaviours are minimised.</p>



<p>Race can even make it hard to take the first steps in seeking out mental health services. Or, rather, the lack of provision within mental health services of sufficient resources for Black patients, such as POC therapists, can make this hard. “I would take anything right now not to feel the way that I did last night because it was awful,” a friend said to me, “and I know that I need therapy but I am not willing to go to a white therapist at this point in time.” Similarly to how a female assault victim would rather see a female therapist, a Black person who has been psychologically impacted by the frequent traumas of racism would rather see a Black therapist to discuss these things. The fact that healthcare services don’t think about this shows they don’t think about Black patients and their experiences.</p>



<p>I know these are services that are already strained but when Blackness is such a common denominator among those let down by them it’s impossible not to look at race as part of the reason for these failings. The recent deaths of Olisa Odukwe and Richard Okorogheye serve as yet more tragic reminders that while Black folks are let down in all areas of healthcare, mental health is one which seems to particularly fail and exclude us time and time again. In the words of @lookingformothermax, “young Black people’s lives should not be cut short before they are afforded access to, and inclusivity in facilities and services… the face of mental health advocacy and campaigning should not and cannot only be white middle-class people.”</p>



<p>The health disparities highlighted by Covid-19 won’t be going away once the pandemic is over (nor did they only come to exist when it started), and if negative health outcomes resulting from racial bias aren’t spoken about they never will. We need more research into how race impacts health outcomes. Data needs to be gathered so problems and solutions can be identified. As long as the experiences of Black people are ignored and gaslit by society and by documents like the Sewell Report, they’ll be ignored and gaslit by our doctors.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="658" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1024x658.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4013" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1024x658.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-768x493.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1536x986.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1320x848.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri.jpg 1601w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>And for those who lack certain levels of humanity and need these issues framed in the context of how wider society is affected for them to mean anything to you, vaccine hesitancy among BAME communities is a direct result of the mistrust these groups have of the medical establishment because of its racist past and present. It might not make sense to some why people would trust their barber or pastor over the CDC, but would you trust someone who time and time again has demonstrated that they don’t have your best interests at heart?</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Thuli Jane Maseko, to keep up with her work follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thuliijane" data-type="URL">Intagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../medical-racism/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;“Any Black doctors avail&shy;able?”&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
