<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sasha Rainbow - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 19:50:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Sasha Rainbow - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Docu&#173;mentary / Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&#173;bow</title>
		<link>./../../../kamali/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=kamali</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joelle Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sasha Rainbow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap>
Kamali is a Bafta-nominated short film, about a kick-ass young skateboarder with a <span id=span1>...</span><span id=span2>beautiful story to tell. Kamali is a 7-year-old girl from a small fishing village in</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> Mahabalipuram, India. She is the only female skateboarder in her village, where a skate ramp was built right outside her house…<span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kamali/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;mentary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&shy;bow&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xzlXrVqMtNY" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<p>Kamali is a Bafta-nominated short film, about a kick-ass young skateboarder with a beautiful story to tell. Kamali is a 7-year-old girl from a small fishing village in Mahabalipuram, India. She is the only female skateboarder in her village, where a skate ramp was built right outside her house.  The film also follows the story of her mother, on a pilgrimage of self-discovery after leaving an abusive relationship. This short film directed by Sasha Rainbow&nbsp;is an insight into how India&#8217;s gender roles are changing for the younger generation. </p>



<p>Joelle: How would you describe the concept of the film?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sasha: Kamali is about a single Indian mother&#8217;s fight for her daughter&#8217;s empowerment through skateboarding. It&#8217;s about the cycle of empowerment disrupting the status quo for everyone involved.</p>



<p>J: How did you cross paths with Kamali?</p>



<p>S: I made a documentary music video for a British Band&nbsp;The Wild Beastswhich featured the new generation of female skaters in India. After seeing a picture of Kamali in a little dress, 6 years old, blasting down a ramp, I knew she had to be in the video. We tracked her down while we were in India and managed to convince her and her mum to leave their village for the first time and come to the big city of Bangalore, where they stayed with us and Kamali experienced her first real skatepark.<br><a href="https://vimeo.com/199716710" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://vimeo.com/199716710</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot2019-03-26at16.30.21-edited.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2011" width="665" height="413"/></figure>



<p>J: Can you tell us a bit about how Kamali got into skateboarding?&nbsp;</p>



<p>S: A skate crew&nbsp;called Hollystoked built a tiny ramp outside Kamali&#8217;s house when she was about 5.&nbsp;Because her uncle was a surfer, she was already playing on the board with him in the water, so I guess she was also attracted to the board on land. There they all share boards. One day pro skater Jamie Thomas was passing through the village and saw Kamali and&nbsp;ended up staying a few days, taught her to drop, and left her his board. The photo I first saw of Kamali was of this moment. The rest is history as they say!&nbsp;</p>



<p>J: What does Kamali symbolise to you and how can she inspire others across the world, regardless of age?</p>



<p>S: Kamali symbolizes hope for the future as an unquestionable example&nbsp;of what females can achieve when they&#8217;re allowed to play and explore their passions freely. Because, as we see in the film, this doesn&#8217;t just affect one person, it affects the whole community by changing the narrative of what can and can&#8217;t be done.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2017" width="661" height="373" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433.jpg 770w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 661px) 100vw, 661px" /></figure>



<p>J: What were some highlights on the set of filming Kamali, is there a moment that will stick with you? Did you also come across&nbsp;any challenges?</p>



<p>S: The whole experience of filming Kamali was a world unto itself. We were able to step into another person&#8217;s existence for a moment in time, in this case, a whole&nbsp;family&#8217;s. That&#8217;s unique and doesn&#8217;t happen every day. Often when you travel it&#8217;s very fleeting or can be superficial, but we got to stay long enough for the days to be their own mini existences, to get to know the locals and travelers to the even smaller villages and mooch around in the heat with good company, to the point that we almost felt like the camera was another extension of the group. It was tough not speaking the same language but that&#8217;s when I really understood how much communication is around body language and tone more than anything. It informed how we filmed and proved to be the truest guide. I often wonder what the film would have been like had I understood everything being said around me.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="756" height="472" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image-asset-edited.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-2013"/></figure>



<p>J: How is Kamali now, are you still in touch?</p>



<p>S: Kamali is growing up to be an amazing 10-year-old. She still surfs and skates and her English is fantastic.&nbsp;She has such a sweet, kind, intelligent soul.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m very excited to have a beer with her when she&#8217;s a bit older and ask what the experiences of her youth were like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>J: Having you got any upcoming projects?&nbsp;</p>



<p>S: I&#8217;ve switched documentary gears and I have been writing since lock-down, something I&#8217;d been hoping to do. I&#8217;ve got a mystery comedy set in Hollywood on the go and am working on a family comedy in New Zealand which I&#8217;m very excited about. </p>



<p>Thank You!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-1024x717.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2016" width="798" height="558" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-1024x717.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-768x538.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 798px) 100vw, 798px" /></figure>



<div id="footer"> 
Head over to <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/archive/in/entry/kamali-documentary-skateboarding-sasha-rainbow_in_5da5749be4b0058374e83151" data-type="URL">Huffington Post</a> for the full film. If you&#8217;d like to hear more from Sasha, she will be participating in an interview for International Women&#8217;s Day, which You can keep by following her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/itssasharainbow/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kamali/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;mentary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&shy;bow&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
