<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Articles - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 25 Jan 2022 11:13:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Articles - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Article / Sidney Poitier</title>
		<link>./../../../sidney-poitier/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=sidney-poitier</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 17:06:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Maseko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=5142</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Beloved Bahamian-American actor and activist Sidney Poitier passed away on <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> 6 January. He will be remembered as the first black movie star, an accomplished </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> irector, social activist, and an icon of cinema. Born in 1927 and growing ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../sidney-poitier/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Sidney Poitier&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="1024" height="862" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/01/potiewidewide-copy-1024x862.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5159" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/01/potiewidewide-copy-1024x862.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/01/potiewidewide-copy-768x646.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2022/01/potiewidewide-copy.jpg 1283w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Beloved Bahamian-American actor and activist Sidney Poitier passed away on 6 January. He will be remembered as the first black movie star, an accomplished director, social activist, and an icon of cinema. Born in 1927 and growing up in the Bahamas, Poitier would begin acting in his twenties at the Harlem based Community Negro Theatre. It was around fifteen years later that he would become the first black man to win the Oscar for best actor (Lilies of the Field, 1963) and cement his legacy as a true pioneer in Hollywood history.</p>



<p>Outside of his acting career he was a dedicated civil rights and independence activist. Serving as Bahamian ambassador to Japan and UNESCO, and being a vocal advocate for human rights, he used his status to serve his community, with Martin Luther King jr. saying of him; “he is a man of great depth, a man of great social concern, a man who is dedicated to human rights and freedom.” </p>



<p>While many of the characters he played were often criticised as representing “too good to be true” idealisations of the palatable black man, his roles in the likes of In the Heat of the Night and Guess Who’s Coming to Dinner saw him in parts with more depth and gravitas than had previously been given to black actors. Seeing him slap a white man and not die by the end of the film was a powerful thing for many black people to see in a big Hollywood movie. It’s true that much of what we saw of Poitier was a quiet caricature of the ideal black American, an image put upon him by the industry limitations of tokenism and stereotyping, but he had agency,&nbsp;was smart, and expanded black representation in cinema significantly.</p>



<p>&#8220;Before Sidney, African American actors had to take supporting roles in major studio films that were easy to cut out in certain parts of the country. But you couldn&#8217;t cut Sidney Poitier out of a Sidney Poitier picture”&#8230; “He was the reason a movie got made: the first solo above-the-title African American movie star” (Denzel Washington).</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Thuli Maseko, to keep up with her work follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thuliijane" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../sidney-poitier/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Sidney Poitier&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / Watchful Force</title>
		<link>./../../../watchful-force/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=watchful-force</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 25 Dec 2021 21:07:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Farrant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3829</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> There are security checks in every metro station, utilising x-ray scanners and metal detectors <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> It’s easy to feel aware of the police presence in much of the city</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> At times it feels like a glimpse into an Orwellian high-tech future, with the overbearing lights illuminating one’s darkest dystopian fears.<br />
...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../watchful-force/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Watchful Force&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large watchfheader"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="360" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WATCforce13-1024x360.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4450" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WATCforce13-1024x360.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WATCforce13-768x270.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WATCforce13-1536x540.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/WATCforce13-1320x464.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large watchfuleye"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="945" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watch-1024x945.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4459" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watch-1024x945.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watch-768x709.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watch-1536x1418.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watch-1320x1218.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watch.jpg 1933w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large watchf1"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="483" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/checkpoint-1024x483.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4857" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/checkpoint-1024x483.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/checkpoint-768x362.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/checkpoint-1536x725.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/checkpoint-1320x623.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large watchf2"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="550" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cctv-1024x550.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4856" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cctv-1024x550.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cctv-768x412.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cctv-1536x825.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cctv-1320x709.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>There are security checks in every metro station, utilising x-ray scanners and metal detectors. It’s easy to feel aware of the police presence in much of the city. At times it feels like a glimpse into an Orwellian high-tech future, with the overbearing lights illuminating one’s darkest dystopian fears.</p>



<p>The feeling this presence creates is visceral. Our very experience of space intersecting with an understanding about its relationship to the forces of surveillance, and control.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="681" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchfulforce10-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4455" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchfulforce10-1024x681.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchfulforce10-768x511.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchfulforce10-1536x1022.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchfulforce10-1320x878.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Part of this comes from preconceptions. China has been historically notorious for its role in surveillance, censorship and control of its population.</p>



<p>We might question the legitimacy of these reporting’s though, given the Chinese government clearly being seen as a rival to the West. But beyond being seen as an exaggeration, perhaps this is a case of hypocrisy? London is reportedly among the most surveilled cities on the planet&nbsp;<a href="https://www.businessinsider.com/most-surveilled-cities-in-the-world-china-london-atlanta-2019-8">[1]</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="717" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Mugshot3-2-717x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4884" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Mugshot3-2-717x1024.jpg 717w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Mugshot3-2-768x1097.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Mugshot3-2-1075x1536.jpg 1075w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Mugshot3-2-1320x1886.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Mugshot3-2.jpg 1386w" sizes="(max-width: 717px) 100vw, 717px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Through the past two decades there has been a lot of reporting on China’s state censorship of the news. This is a process that has evolved from once simple methods. When an unfavourable report would come on the BBC World Service, for example, the screen would temporarily switch off <a href="https://www.hollywoodreporter.com/news/general-news/chinese-censors-temporarily-black-cnn-417411/">[2]</a>.</p>



<p>Since those days, in 2010, both Google and YouTube Since those days, in 2010, both Google and YouTube were blocked, marking a key stage in the state’s censorship transition into the Internet age&nbsp;<a href="https://www.bbc.com/news/10449139">[3]</a>. Since then, a far more complex system of online censorship has evolved, with the systematic burying, flagging and hiding of dissenting texts taking place – with more moderate dissent being allowed, effectively constructing an image of free speech&nbsp;<a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2020/12/19/world/thousands-of-internal-documents-reveal-how-china-censored-its-internet-in-the-early-days-of-the-pandemic.html">[4]</a>.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>In recent years, reports on the persecution of Uyghurs in Xinjiang have emerged, with thousands disappearing into re-education centres, supposedly in order to “learn Chinese values”&nbsp;<a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=WmId2ZP3h0c">[5]</a>.</p>



<p>The reality of the situation is incredibly obscured, though evidence of thousands being put to unpaid labour has been reported&nbsp;<a href="https://qz.com/1811305/nike-apple-linked-to-forced-uighur-labor-in-china-report-says/">[6]</a>, accusations of rape, torture and forced sterilisation have also emerged, alongside innumerable other rights abuses&nbsp;<a href="https://www.aljazeera.com/news/2021/6/4/uighur-tribunal-hears-evidence-of-alleged-china-abuses">[7]</a>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-below-left">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Any Uyghur whose behaviour is seen as having anything to do with religious belief – books, beards&nbsp;<a href="https://www.theguardian.com/world/2020/feb/18/china-detains-uighurs-for-growing-beards-or-visiting-foreign-websites-leak-reveals">[8]</a>, even dresses deemed too long&nbsp;<a href="https://www.taiwannews.com.tw/en/news/3483812">[9]</a>&nbsp;– have been targeted, with thousands of families split apart in the process. Amounting to both cultural, and human genocide.</p>



<p>Xingjiang laid the groundwork for a system of rigorous surveillance that could be rolled out across the nation. CCTV cameras are ever present, lining every street.</p>



<p>Accompanied by police checkpoints on almost every corner, at which citizens are required to show ID and provide justification for their presence&nbsp;<a href="http://%5B10%5D/">[10]</a>.</p>



<p>An understanding of this context colours one’s navigation of other Chinese cities such as Shenzhen; the feeling that our actions and identity could be under constant surveillance. </p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="686" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum5-686x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4445" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum5-686x1024.jpg 686w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum5-768x1147.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum5-1028x1536.jpg 1028w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum5-1320x1971.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum5.jpg 1372w" sizes="(max-width: 686px) 100vw, 686px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-below-right">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="693" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Standoff-693x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4864" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Standoff-693x1024.jpg 693w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Standoff-768x1135.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Standoff-1039x1536.jpg 1039w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Standoff-1320x1951.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Standoff.jpg 1386w" sizes="(max-width: 693px) 100vw, 693px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>The reality of course, is that perpetual manned surveillance is near impossible, and that such cities are not direct parallels to Xinjiang.</p>



<p class="collapse-below-left">Despite this, state rollout of surveillance across other major Chinese cities, demonstrates that the intention may remain on the horizon. Across the centre of the city of Shenzhen there is a heavy police presence, and police booths are ubiquitous.</p>



<p>Meanwhile metro stations each have their own officer, one’s bags must be scanned on entry to any and every metro station.</p>



<p>But this is only a small part of the larger picture. In contrast to the overt heavy-handed authoritarianism of a fascist state, surveillance, and thus control, are far more subtle here.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>Still, we only need to look around, to observe the high presence of CCTV, symbolising the fact that our actions may be monitored.</p>



<p>You might ask why surveillance matters? It matters because the standard for acceptable behaviour placed on citizens by an unjust state, can easily veer into that which confines the individual. Facilitating oppressive punishment for the breaking of the rules.</p>



<p>Tresspass, drug use and dissent, stand out as examples of where pervasive surveillance allows the force the state to easily come down on rule breakers. This cements the political order and punishes those marginalised by it: those living by a morality beyond that of the state, or committing petty crimes in order to survive under a system that threatens it.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="693" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Huaqing-Road-1-1024x693.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4865" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Huaqing-Road-1-1024x693.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Huaqing-Road-1-768x519.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Huaqing-Road-1-1536x1039.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/Huaqing-Road-1-1320x893.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>The feeling this surveillance creates is strangely unsettling, especially when contrasted against the high-tech beauty of parts of the city. Creating a dual feeling of comfort and discomfort at one’s environment in the knowledge that they may be being watched.</p>



<p>A position perhaps only afforded to those able to navigate these spaces with the detachment of a tourist, where real consequences for misbehaviour are a fraction of that for citizens.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="693" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cyberrennaisance-1024x693.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4860" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cyberrennaisance-1024x693.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cyberrennaisance-768x520.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cyberrennaisance-1536x1040.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/cyberrennaisance-1320x894.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>As an observer, I felt almost above the surveillance present, yet simultaneously fearful of it, in a country where punishment is beyond disproportionate. Ultimately, Shenzhen, and many other cities across China (and even London), construct a model of the world in which our locations, actions, conversations may be constantly surveilled.</p>



<p>And yet, we are free to navigate the expanses of the city, demonstrating the failure for models of surveillance to fall into strict binary established between Orwell and Huxley.</p>



<p>Orwell’s imagining was of total surveillance, and immeasurable consequence for stepping out of the clear paths established by authority; Huxley’s was of a society dominated by coercion and misinformation. This is a space that begins to embody facets of both.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="693" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/work-1024x693.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4862" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/work-1024x693.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/work-768x519.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/work-1536x1039.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/11/work-1320x893.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>For one to step out of the defined routes, to trespass for example, could result in severe punishment. Yet most citizens live their lives in relative freedom, privy to the spoils of middle-class luxuries, drink and food. All the while ones life is underlined by strict state control of information.</p>



<p>The notion that surveillance is a Chinese thing alone is no longer true, as tech becomes more ubiquitous, and as power and wealth concentrates. The same patterns may be observed globally, with high tech surveillance providing an easy means for states to control their citizens.</p>



<p>Shenzhen, and at the extreme, the experience of the Uyghurs in Xinjiang, act as case studies for this intersection of modernity and control.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="680" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum6-1024x680.png" alt="" class="wp-image-4443" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum6-1024x680.png 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum6-768x510.png 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum6-1536x1020.png 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/08/watchsum6-1320x876.png 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written for James Farrant&#8217;s book fragments, which you can find out more about <a href="https://www.jpf__art.com/" data-type="URL">here</a>. One of Five articles to be published to SUMweekly.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../watchful-force/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Watchful Force&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / To Bell, With Love</title>
		<link>./../../../bell-hooks/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bell-hooks</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 22 Dec 2021 19:01:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Maseko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=5072</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> While Bell Hooks has always been a giant in revolutionary thought, her recent <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> passing has heighted discussion of her work and the impact she has had </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> on individuals, movements, and progressive thinking. Part of her contribution ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../bell-hooks/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;To Bell, With Love&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="687" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase5-1-1024x687.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5075" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase5-1-1024x687.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase5-1-768x515.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase5-1-1536x1030.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase5-1-1320x885.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase5-1.jpg 1602w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>While Bell Hooks has always been a giant in revolutionary thought, her recent passing has heighted discussion of her work and the impact she has had on individuals, movements, and progressive thinking. Part of her contribution we should be most grateful for is what she taught us about love.&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>hooks is often and rightly lauded as a radical. One of her most radical and revolutionary positions was her view on the socially and politically transformative power of love. It’s through love that we can begin to disconnect ourselves from materialism and systems of domination.&nbsp;</p>



<p>From romantic love to self-love, hooks was fearless and prolific in her advocacy for the concept. She saw what self-hatred and low self-esteem could do to people and, subsequently, whole movements; how through a lack of love fights against oppressive systems could end up feeding into and sustaining others; how when we fail to see the subjecthood of others we are liable to only be moved to action when our own self-interests are threatened.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="819" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase3b-1-819x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5091" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase3b-1-819x1024.jpg 819w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase3b-1-768x961.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase3b-1.jpg 901w" sizes="(max-width: 819px) 100vw, 819px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p></p>



<p>We need what hooks called “a love ethic”, a shared commitment to the welfare of ourselves and others, to ground our struggles against structures of domination; “&#8230; it is in choosing love, and beginning with love as the ethical foundation for politics, that we are best positioned to transform society in ways that enhance the collective good.”</p>



<p>The definition of love hooks embraces sees love as “the will to extend one’s self for the purpose of nurturing one’s own or another’s spiritual growth” (M. Scott Peck). This, for hooks, got closer to the essence of love, and was a good place to start as a working universal definition upon which the foundations of our journeys to love could begin. To “extend” indicates action; understanding love as a verb was central to what hooks teaches us about loving.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="703" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase2-1024x703.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5076" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase2-1024x703.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase2-768x527.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase2-1536x1054.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase2-1320x906.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase2.jpg 1728w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>One needs to make a commitment to actively do the work on their inner self: reflecting on and honestly assessing one’s internalised supremacist thinking, recognising and working through one’s pain, learning to view oneself objectively and not through the gaze of materialism, classism or sexist ideals. We also make a commitment to the ones we choose to love.</p>



<p>Whether it be the love we extend to ourselves, romantic partners, or our communities, “to truly love we must learn to mix various ingredients &#8211; care, affection, recognition, respect, commitment, and trust, as well as honest and open communication.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="669" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase-1024x669.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5082" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase-1024x669.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase-768x502.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase-1536x1004.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase-2048x1338.jpg 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/belhooksbase-1320x863.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>To love is to act counter to a culture that centres on individualism, materialism, and imperialism. It is to prioritise the authentic over the transactional, community over isolationism. “The moment we choose to love, we begin to move against domination, against oppression. The moment we choose to love we begin to move towards freedom, to act in ways that liberate ourselves and others. That action is the testimony of love as the practice of freedom.” We should honour bell hooks by considering love thoughtfully and comprehensively in progressive discourse, recognising its spiritual as well as revolutionary value. And we should honour ourselves and our communities by choosing it.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Thuli Maseko, to keep up with her work follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thuliijane" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../bell-hooks/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;To Bell, With Love&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / Peak Privil&#173;ege</title>
		<link>./../../../peak-privilege/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=peak-privilege</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 08 Dec 2021 00:31:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Jane Maseko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=4975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> There are just so many things in this single event that are almost inconceivable for a non-white person to<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>get away with. There are things the legal system afforded Kyle</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> that it would rarely extend to others. The response from police and a justice system that not only punishes POC perpetrators more harshly but goes so far...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../peak-privilege/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Peak Privil&shy;ege&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-5001" width="823" height="548" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1536x1024.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-2048x1366.jpg 2048w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/201030-kyle-rittenhouse-ac-823p-1320x880.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 823px) 100vw, 823px" /><figcaption><em>Rittenhouse during the court case (Nam Y. Huh via AP)</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>There are just so many things in this single event that are almost inconceivable for a non-white person to get away with. There are things the legal system afforded Kyle that it would rarely extend to others. The response from police and a justice system that not only punishes POC perpetrators more harshly but goes so far as to actively vilify these groups, even targeting the innocent, of letting off a man (with sympathy) after he killed two people is probably the starkest display of white privilege I’ve seen in a while.</p>



<p>Many of us were likely in that familiar mindset of being wholly unsurprised yet still feeling a painful sense of injustice. The verdict isn’t the (only) thing that triggers such feelings. It’s the entire system that enabled not only a not guilty verdict to be reached, but that also enabled Kyle to leave Kenosha alive after entering with a semi-automatic weapon and shooting three people.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="847" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1024x847.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4988" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1024x847.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-768x635.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1536x1271.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2-1320x1092.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse2.jpg 1610w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption><em>Kyle Rittenhouse alongside another armed &#8220;Property Defender&#8221;  [Adam Rogan via AP]</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Probably the most obvious place to start in differentiating how law enforcement treats Black bodies and white bodies is Kyle Rittenhouse walking up to police with a rifle. It’s almost inconceivable that a Black person would make it past police officers carrying a gun, especially when Black people, younger and smaller than Kyle, have been killed by police who even just suspected they were armed. And when Black people are legally armed, their Second Amendment right is very rarely respected or defended with the same gusto (recall Philando Castile).&nbsp;</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Kyle’s not subject to profiling in the same way POC groups are, he’s therefore more humanised, more individualised, and thus, more sympathetic. That’s what allowed the defense to put him on the stand with confidence, what allowed him to be seen as a young man with a future etc etc…</p>



<p>why people will see him as someone who wanted to serve his community and not a violent, pesky instigator. Conservatism and white supremacy also play a role here, as the victims were white but not an “acceptable” whiteness by the conscious or unconscious standards of these groups.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/rittenhouse1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4985" width="396" height="461"/><figcaption><em>Rittenhouse&#8217;s Mugshot [Antioch Police Department via AP]</em></figcaption></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>These were white people who had aligned themselves with Black Lives Matter and were threats to what white supremacy and the American system wants to uphold. Their rejection despite being white illustrates the institutional conservatism that permeates these systems along with the institutional racism. We saw this to the extent that Judge Bruce Schroeder didn’t allow those killed to be referred to as victims, because the term was considered too “loaded,” but said that they could be called “looters,” “rioters” and “arsonists”, as if these weren’t loaded terms that would influence a jury in any way.</p>



<p>The victims of the shootings are not offered the same grace as having acted in self-defence, either. After seeing someone kill a man, they pursued&nbsp; him, fired warning shots and attempted to disarm him, yet Kyle was seen as the party in danger. Compared to the actions of the protestors it’s Kyle’s that stand out as more unreasonable, violent and aggressive, but he has the armour of white boyhood and the status quo, so this was never going to be part of the narrative.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="576" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-1024x576.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4992" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-1024x576.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-768x432.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview-1056x594.jpg 1056w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/https___cdn.cnn_.com_cnnnext_dam_assets_211123000103-01-tucker-carlson-kyle-rittenhouse-interview.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption><em>Whitewashing on Fox News</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>The acceptance of Kyle in both mainstream and conservative circles also highlights the conservative context in which the killings and trial took place and how these add to Kyle’s privilege index. Republican senators are offering him jobs, Tucker Carlson did an interview, and far right groups are citing the case as setting a precedent for vigilante action. His attaining martyrdom status among Republican, mainstream and far right extremist groups, and that going largely unquestioned, is an important backdrop to Kyle&#8217;s acquittal.</p>



<p>Imagine if an official came out hailing the Nation of Islam or the Black Panthers as heroes… Attitudes towards non-white groups, extremist or otherwise, have historically been a lot more damning form law enforcement, government and society. Despite white supremacy and white supremacist groups being acknowldedged by the FBI as possibly the most dangerous domestic threat to the United States, a disproportionate amount of time and resources continue to be spent on the comparative over-policing and over-surveillance of non-white groups and individuals.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="695" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1024x695.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4994" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1024x695.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-768x521.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1536x1043.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy-1320x896.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Screenshot-2021-12-07-at-23.13.23-copy.jpg 1950w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption><meta charset="utf-8"><em>Judge Bruce Schroeder during the case [Pool via Getty Images]</em></figcaption></figure>



<p>Kyle is given the benefit of the doubt. Instead of being considered a chaos tourist, right-wing counter protestor looking for trouble or even just someone who’s not where he was supposed to be, he’s seen as the victim who had to defend himself against looting aggressors. Black folk have been treated more suspiciously for being in their own neighbourhoods and colleges.</p>



<p>It’s that same benefit of the doubt that lets a mass shooter be bought Burger King or a rapist have their swim times published, because somewhere inside them people see a good young man with a future, a future white observers are invested in for one reason or another. The point is it’s their shared whiteness that forms the root of this investment, which factors into why we see disproportionate outcomes in the justice system, why Black men receive sentences up to 20 percent longer than whites for the same crimes, why Chrystul Kizer is still awaiting trial and facing life in prison.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There are things Kyle gets because he’s white that other groups don’t, things that oftentimes the system is designed for POC not to get. Kyle can claim all he wants that this all has “nothing to do with race,” but that’s an ignorant position that itself comes from a place of privilege. He had told interviewers “part of my job is to protect people. If someone is hurt, I&#8217;m running into harm&#8217;s way.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="629" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1024x629.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4981" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1024x629.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-768x472.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1536x944.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1-1320x811.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/12/panel1flag-1.jpg 1758w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>It could be said that the protestors were following a similar logic; running into harm&#8217;s way after seeing someone hurt, but neither them nor their cause are afforded the same level of sympathy or justice. They were looters, rioters and arsonists. Kyle was doing his duty, protecting private property (another ideal that’s politically, economically and racially loaded). He was helping others, supporting the blue badge, doing what a young American should. He was a white boy upholding whiteness, and he was most certainly not going to be punished for that.&nbsp;</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Thuli Jane Maseko, to keep up with her work follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thuliijane" data-type="URL">Intagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../peak-privilege/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Peak Privil&shy;ege&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / Marginal Spaces </title>
		<link>./../../../marginal-spaces/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=marginal-spaces</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Jul 2021 06:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[James Farrant]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3822</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Within the vast, modern city of Shenzhen in China, Baishizhou sticks out like a sore thumb<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>. As one moves into it, the meaning of the modern city is completely subverted</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4>. From the uninhabited vast open expanse, into the tight, noisy, populated streets you are ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../marginal-spaces/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Marginal Spaces &lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large marginaltitle"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="351" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/marginalsum-1024x351.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3867" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/marginalsum-1024x351.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/marginalsum-768x264.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/marginalsum-1320x453.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/marginalsum.jpg 1364w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large sidepanel"><img loading="lazy" width="280" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sumshenzhen-280x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3910" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sumshenzhen-280x1024.jpg 280w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sumshenzhen-420x1536.jpg 420w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/sumshenzhen.jpg 560w" sizes="(max-width: 280px) 100vw, 280px" /></figure>



<div class="wp-block-columns col1">
<div class="wp-block-column col1col1">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="670" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5A-670x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3832" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5A-670x1024.jpg 670w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5A-768x1173.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5A-1005x1536.jpg 1005w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5A-1320x2017.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5A.jpg 1341w" sizes="(max-width: 670px) 100vw, 670px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Within the vast, modern city of Shenzhen in China, Baishizhou sticks out like a sore thumb. As one moves into it, the meaning of the modern city is completely subverted.</p>



<p>From the uninhabited open expanse, into the tight, noisy, populated streets you are immediately brought into a space that feels like a genuine reflection of the inhabitants that reside within it.</p>



<p>Shenzhen is a city largely defined by those who possess ownership of it. The city is sharply demarcated by each construction firm and their own goals; from one block to another one finds oneself within vastly different meanings of what the city is.</p>



<p>In this, Baishizhou represents a counter narrative to the modernity the city prides itself on, and as a consequence, is under threat.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>Shenzhen is fascinating for this very reason; its rapid growth has resulted in its very streets becoming a case study in the evolutions of modern cities.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Shenzhen originated as a small collection of fishing villages. During the city’s exponential boom in the ‘70s, the CCP brought the land from the fishermen; however, due to their homeownership, they held on to the rights to occupy the land. As a result, the fishermen were granted greater agency over their pockets of land within the city. As the city grew it enveloped these areas of land, and a stark contrast emerged between the spaces which were owned by massive national firms, and the collectivisation era properties, owned by comparatively small enterprises <sup><a href="https://www.chinafile.com/features/destruction-of-baishizhou">[1]</a></sup>.</p>



<p>These urban villages came to play a big role in the city’s tech boom, providing affordable housing for the city’s low-income workers, nearby to the factories that produce the goods that put Shenzhen on the map <sup><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-12-20/workers-flocking-to-china-s-silicon-valley-can-t-afford-to-buy-homes">[2]</a></sup>. In its prime, 150,000 people inhabited Baishizhou, the largest of these villages <sup><a href="https://en.jiemian.com/article/5492716.html">[3]</a></sup>.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="671" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/imposition-671x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3931" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/imposition-671x1024.jpg 671w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/imposition-768x1172.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/imposition-1007x1536.jpg 1007w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/imposition-1320x2014.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/imposition.jpg 1343w" sizes="(max-width: 671px) 100vw, 671px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>Recently however, Baishizhou, and the hundreds of other urban villages, have been under threat. Their numbers have been shrinking. Since 2005 the government has been closing down parts of Baishizhou <sup><a href="https://www.nytimes.com/2016/07/20/world/asia/skyscrapers-rise-in-china-mark-the-fall-of-immigrant-enclaves.html">[4]</a></sup>, and in 2017 plans were announced for a redevelopment of the entire site <sup><a href="https://iopscience.iop.org/article/10.1088/1757-899X/471/11/112058/pdf">[5]</a></sup>. In 2019 it was reported that its 150,000 residents had been asked to leave by September of that year <sup><a href="https://www.scmp.com/news/china/society/article/3019506/migrant-workers-forced-out-one-shenzhens-last-urban-villages">[6]</a></sup>.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="662" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5e-1024x662.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3932" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5e-1024x662.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5e-768x497.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5e-1536x993.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5e-1320x854.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="669" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5I-669x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3835" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5I-669x1024.jpg 669w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5I-768x1176.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5I-1003x1536.jpg 1003w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5I-1320x2021.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5I.jpg 1338w" sizes="(max-width: 669px) 100vw, 669px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Since my visit to Shenzhen in 2018, with mass evictions in 2019, the population of this village has shrunk considerably, with entire streets being closed off <sup><a href="https://shenzhennoted.com/2021/03/23/is-the-era-of-shenzhen-urban-villages-over/">[7]</a></sup>. It seems the fate of this space is sealed.</p>



<p>The conflict between these areas in the city manifests the moment and context from which they arise. People’s lives are subject to the overwhelming power of capitalism, and the city that it creates (china’s economic reforms are expressly capitalist, with the majority of land and productive power being owned by private entities <sup><a href="https://thediplomat.com/2017/10/xi-jinping-thought-vs-deng-xiaoping-theory/">[8]</a></sup>).</p>



<p>These urban villages came about as marginalised spaces within a wider vision for a modern, construction firm led cityscape. For a period of time, they were able to exist for their usefulness in facilitating the city’s economic boom in the new technological era, providing affordable homes for migrant workers coming from the country’s rural areas in search of work.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p> </p>



<p>The quasi-organic form these spaces took formed a powerful counter narrative to the premeditated city, which surrounds it. Densely populated and full of life, they sit in stark contrast with the atomised navigation of space that takes place in the rest of the city.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="669" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5KEDIT-1024x669.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3934" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5KEDIT-1024x669.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5KEDIT-768x502.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5KEDIT-1536x1004.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5KEDIT-1320x863.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>For the construction firms of the city, these plots of land represent massive financial incentive and opportunity. With property prices being exponentially high within the city, the potential profits of a redevelopment project are huge <sup><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/2023255/last-days-shenzhens-great-urban-village">[9]</a></sup>.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>And with no one in power to defend the interests of these residents, they are forced out into the surrounding province of Guangdong. It seems that the convenience of these places of living was considered too high for the low-income residents of the village, amongst the wealthy megacity.</p>



<p>Ultimately, Baishizhou only existed, as a fragment of the cities disjointed metamorphosis: from a small fishing village of just 30,000 to a megacity of 12.59 million in just 40 years <sup><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/2023255/last-days-shenzhens-great-urban-village">[9]<sup></sup></a><a href="https://www.bloomberg.com/news/features/2020-12-20/workers-flocking-to-china-s-silicon-valley-can-t-afford-to-buy-homes#:~:text=In%202018%2C%20the%20Shenzhen%20government,both%20for%20sale%20and%20rent.&amp;text=Authorities%20have%20also%20been%20experimenting,free%20apartments%20to%20skilled%20workers.">[10]</a></sup> &#8211; a process of growth leading to the end point of a total hegemony of space, and marginalisation of the working poor.</p>



<p>This process highlights fundamental dynamics in Chinese capitalism. China has been moving rapidly from a production oriented LEDC, to finance and business oriented MEDC, with a massively expanding middle class.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="671" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5j-671x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3940" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5j-671x1024.jpg 671w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5j-768x1172.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5j-1007x1536.jpg 1007w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5j-1320x2014.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5j.jpg 1343w" sizes="(max-width: 671px) 100vw, 671px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="685" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5bed-685x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3938" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5bed-685x1024.jpg 685w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5bed-768x1149.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5bed-1027x1536.jpg 1027w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5bed-1320x1974.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/5bed.jpg 1370w" sizes="(max-width: 685px) 100vw, 685px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>As such, less need for low paid workers has led to the further marginalisation of the working class. Despite this, Chinas economy still has a massive reliance on its productive capacity, and the inevitable move to the homogenous form of the city, causes direct harm to the companies that have defined the city’s tech boom <sup><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/2023255/last-days-shenzhens-great-urban-village">[9]</a></sup>.</p>



<p>“If Shenzhen loses its affordable housing, the whole chain will break. The industrial sector will hollow out, and for most of our start-ups, our design companies, and our tech companies, the cost of labour will go up, because almost all of their young workers live in the urban villages.” – Local Architect; Duan Peng (SCMP, 2016)<sup><a href="https://www.scmp.com/magazines/post-magazine/long-reads/article/2023255/last-days-shenzhens-great-urban-village">[9]</a></sup></p>



<p>With less housing for low paid workers, these companies face a shortage of employees. Here we can see how the state steps in to resolve the inherent flaws that arise from unregulated capitalism. In 2018 the CCP announced its solution; by 2035, 60% of its new housing supply would be government-subsidized. Currently, state-backed homes account for just 5% of the market <sup>[10]</sup>.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>Ultimately, these urban villages represent clearly how space, and the life that inhabit it, relate to forces beyond their control. It demonstrates a microcosm of the flux of life within cities; as people seek out work and a means to a good life, alongside the conflicts this gives rise to.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="670" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5L-2-1024x670.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3892" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5L-2-1024x670.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5L-2-768x502.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5L-2-1536x1005.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/5L-2-1320x863.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large baishi"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="664" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/baishizhousum2-1024x664.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3927" title="" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/baishizhousum2-1024x664.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/baishizhousum2-768x498.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/baishizhousum2-1536x996.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/baishizhousum2-1320x856.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large coord"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="351" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/coordinatessum-1024x351.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3916" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/coordinatessum-1024x351.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/coordinatessum-768x263.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/coordinatessum-1536x526.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/coordinatessum-1320x452.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/coordinatessum.jpg 2002w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written for <a href="https://www.instagram.com/jpf__photo/" data-type="URL">James&#8217;s</a> upcoming book &#8220;Fragments&#8221;. One of Five articles to be published to SUM.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../marginal-spaces/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Marginal Spaces &lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / “Any Black doctors avail&#173;able?”</title>
		<link>./../../../medical-racism/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=medical-racism</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 08 Jul 2021 19:30:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Thuli Jane Maseko]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3942</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> The historical anatomical othering of Black people has created healthcare services that are ill-equipped to care for Black patients <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2></span><span id=span3> The “race awakening” brought about by the murder of George Floyd last year ...</span><span id=span4></span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../medical-racism/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;“Any Black doctors avail&shy;able?”&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The historical anatomical othering of Black people has created healthcare services that are ill-equipped to care for Black patients, and yet another area of life where race is inescapable.</p>



<p>The “race awakening” brought about by the murder of George Floyd last year and the disparities in the Covid-19 impact between whites and BAME communities has, for some, spotlighted how Black people are let down by and systematically excluded from society’s institutions.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>One I find particularly disturbing is healthcare. Racism and the historical medical mistreatment of Black bodies have upheld ideas of Blackness as not only culturally other but humanly other altogether.</p>



<p>Black people experience higher levels of neglect and mistreatment by medical professionals, are haunted by erroneous anatomical beliefs fabricated by racists that still find their way into medical practice today, and, to make this game even more despicable, are put at increased health risk by the very same racism that makes seeking out healthcare so much harder for us.Black people know this, and medicine’s bright white history has left many mistrustful. So many of us are always ready for the potential awkwardness from the receptionist when we ask “do you have any Black doctors available?”</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="564" height="794" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/j.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4041"/></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>It shouldn’t be surprising that Black folks face discrimination and neglect when it comes to health services. The history of western medicine is white, male and riddled with atrocities committed on Black bodies. And the legacy of this history, as with all institutions in society, is still very much alive, still perpetuating the racism that’s been inherent in medicine since the colonisers colonised. There isn’t sufficient knowledge among healthcare workers in diseases like sickle cell, which predominantly affects those of African and Caribbean descent.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="782" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2-782x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3965" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2-782x1024.jpg 782w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2-768x1006.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ohno2.jpg 1063w" sizes="(max-width: 782px) 100vw, 782px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Medical schools aren’t training doctors to know how some illnesses present in people with Black skin, with some doctors going through their entire training without seeing examples of how common skin conditions like eczema appear on non-white skin.</p>



<p>One that’s been headlining recently is how pulse oximeters are more likely to miss low levels of oxygen in people with Black skin, resulting in Black patients being sent home when they should be hospitalised. “Historically medical education was designed and written by white middle-class men, and so there is an inherent racism in medicine that means it exists to serve white patients above all others,” leaving Black patients subjected to higher levels of neglect, mistreatment and death.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>A recent and tragic case involving a sickle cell patient is that of Evan Smith, who died after calling 999 from inside the hospital when he was denied oxygen after being told his blood saturation levels were healthy. The coroner ruled that the cause of Smith’s death was not receiving “a timely exchange transfusion”. A significant factor in the delay was “a lack of understanding of sickle cell disease in the medical and nursing staff looking after Mr Smith.” An alarming finding was that “nurses did not have specific training in managing sickle cell disease, despite serving an area with a large African and Caribbean community.” The coroner did not make a ruling of neglect.</p>



<p>There was a case at my local hospital, also in an area with a large population of African and Caribbean people, where a woman took herself with her new-born to A&amp;E and was sent home by hospital staff on a bus. It turned out she had developed sepsis a week after giving birth. A Black nurse who later heard about this said she immediately knew the woman was Black because such treatment was so commonplace.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Black people are mistreated and under-served in healthcare. This is a direct result of medicine’s racist history, for which not enough has been done to undo, and the subsequent implicit biases held by medical professionals and healthcare workers. As recently as the 1970s there were medical text books that stated Black people have a higher pain threshold than whites.</p>



<p>And as recently as 2016 a study from the United States found that many medical students “believed that black people’s nerve endings are less sensitive than white people and that black people’s blood coagulates quicker.” </p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="881" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-881x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4072" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-881x1024.jpg 881w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-768x893.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-1322x1536.jpg 1322w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7-1320x1534.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/parasumtamol7.jpg 1516w" sizes="(max-width: 881px) 100vw, 881px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>There have been other studies showing that “black patients are often prescribed less pain relief than other people, despite having the same conditions, and that applies to children too.” There are countless cases of Black patients being denied the care they need and are entitled to or having to fight a lot harder to receive it.</p>



<p>It was hard not to think about my own experiences and those of people close to me as I went through these stories of mistreatment and learnt even more about how deeply race impacted medicine and healthcare provision. When I hear that there are medical workers out there who think our blood coagulates quicker I can’t help wonder about a time I went to A&amp;E and instead of leaving with stitches I got a dodgy tape up that had reopened by the time I got home. I had to buy my own supplies and take care of the dressing myself.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="884" height="758" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pelwis8ioho.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4046" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pelwis8ioho.jpg 884w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/pelwis8ioho-768x659.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 884px) 100vw, 884px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>When I hear that our pain is perceived differently I can’t help think about the time when a doctor wouldn’t prescribe me pain medication for migraines. Maybe the hospital staff there were bad at their jobs, maybe it was an accident. Maybe that doctor genuinely thought I’d be fine if I watched my caffeine intake and tried to take paracetamol as early on as possible. The fact is I can’t not wonder if race played a part in these events. Especially when stories of Black people being treated differently are so widespread and seen in all areas of healthcare.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>An area that’s been receiving particular attention recently, also with a long history of neglecting Black people, is mental health care. In school, I saw white students getting access to services and being treated with more sympathy than my Black peers and myself. Even once in the system I’ve had friends report also feeling gaslit and treated with blatant disregard at points. Medication reviews feel one sided, symptoms are questioned and ignored, problematic behaviours are minimised.</p>



<p>Race can even make it hard to take the first steps in seeking out mental health services. Or, rather, the lack of provision within mental health services of sufficient resources for Black patients, such as POC therapists, can make this hard. “I would take anything right now not to feel the way that I did last night because it was awful,” a friend said to me, “and I know that I need therapy but I am not willing to go to a white therapist at this point in time.” Similarly to how a female assault victim would rather see a female therapist, a Black person who has been psychologically impacted by the frequent traumas of racism would rather see a Black therapist to discuss these things. The fact that healthcare services don’t think about this shows they don’t think about Black patients and their experiences.</p>



<p>I know these are services that are already strained but when Blackness is such a common denominator among those let down by them it’s impossible not to look at race as part of the reason for these failings. The recent deaths of Olisa Odukwe and Richard Okorogheye serve as yet more tragic reminders that while Black folks are let down in all areas of healthcare, mental health is one which seems to particularly fail and exclude us time and time again. In the words of @lookingformothermax, “young Black people’s lives should not be cut short before they are afforded access to, and inclusivity in facilities and services… the face of mental health advocacy and campaigning should not and cannot only be white middle-class people.”</p>



<p>The health disparities highlighted by Covid-19 won’t be going away once the pandemic is over (nor did they only come to exist when it started), and if negative health outcomes resulting from racial bias aren’t spoken about they never will. We need more research into how race impacts health outcomes. Data needs to be gathered so problems and solutions can be identified. As long as the experiences of Black people are ignored and gaslit by society and by documents like the Sewell Report, they’ll be ignored and gaslit by our doctors.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="658" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1024x658.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4013" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1024x658.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-768x493.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1536x986.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri-1320x848.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/uteri.jpg 1601w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>And for those who lack certain levels of humanity and need these issues framed in the context of how wider society is affected for them to mean anything to you, vaccine hesitancy among BAME communities is a direct result of the mistrust these groups have of the medical establishment because of its racist past and present. It might not make sense to some why people would trust their barber or pastor over the CDC, but would you trust someone who time and time again has demonstrated that they don’t have your best interests at heart?</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Thuli Jane Maseko, to keep up with her work follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thuliijane" data-type="URL">Intagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../medical-racism/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;“Any Black doctors avail&shy;able?”&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / The Facism of the Israeli State</title>
		<link>./../../../israeli-state/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=israeli-state</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 02 Jun 2021 17:40:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Max Coleman]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3602</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> My social media feed has been dominated by videos from Gaza of babies blown limb from limb, whole families<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> wiped out by a single missile and entire media buildings being </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> destroyed. Without the bravery of Palestinians who have opted to risk death in order to ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../israeli-state/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;The Facism of the Israeli State&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>My social media feed has been dominated by videos from Gaza of babies blown limb from limb, whole families wiped out by a single missile and entire media buildings being destroyed. Without the bravery of Palestinians who have opted to risk death in order to go outside and film these scenes to show the world their pain, we would be blind to the atrocities of the Israeli State.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Kashfi-Halford-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3605" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Kashfi-Halford-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Kashfi-Halford-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Kashfi-Halford-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Kashfi-Halford-1320x881.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Gaza, 2014 [<a href="http://www.kashfihalford.com/">Kashi Halford</a>]</figcaption></figure>



<p>As a result, I have felt compelled to write this article in which I hope to exemplify the similarities between the most evil state in European History, with the very country that was created in response to its atrocities. Before starting I would like to say that this is by no means targeting Jewish people, but instead the Zionist project and Netanyahu’s current far-right Israeli regime, whose methods of indoctrination, control and brutalisation echo the tragedies of history. It is also not the first and I am sure it will not be the last country to create such discriminatory laws (the British Empire did this many times and were an integral part of the Zionist project in Palestine).</p>



<p>I write this without prejudice; I am not Jewish or Muslim, Palestinian or Israeli but instead a fair-minded observer of the facts and, in my opinion, the similarities between the techniques and strategies of the two oppressive regimes stand out to me astonishingly. Thus, I will do this by first examining the incredibly successful propaganda machines of both countries; secondly the tactics of dehumanisation and justifications both regimes have used for their targeted ethnic groups; and finally the ways in which this led to the ethnic cleansing in their respective countries.</p>



<p>The UN General Assembly of 1975 determined zionism to be “a form of racism and racial discrimination.” Yet the strength of the Israeli propaganda machine indoctrinates many, not only in Israel, but especially in places such as the USA, with the Zionist ideals of a commitment to the unquestioning defence of Israel and a deep entitlement to the Palestinian homeland despite their origins as white Europeans. Not only do they propagate pro-Israeli propaganda but also an anti-Arab message that promotes discrimination and apartheid.&nbsp; In January 2020, the Israeli Ministry of Strategic Affairs donated $40,000 to the American anti-Muslim hate group <em>Proclaiming Justice to the Nations.</em> Palestinians have been evicted, tortured, brutalised, exiled and dehumanised yet through Israel’s worldwide propaganda, and huge lobbying of foreign governments, they have successfully remained the victim in the media’s eyes.</p>



<p>Comparably, Nazi propaganda put all Germans in an awkward position – the idea being that if you loved the motherland then you hated the Jews. They utilised Joseph Goebbels’ propaganda machine to indoctrinate millions of people into supporting the Nazi party through starting from an early age at the Hitler youth camps, strict censorship and consistent messages of racial superiority. Although the Nazi’s efforts were far more virulent there are obvious similarities between the two which are both, after all, far-right regimes.</p>



<p>Zionist philosophies are ingrained from a young age through biased education, and then reinforced with every Israeli citizens’ requirements to do three years of military service where a nationalist ideology is instilled in order to protect from the ‘other.’ The Israeli Military Censor will then censor any material that threatens the security of Israel, thereby, any publications coming from Palestinian land protesting their unfair treatment. Just as the Nazis hid their treatment of Jews from their citizens and the world, Israel has been hiding the brutalising of Palestinians successfully for decades however it is threatened by the advent of social media. It is for this reason Palestinian media, electricity and internet has been a major target.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="681" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WEST-BANK_Justin-Mcintosh-1024x681.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3606" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WEST-BANK_Justin-Mcintosh-1024x681.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WEST-BANK_Justin-Mcintosh-768x511.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WEST-BANK_Justin-Mcintosh-1536x1021.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/WEST-BANK_Justin-Mcintosh-1320x877.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>West Bank [Justin Mcintosh]</figcaption></figure>



<p>When footage of Palestinians being killed is inevitably shared with the world, Israeli-backed propaganda is quick to point the finger at Palestinian aggression. Hamas is often the main subject of contention as it has been labelled a terrorist organisation by many western governments, and their rocket fire has been used to justify the senseless killing of thousands of innocent palestinian men, women and children. The reality of this situation however is more nuanced than the medias representation, palestinians have been subject to extraordinary levels of brutality since 1948.</p>



<p>And with the overwhelming military force placed on them by the israeli military, an armed response is to be expected, as dissilusioned palestinians chose to fight for their freedoms. Hamas fail to differentiate between anti-Zionism and anti-Semitism in their covenants and have resorted to suicide attacks, yet their designation as a terrorist group is arguable as their attacks target civilians no more than Israeli attacks do. Of course, their militant rule is by no means benign however it is a well known fact that extremism is a result of poverty thus Israel’s blockade of Gaza is directly responsible for Hamas’ inception.</p>



<p>Western governments and media sit on the fence as to who is to blame because Israel provides a lot of trade (Biden has agreed a $735m sale of weapons this May and the UK’s exports of arms have reached record levels) despite the fact that twenty times more Palestinians are killed than Israelis. Not only does this exemplify why western governments are unwilling to condemn the actions of Israel no matter how gruesome, but also the enormous repertoire of weapons that Israel is arming itself with to fight the blockaded, poverty-stricken people of Gaza.</p>



<p>One way the Nazis justified their actions towards Jews was to dehumanise them so their maltreatment would not be so offensive. The 1935 Nuremberg Laws designated Jews as second-class citizens because of their ‘impure blood.’ It was a way of persuading the German population that their actions were reasonable and justified because they were an inferior people to Aryan Germans. Through repetition, indoctrination and propaganda the German people were brainwashed into believing these bogus notions to such an extent that many worked at the Jewish death camps overseeing the deaths of millions of people. To dehumanise someone is to ignore their humanity and once that can be achieved on a widespread scale the systematic cleansing of people becomes justifiable, and thereby, accepted.</p>



<p>Netanyahu’s regime has achieved this in the eyes of many Israelis, especially their military. Palestinians are dehumanised in the media and at the highest roles in government in order to facilitate the continued evictions and widespread brutaliastion of Palestinian people. Here are a selection of quotes from some high ranking ministers in the Israeli government:</p>



<p>“Beat them up, not once but repeatedly, beat them up so it hurts so badly, until it’s unbearable.” &#8211; Benjamin Netanyahu, Israeli Prime Minister, 2001</p>



<p>[The Palestinians] are like animals, they aren’t human. A Jew always has a much higher soul than a gentile.” Eli Ben-Dahan, Former Deputy Minister of Defence, 2013</p>



<p>“I’ve killed many Arabs in my life, and there’s no problem with that.” &#8211; Naftali Bennett, Former Member of Knesset, 2013</p>



<p>“They are all enemy combatants, and their blood shall be on their heads, they should go, as should the physical homes in which they raised the snakes, otherwise more little snakes will be raised there.” &#8211; Ayelet Shaked, Former Justice Minister, 2014</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-English-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3608" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-English-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-English-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-English-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-English-1320x881.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Inspecting the Destruction, Gaza, 2009 [<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/aljazeeraenglish/3372653098/in/photostream/">Al Jazeera</a>]</figcaption></figure>



<p>Dehumanisation has been a strategy used by the oppressor for centuries through a mix of bogus eugenics, propaganda, philosophy and rewritten histories. Catholics were dehumanised by the British in Britain and Ireland; African people were dehumanised for centuries by white Europeans as a way to justify their enslavement and, of course, Jews have been dehumanised throughout history, but most notably during Nazi rule. Current Israeli tactics are nothing new but, I have used this comparison because the Holocaust has been used by defenders of the Israeli regime as a way to justify their acts of terror through a god-given right to that land. It has even been used as an excuse for revenge:</p>



<p>In 2015 at the Zionist Congress Netanyahu made the accusation that the Palestinian Grand Mufti of Jerusalem, Haj Amin al-Husseini, was responsible for the Holocaust because he told Hitler to burn the Jews instead of expelling them to Israel which is a pure falsehood. Netanyahu not only stooped to the depths of lying during his speech but he also exonerated the Nazis of coming up with the Holocaust. His hatred for the Palestinian people is so great that he is willing to absolve Hitler of full responsibility in order to increase the support for a continuation of attacks on the Palestinians out of a bloodlust for revenge. This is the reason why I have compared the Israeli regime with the Nazi regime; one cannot and must not use their own persecution as a justification to persecute others.</p>



<p>During the ghettoisation of Jews throughout the German Empire houses were either labelled with the star of David, robbed or burnt to the ground and the people who lived or worked inside of these buildings were moved to unsanitary, overcrowded ghettos where many died of disease, starvation, and brutal maltreatment. This anti-semitism was as a result of Hitler using Jews as a scapegoat for losing the First World War. Their brutalisation was then justified through a systematic publication of propaganda that dehumanised and vilified Jews within the German Empire. Jews were rendered second or third class citizens. The propaganda mobilised the German population to accept and support the racially targeted persecution and mass murder of Jews. The long process of dehumanising a certain group in the eyes of the public prepares this public to accept the most brutal and criminal measures against them.</p>



<p>Now when we talk about Israel, its inception and its propaganda campaigns it is hard to avoid the shocking similarities that surface. The Palestinians have been treated as second or third class citizens as well since the early creation of Israel by war in 1948. During that war around 700,000 Palestinians were forced by armed Zionist organisations from their homes and expelled from their own country as Israel took control of the UN-sanctioned Palestinian territories. Those who did not leave the country were given Arab Israeli citizenship which, in theory, gave them equal rights to Israelis. Those who remained in East Jerusalem, the West Bank and Gaza were subject to life under an occupying power. These Palestinians are technically stateless and so cannot vote, gain passports (thereby leave or return) are subject to constant searches and roadblocks and those in Gaza are threatened by indiscriminate bombing and an illegal blockade.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="768" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/blhphotography-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3609" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/blhphotography-1024x768.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/blhphotography-768x576.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/blhphotography-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/blhphotography-1320x990.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>&#8220;Israeli Peace&#8221;, 2002 [<a href="https://www.flickr.com/photos/blhphotography/406354353">blhphotography</a>]</figcaption></figure>



<p>Since 1948 the Israeli people have been aggressively grabbing Palestinian land properties within the newly established state. After the second war in 1967 the same policy of stealing the land intensified in the West Bank, the Gaza Strip and East Jerusalem in violation of international law. This is undertaken as a result of Zionist principles that is simply cloaked settler colonialism. As more Palestinian land is expropriated, more Palestinian inhabitants are thereby forced into fleeing to refugee camps in the surrounding countries or into the Gaza Strip. Just as Germans who benefitted from the forceful evictions of Jews were comforted by the blanket of being part of the superior Aryan race, Israelis who benefit from the forceful evictions of Palestinians are comforted by the blanket of Zionism and its doctrine.</p>



<p>This is why the Gaza Strip, which is 200㎢ smaller than the Isle of Man has a population that is 25 times larger than it at over two million. The blockade, imposed since 2007, around the territory has repeatedly stopped construction materials and fuel from entering, cut off all electricity, restricted food and water, medical assistance, and COVID vaccines, all the while preventing Palestinians from leaving. The UN declared that the Strip is ‘unlivable’ because of the worsening conditions of all aspects of human life. It does not take someone with an anti-Israeli agenda to see the similarities of a ghettoised Jewish camp of 1940 to the entire Gaza Strip in 2021.</p>



<p>Palestinians are literally forced out of their homes and businesses in exactly the same way Jews were in the 1930s and 40s, and a police or army presence will always side with the Israeli aggressor giving the Arabs nowhere to turn. Yes, Israel are not shipping Palestinians to death camps but they are slowly cleansing the country of the Palestinian ‘threat.’ And it is at times of violence and uprising such as this when indiscrimate killing of Palestinian men, women and children become easier for the Israeli State to justify. They claim to be acting in defence (even when their bombs target schools and hospitals) so as to remain the victim in this so-called conflict. We in the West are only made aware of the Zionist killing machine when their slow and silent cleansing is intensified to war and bombs.</p>



<p>Of course, the Nazis committed far more atrocities and were responsible for the worst genoicde in human history, however I hope I have exemplified ways in which the Israeli far-right regime shares many similarities with that of the Nazis. They are steadily cleansing Palestinian territories of Palestinians, forcing them abroad or into the open air prison that is the Gaza Strip; they rely heavily on state funded anti-Muslim and pro-Zionist propaganda and they use bogus sceince and history to dehumanise Palestinians in order to justify their brutal acts.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-1024x683.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3610" width="799" height="532" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-1024x683.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-768x512.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-1536x1025.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/06/Al-Jazeera-1320x881.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 799px) 100vw, 799px" /><figcaption>Gaza Burns, 2009 [<a href="https://he.wikipedia.org/wiki/%D7%A7%D7%95%D7%91%D7%A5:Gaza_Burns_-_Flickr_-_Al_Jazeera_English.jpg">Al Jazeera</a>]</figcaption></figure>



<p>I want to again reiterate that this is by no means intended to be anti-Jewish but instead a criticism of the Zionist project and the current Israeli regime. It is important that we are not silenced when talking about Israel and its crimes because of a fear of seeming anti-semitic. That is the most common refute to criticism of Israel and thus, derails the intended point of the conversation which, ultimately, is not a religious one at all, but a human one. It is a story of oppressor versus oppressed not of Jews versus Muslims and thus, it is vital that we stand with the Palestinians who are merely fighting for their most basic human rights.</p>



<p>“Every single member of my family on both sides were exterminated [in the Holocaust]… it is because of the lessons my parents taught me and my two siblings that I will not be silent when Israel commits its crimes against the Palestinians. I consider nothing more despicable than to use their suffering and their martyrdom to try to justify the torture, the brutalisation, the demolition of homes that Israel daily commits against the Palestinians. So I refuse any longer to be intimidated by the tears. If you had any heart in you, you would be crying for the Palestinians.”</p>



<p>-Norman Finkelstein, an American Jew speaking at the University of Waterloo, Canada.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Written by Max Coleman, who you can follow on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/maxcoleman4/" data-type="URL">Instagam</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../israeli-state/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;The Facism of the Israeli State&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Short Story /  Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.2)</title>
		<link>./../../../birds-two/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=birds-two</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 15:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Grace King]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Like most Londoners, Gary the pigeon held a permanent expression of being<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> mildly pissed off. To maintain his persona of relentless irritability </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4>, there was an abundance of things to be pissed off about ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../birds-two/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Short Story &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.2)&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-above-right">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Achingly tender, Stella was a star among seagulls. There were no words to describe the beauty she possessed. Her feathers were still damp from the fountain. She was all white apart from a line of feathers down by her neck that faded from white to grey. A sexy, discreet shade of grey. She stretched out her wings with a flirtatious flutter. She hadn’t imagined the first day after moving to the city would result in meeting a handsome stranger. He was gentle and introspective, qualities Stella admired in a bird. Not like all the cocks she’d met back in Brighton.</p>



<p>Gary had invited her on a tour of London and Stella felt like the unassuming star of a new Netflix rom-com.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3412" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-768x768.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-200x200.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg-1320x1320.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/05/birds-of-a-rpg.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p><a href="https://www.sumweekly.com/birds-of-a">(Part 1 here)</a></p>
</div>
</div>



<p>The scope possibility was more tangible than ever. Her life was about to reach new heights and if the early bird gets the worm, Gary was ready to make this flighty decision for good.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>The number 24 floated north at a pleasantly drowsy speed. London was fully awake, but as Gary and Stella sat on the roof of the bus heading out of London’s epicentre, they were not overwhelmed by noise and flashing lights. Instead, skyscrapers turned to houses and businessmen to shop owners. Trafalgar became Oxford Circus which became Warren Street which morphed into Camden High Street. While they sat, they began to chat. They talked about home and about family. Stella was originally from Brighton. Raised as seaside gulls, London was an unfamiliar place to them. Stella told Gary about her dad who’d left for Devon when she was young for better chips. She told him about this guy she dated a year before you decided to leave for London. He was a pelican called Nigel who’d spent too many years alone at sea that he’d completely forgotten what commitment meant.</p>



<p>Gary listened enchanted. The inconsistencies, slurs and sloppiness of her speech was so endearing. He told her about his own family. His New York cousins, Berkshire Grandparents, Camden lads and Percy, the grime artist gone cuckoo. They talked about government, global ethics, whether the Marxist revolution will ever happen and if it will solve the problem of the bin strikes.</p>



<p>“I just sometimes feel as though everyone is forgetting how big the world actually is, and we just need to start being a bit more Bon Jovi, you know what I mean? It’s like what my nan used to say, God bless her, ‘Don’t be a tit, but have the courage of an eagle and eyes like a hawk’. She was right you know, I wish there were more birds like her in our skies. Have you ever been to New York to visit your cousins? I’d love to go to America! Heck of a long flight though! That’s another thing about my nan, that is, she never flew outside of Brighton. Not once. I don’t think that’s right, Gary. I mean, like, today. I came to London to take hold of my future and my music and here I am with you. Crazy, isn’t it?! S But anyway Gary, I really like you, I do. Not everyday you meet a pigeon who can show you around London on the top of the bus! Is this our stop?”</p>



<p>“Yeah,” Gary said.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>Finally, they arrived at the top of Primrose Hill. Before him Gary saw a city so full of colours his tiny pigeon head nearly exploded. Never had everything been in such high definition. People walking, sitting, running, talking, laughing, feeling. Gary wasn’t just some passive spectator, watching the world unfold around him, he was here with Stella under his wings, real and alive.</p>



<p>“Why do you think we met, Gary?” Stella asked, her question assuming a philosophical edge that Gary was uncertain of.</p>



<p>“I don’t know, Stella. But I’m happy we did. Whatever cosmic force is bringing us together, I’m grateful. If it’s just fate, then perhaps my opinion of determinism has brightened.”</p>



<p>“Oh Gary, you’re such a romantic! I wish I didn’t have to say goodbye.”</p>



<p>“Why do you mean?” Gary hadn’t meant for his voice to be so panicky, but as soon as the words were said, the air changed.</p>



<p>“I’m a seagull Gary! I eat candy floss 4 times a day, is candy floss even vegan?! You’re a city bird, a high-flying Londoner. This wouldn’t work.”</p>



<p>At that point, 16:32 Wednesday afternoon, Gary realised the meaning of life. The world is full of impossibilities, but we can choose to stay perched on our fears forever or we can spread our wings and fly straight through them. Some birds we’re willing to risk our lives for. Others fly right by. Gary knew he’d found the Robin to be his Batman.</p>



<p>“Stella, today has been the best day of my life. I don’t want it to end. You’re so beautiful and funny and kind and the way you pronounce ‘almond’ makes me laugh. I woke up this morning after an evening of sitting on a lamppost. Now I don’t ever want to sit down again! I want to fly everywhere, see everything! Come fly with me, Stella. What do you say?”</p>



<p>“Yeah, ok.” said Stella.</p>



<hr class="wp-block-separator is-style-default"/>



<p>Unlike most pigeon-seagull relationships, Gary and Stella find their differences bring them closer together rather than further apart. Gary migrated to Brighton and has enjoyed pioneering the gentrification of Brighton’s pier. Percy did not continue in the music industry and now lives in Waterloo station. Kelly died of a heart attack and Danny drank himself to death after having a nasty accident with a British Airways plane on his way home and falling, mouth open into the Atlantic.</p>



<p>London and Brighton are both places spilling with colours, without a dash of grey to be seen. This means for Gary that each morning when he wakes up, still with an expression of being mildly pissed off, he turns and sees Stella. She is a painting, iridescent with colour. She is hope, she is tomorrow.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Part 2 coming next week! To keep up with Graces&#8217;s work, follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/gracelouiseking/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>, illustration by <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sketchbook_of_verity/" data-type="URL">Verity Hayhow</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../birds-two/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Short Story &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/ &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Birds of a Different Feather (Pt.2)&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food / When the Maql&#173;ouba is Flip&#173;ped</title>
		<link>./../../../maqlouba/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=maqlouba</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 17:14:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Yusuf Ali]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3217</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> When the Maqlouba is flipped, you will almost always let out a cheer of joy<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>. The large silver pot is turned upside down on the table and everyone</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> gathers round eagerly waiting for the reveal. Will the shape of the rice hold together? What has the cook put inside this particular ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../maqlouba/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Food &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;When the Maql&shy;ouba is Flip&shy;ped&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1024x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3242" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1024x1024.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-768x768.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1536x1536.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-200x200.jpg 200w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/nikki-1320x1320.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>When the Maqlouba is flipped, you will almost always let out a cheer of joy. The large silver pot is turned upside down on the table and everyone gathers round eagerly waiting for the reveal. Will the shape of the rice hold together? What has the cook put inside this particular version? The pot is lifted and the beautiful dish is revealed. There are different variations of maqlouba, but to describe it simply, it is a dish of Palestinian origin (which is also found across the Levant) consisting of rice, vegetables, and often meat. </p>



<p>It is arranged in layers and steamed to create a beautiful mould inside the pot. It is then flipped to serve, with the key ingredients cooked at the bottom to then appear at the top for the guests to marvel at. There are a few main variations of Maqlouba; chicken, lamb, fish and also vegetarian. The differences will appear with their own array of vegetables that pair well, as well as being dependent on its region. For instance, Maqlouba with fish is most commonly served in the south of Palestine due to the abundance of fish on the coast. This is similar to many regional dishes such as Jollof rice which will be prepared using different ingredients depending on the country you eat it in.</p>



<p>When the Maqlouba is flipped, we see the layers of its history, layers which have dated back to around the 12th Century. A popular story of its origin refers to the conquest of Jerusalem by Salaheddin Al Ayubbi. A very significant figure in the 12th Century, he was the founder of the Ayubbid empire, which at the height of its power ruled over large parts of the Levantine region. When he entered Jerusalem, he was greeted by the locals with the dish. </p>



<p>At the time it was referred to as ‘bazenjaniyah’, coming from the root word of ‘Bazenjan’ which means Aubergine in classical Arabic, a key ingredient in the dish. When Salaheddin saw the theatrical motion of the pot being flipped, he renamed the dish ‘Maqlouba’ which literally means inverted/upside down. Naturally, this dish has grown to mean more than the ingredients it contains. People of all faiths who have descended from centuries of lineage in Jerusalem will view Maqlouba as a symbol of their right to the city.&nbsp;</p>



<p>When the Maqlouba is flipped, it exudes an energy of defiance and symbolism which is unparalleled. During the Trump presidency, he recognised Jerusalem as the capital of Israel, a decision which was heavily contested in the region. Jerusalem is a heavily controlled region and so while physical protests would be strongly controlled, Maqlouba was used as a symbolic form of protest. Women sat outside of the walls of the Al-Aqsa mosque, flipping pots of maqlouba and serving it to the demonstrators. In any other circumstance this may be seen as a very common practice of support.</p>



<p>However, knowing the history of this dish we can see that they were using Maqlouba as a metaphor, serving the dish as it was served to their historical leader Salaheddin. A subtle but powerful message that they will always hold the city to be theirs. Maqlouba isn’t the only food which is used as a form of protest; watermelons have also been used in opposition to the IDF soldiers. Palestinians have previously walked the streets of Jerusalem with watermelons cut open. The vibrant reds, blacks and greens of the watermelon bearing the colours of the flag which is disallowed from being raised in certain areas.</p>



<p>While the issues between Palestine and Israel have remained a subject of the highest controversy in society&#8217;s discourse, it does not take away from the main messages raised in this piece. As I mentioned in <a href="https://www.sumweekly.com/fried-chicken">‘The Fried Chicken Stereotype’</a>, food holds the value it does because of our personal connection to it. Through the African Americans, fried chicken meant survival, and was one of the only forms of economic growth immediately after the emancipation. For the Palestinians, Maqlouba is a physical representation of their right to their home. The knowledge that a dish which you hold central to your identity, outlives modern conflicts by centuries is a tool more powerful than any signed law.</p>



<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/1gjhocgQ5Wc" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Yusufs Maqlouba Recipe:</span></p>



<ul class="marginbottom"><li>600 bone-in chicken pieces</li><li>2 Tbspn Salt</li><li>1 Tbspn Black Pepper</li><li>1 Tbspn Cumin</li><li>1 Tbspn Cardamom Powder</li><li>1 Tbspn Pimento Powder</li><li>1 Tbspn Cinnamon Powder</li><li>1 Tbspn Coriander Powder</li><li>1 Head of Cauliflower</li><li>500g Potatoes</li><li>3 Medium Carrots</li><li>300g Basmati Sella Rice</li><li>2 tbsp toasted pine nuts</li></ul>
</div>
</div>



<p>1. Season your chicken using all the spices and fry in a large pot before covering with water and allowing it to boil.</p>



<p>2. Soak the rice in cold water for 25 mins</p>



<p>3. Whilst the chicken is boiling, cut up your veg into small pieces, fry until gold.</p>



<p>4. Remove the chicken from the water and cook the rice 75% of the way in the same water. Drain the rice and reserve half a glass of the stock.</p>



<p>5. Layer a wide pot with the veg at the bottom, chicken, and then sprinkle the rice on top, packing down. Cover with a small amount of stock so the bottom doesn’t stick and simmer for 20 minutes.</p>



<p>6. LET IT REST for 10-15 mins before flipping onto a plate or tray, carefully lifting the pot and garnishing with pine nuts.</p>



<div id="footer">Yusuf makes fantasic, insightful videos on the art of cooking, recipes and the history behind food, which you can find on his YouTube channel <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCaPzQQzAG_dXEDXNxbfAPsA" data-type="URL">&#8216;Sliced&#8217;</a>. You can also follow him on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/sliced_yt/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagam</a> to keep updated with his work.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../maqlouba/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Food &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;When the Maql&shy;ouba is Flip&shy;ped&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Article / Deco&#173;lonising Geog&#173;raphy</title>
		<link>./../../../decolonising-geography/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=decolonising-geography</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 20 Apr 2021 00:22:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bola Ogundipe]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=3006</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> To decolonise geography we need to think about the colonial histories that<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> have influenced geography as a discipline. Past colonial and imperialist legacies</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> are rife in modern day society, leaving a range of institutions that need to be decolonised ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../decolonising-geography/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Deco&shy;lonising Geog&shy;raphy&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" id="dcghead"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="696" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/1-1024x696.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3107" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/1-1024x696.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/1-768x522.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/1-1536x1043.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/1-1320x897.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>To decolonise geography we need to think about the colonial histories that have influenced geography as a discipline. Past colonial and imperialist legacies are rife in modern day society, leaving a range of institutions that need to be addressed. Furthermore, we need to critique the past, present and future of colonial and imperialist legacies that influence society and the disciplines and institutions we enter on a day-to-day basis.</p>



<p>The oppression of Indigenous people and their landscapes, along with the indignity this creates, is still common today, demonstrating that we must remain critical about anti-racism and a post-racial society  – we need to look beyond the current perspectives that result from the way Indigenous peoples and ethnic minorities are currently being represented in society. </p>



<p>We also need to understand what intersectionality is and how to decolonise this. There is much imperialistic and colonial oppression on these types of queer geographies that can have an effect on our ontological (nature of being) and epistemological (theory of knowledge) viewpoint of this type of geography.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="696" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.2-1024x696.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3110" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.2-1024x696.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.2-768x522.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.2-1536x1043.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/2.2-1320x897.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>So how do you decolonise geography? It’s very important to understand geography is a subject that has ties to imperialist and colonial rule. Geography needs to be acknowledged as being a part of a history that built the British Empire and its colonial efforts. To decolonise geography means to take the subject apart piece-by-piece and show how much impact it has had over different timeframes and scales. This could stretch all the way to when colonists first came into existence, forward to how the topic is represented today. To begin with, it’s important to understand there are many aspects in geography that need to be reflected upon. </p>



<p>Methodology is a key concept that should be to be looked into, as the way indigenous and BAME people are researched is constantly oppressing them, through a colonial and imperialist presence. When it comes to research, it needs to be understood that these focus groups are not guinea pigs or some sort of lab experiment to be tested on, and it’s important to recognise when being around these groups of people, their knowledge about what is being researched on is just as important as finding out the data that needs to be produced. </p>



<p>When looking at Indigenous Australia, this has been at the forefront of colonial history, which has constantly seen the denial of Indigenous homelands. Indigenous people have been consistently ignored by the Australian government, and this continues in modern day society. Indigenous Australians have the right to govern their own lands and be given their own sovereignty they deserve, not only because it’s a part of their history and ancestry but because self governance and autonomy are intrinsic rights for communities that demand them.</p>



<p>Australia is a country that has been at the centre of colonial histories with constant discrimination and prejudice towards the Aboriginal people. The British denied indigenous Australians sovereignty by illegally possessing the country that was embodied by the crown of England. Contextually, the crown had full occupation of the Australian territory and patriarchal domination was ever present in excluding and denying what was rightly owned by Indigenous Australians. However, this is continued into the present day, as we still see Indigenous Australians being denied their land, along with the political, cultural, and socio-economic responsibility to control it. This is their right, yet we still see colonial settlers destroy and replace their lands with a new political order. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="696" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/mask-1024x696.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3075" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/mask-1024x696.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/mask-768x522.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/mask-1536x1043.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/mask-1320x897.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>The Uluru Statement (2017) highlights the contemporary issues Indigenous Australians continue to face, with propositions for constitutional change and structural reform to return what is rightfully theirs. Indigenous Aboriginals deserve a right in their say for the future, it’s clear there needs to be a focus on constitutional recognition to assert Indigenous sovereignty and to look at the past on how colonial rule has led to the voices of Indigenous Aboriginals being unheard.</p>



<p>Diasporas is an emerging concept within societies that migration has affected. The decolonisation of the concept of Diasporas has shown that the phenomenon is not only the case within Indigenous countries, but also a situation that is happening in Western societies as well.</p>



<p>Countries such as Scotland, Northern Ireland and Wales are starting to realise they do not represent the imperialist ideology of the United Kingdom and are increasingly seeking to draw away from the UK, in part because it is not aiding the development of their countries, rather, their countries could economically develop quicker without the UK. Furthermore, identities formed from a basis of political divergence have helped to divide the kingdoms of Britain.</p>



<p>Decolonisation also extends to other key spaces, such as that of museums, where it has enabled clear critiques and demands about the origins of the materials and artefacts that have been contained within museums for centuries. The decolonisation of museums needs to acknowledge the collections of the slave trade. Further, the content of museums and galleries does not represent national demographics, and this must be addressed.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="782" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/3-1-1024x782.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3114" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/3-1-1024x782.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/3-1-768x586.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/3-1-1536x1172.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/3-1-1320x1008.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Tolia-Kelly (professor of geography) examines how the gallery space can become a “theatre of pain.” an experience that promotes violence and genocide, leaving the artefacts lifeless. She contests that the museum embodies racial and ethnic stereotyping, elements that possess zero academic merit. Many paintings lack the appreciation of how some ethnic faces might be represented, giving them a false depiction that adds to the colonial oppression within these institutions. </p>



<p>Another example is the on-going issues related to identity, space and place regarding public art within post-apartheid South Africa. In contrast to the issues with museum collections, knowledge production art can help open new narratives that were once neglected in the past. Some engagement into history, memory and space can recreate the ideas of the city to conceptualise a better future.</p>



<p>Kimberlé Crenshaw (civil rights activist and philosopher), describes intersectionality as “trying to address rhetorical failures in politics, feminism and anti-racism”. Analysing intersectionality in society and it&#8217;s institutions is important because there is clear systemic oppression of feminism, class, culture and queer identities. Through racial violence and its gendered and sexualised politics, we live in a society where violence against women is not acknowledged by the capitalist powers that run society.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this, black feminism is also further excluded. There needs to be an understanding in creating more spaces for women of colour within the feminist movement so there can be an acknowledgement of self-identity, so women of different colour can build communities together and have a general consensus, without the role of colonial feminism.</p>



<p>Australian sociologist Raewyn Connell writes about the dilemmas in feminism going global, and looks at how the minority of feminists are starting to challenge the perpetuation of women’s oppression by radical liberal feminists. This provides a detailed overview of “intersectionality” and the reason it needs to be decolonised, because there are still inequalities and multiple forms of oppression within the feminist movement.</p>



<p>Lastly, Afro-futurism is a new idea that develops a significant empowerment for Afro-Heritage people. The idea was coined by Mark Dery (an American author), and has seen a number of science-fiction TV programmes and movies being created. Most notably, the movie Black Panther has recently increased the interest in Afro-futurism.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="1024" height="685" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/4-1024x685.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-3112" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/4-1024x685.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/4-768x513.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/4-1536x1027.jpg 1536w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/04/4-1320x883.jpg 1320w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>Similarly, Black Mirror episodes have also seen a rise in a number of Afro-heritage actors taking up Afro-futuristic roles, and Anthony Mackie’s performances in Altered Carbon on Netflix and Marvel’s Capitan America have also contributed to this. In everyday life black people are constantly oppressed, these movies and TV programmes promote the culture of Afro-American and Black British traditions that create a form of resistance to the capitalist powers that try to oppress people from these backgrounds.</p>



<p>It’s very important to develop an understanding of Afro-futurism, and how this can help BME people survive the present. The term “Wakanda” comes from the movie Black Panther and this creates and celebrates a connection of community that feels like home for people of BME heritage. It’s important to recognise this imagination because BME people are not represented in the attractive ideology of the future. When decolonising postcolonial futures in film, we need to enforce BME futures that discover the different designs that can be built of the things Afro-heritage people currently hold, and their traditions.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
Article written by Bola Ogundipe, illustrations by <a href="https://www.sumweekly.com/tag/james-farrant" data-type="URL">James</a>.
</div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../decolonising-geography/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Article&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Deco&shy;lonising Geog&shy;raphy&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
