<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Joelle Robinson - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 21:58:36 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Joelle Robinson - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Music / BaggE</title>
		<link>./../../../bagge/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=bagge</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 09 Mar 2021 15:18:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Music]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joelle Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BaggE]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2052</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> BaggE is an upcoming Neo-Soul artist from North London. whose music <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>features a soothing, raspy voice, with soulful undertones. Her uplifting</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> music stems from messages of self-love. She is truly an artist to watch ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../bagge/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Music&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; BaggE&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/jNDShU6UFzY" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<p>BaggE is an upcoming Neo-Soul artist from North London. Her music features a soothing, raspy voice, with soulful undertones. Her uplifting music stems from messages of self-love. She is truly an artist to watch!</p>



<p>We sat down with BaggE for a catch-up and to discuss her music:</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Joelle:</span> Hey BaggE how&#8217;ve you been? What you&#8217;ve been up to?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">BaggE:</span> I&#8217;ve have been good. Um, what is there to be up to really? I&#8217;ve been watching a lot of RuPaul&#8217;s drag race. It&#8217;s so good. The British one.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Yeah. And I think UK one bangs, I have to say, I feel like they&#8217;re just much more Savage. Who&#8217;s your favourite?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> I think tasty and A&#8217;Whora. I love A’Whora.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> So, have you managed to stay creative in this lockdown?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> I don&#8217;t know. I think, cause it&#8217;s just like no end in sight it was hard, but now that we can see and end it&#8217;s been pushing me a bit more. But it&#8217;s been hard, nothing to give you that push really.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Absolutely, lockdown brings a lot of pressure to be doing things. Let&#8217;s get stuck in then &#8211; So tell everyone a bit about yourself!</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="679" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/bagg-679x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2139" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/bagg-679x1024.jpg 679w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/bagg-768x1158.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/bagg.jpg 940w" sizes="(max-width: 679px) 100vw, 679px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Whats 3 words to describe your music?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Hmm. I don&#8217;t know. I feel like it&#8217;s changed at the moment. I feel like back back in like my first ever EP &#8216;Preserving the Prior&#8217;, I felt like that was very chilled out and slow. Whereas &#8216;What About Summer&#8217; my latest EP is a bit more dancy. And then the tracks I&#8217;m doing right now with Barney Dwyer, is more dancy. And I feel like I&#8217;m seeing the sun and I&#8217;m getting a bit more excited. So my music I would say is, is dancy a word?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Yeah. You can make it a word.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Well then &#8211; dancy, easy and sunny.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> I like that. Do you know, reinvent, reinvent the dictionary? I feel like it does describe music quite well. And I feel like also you&#8217;re right. It doesn&#8217;t have to be like static, three words because everyones music evolves And I feel like I shouldn&#8217;t feel the need to talk to like stick to one sort of category. So who would you say inspires you?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Oh, so many. I know this is going to sound really weird, but I inspire myself a lot. like, I feel like when I do write, it&#8217;s a lot about my, the circumstances I&#8217;m in at that exact time. Listening to my past music and looking at where I am now and how much things have changed around me, inspires me a lot and inspires me to sort of change, and experiment with my sound to see how that, that fits in with BaggE. Also, you got like the greats, like Jill Scott and Erica Badu, and Ella Fitzgerald. And when Charlotte&#8217;s Dos Santos, she&#8217;s so sick and not a lot of people know about her, but she&#8217;s super sick.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> So would you say BaggE as an artist is constantly evolving?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Yeah. I mean, I feel like every artist is still evolving. I don&#8217;t know. Like even let&#8217;s say like Beyonce, even she&#8217;s making &#8216;The Carters&#8217;, they&#8217;re like reinventing their sound and stuff like that. So I feel like I&#8217;ll always be evolving, but I feel like I always do have my sound. I&#8217;ll always go back to the way I write. And I do have a sort of standard with who I work with and the producers that I work with.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="678" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PHOTO-2021-03-09-15-13-46-678x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2056" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PHOTO-2021-03-09-15-13-46-678x1024.jpg 678w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PHOTO-2021-03-09-15-13-46-768x1159.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PHOTO-2021-03-09-15-13-46-1018x1536.jpg 1018w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/PHOTO-2021-03-09-15-13-46.jpg 1060w" sizes="(max-width: 678px) 100vw, 678px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Right. Do you set time aside for writing or do you sort of do it on the go? Like while you&#8217;re on the move on the bus?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> No, not really. Like, um, I find it really cool when people say that they sit on a train and they start just writing lyrics and I&#8217;m like, I just, I don&#8217;t know what it is. I feel like anyone that knows me kinda knows, my mind goes a hundred miles a minute hahaha.</p>



<p>I can&#8217;t imagine myself sitting on a train and writing lyrics, I&#8217;ll get distracted by everything. So I kind of just like sit down, I have like a little set up in the other room and I kind of listen, I get sent some beats.</p>



<p>So I go through beats and I pick ones I like and start writing to it, or I find beats of YouTube. Write. It, and then find a producer to remake the beat behind it. But I need to like set, set time aside to do music. Like I feel like I can&#8217;t just do it on the go really.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Fair enough. I guess some people just have to be in the zone and sometimes it comes out that way. I feel like that&#8217;s like me, I&#8217;m not, I&#8217;m not an artist. I don&#8217;t make music, but if I have to do something, it has to be like dedicated time to do it. I can&#8217;t just like, I&#8217;m like you though, my brain is always just moving in every direction&#8230;</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> What message do you want to give out through your music?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> I think, self-love, I feel like a lot of my writing, is about getting out of situations that you&#8217;re not comfortable in that you&#8217;re not being inspired by and being around people that aren&#8217;t good for you. And feel like what I&#8217;ve learned within the past two years is you gotta work on yourself before you try and work on anyone else. </p>



<p>So I suppose just self-love and self-acceptance and learning how to deal with your emotions. If someone was listening to my music, I&#8217;d want them to work out their emotions and sort of have my music help them, which I feel like music should do. Should provoke feelings that make you understand what&#8217;s going on in yourself. Cause it can sometimes be odd.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J: </span>Yeah, I hear that. I really like that as a message for your music, because it&#8217;s definitely how I feel when listening to it. Your &#8216;Stalker&#8217;, what was the message behind that? Did you actually have a real stalker?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> So my whole thing with this is I&#8217;m not going to talk about what &#8216;Stalker&#8217; is about. I wanted people, make up their own narrative about it. So (laughs) it&#8217;s about you want it to be about. I feel that everyone could take it in different ways. It could be literal. It could be what&#8217;s the opposite of literal non-literal yeah.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Is the music video out yet?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> No, not yet. We&#8217;ve penciled in the 12th March.</p>



<p>J: Nice! looking forward to seeing it! Are you working on anything else at the moment?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> I have some music&#8217;s in the works with Barney Dyer who did &#8216;Can&#8217;t keep fighting you&#8217;. We&#8217;ve got like a summer track coming out. I got another song coming out with Ty green and I got a song with Chuck Enzo and RADA that we&#8217;re working on. So I got like three releases this year, not including a music video.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Nice so you&#8217;ve got a busy summer. What is your favourite song at the moment for this summer?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> So basically, so I&#8217;ve been walking and when I walk, I&#8217;ve got to listen to something that&#8217;s quick, so I can walk quick or I&#8217;ll dilly dally and I&#8217;ll walk really slow. So I&#8217;ve recently liked the song &#8216;Up&#8217; by Cardi B, but then I heard all this controversy about her stealing the song. And then I searched up the song that she apparently stole, which is &#8216;Stuck&#8217; by Mir Pesos and Mir Fontane. And it&#8217;s literally exactly the same. ANYWAY, I&#8217;ve been listening to &#8216;Stuck&#8217; now. (Laughs).</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Wow I didn&#8217;t know that. I agree with you on the music whilst walking thing. Sometimes like sometimes I put on really intense music so I can get where I need to be. So lastly, Aside from music, what is one thing you love during your spare time?</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="679" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_from_ios-679x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2090" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_from_ios-679x1024.jpg 679w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_from_ios-768x1159.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_from_ios-1018x1536.jpg 1018w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image_from_ios.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 679px) 100vw, 679px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Cooking! I looove cooking.</p>



<p>J: Aren&#8217;t you vegan?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> No, I&#8217;m veggie I love cheese too much. I don&#8217;t think I could be vegan.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Yeah. It&#8217;s a, it&#8217;s a hard life. I&#8217;m lactose intolerant and I just don&#8217;t stick to it (laughs) because cheese makes me happy.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Oh, that&#8217;s so sad!</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> So, how does your style define you as an artist?</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Growing up, I was really inspired by my brother. Cause my brother&#8217;s older than me and he dresses like a skater boy. And I was like, Oh, he dresses cool. So I suppose I got my started off my core style from him. And then, and then I it just branched off and then I looked at like FKA, twigs. I love her. </p>



<p>Yeah, I suppose it does link to me as an artist because, this sounds really shallow, but when you go and watch someone live, you want to see a cool costume. You don&#8217;t want to see them in like a plain white t-shirt and some skinny jeans, bit boring. </p>



<p>Also I got my name BaggE from wearing baggy clothes and people used to always ask why aren&#8217;t you where tight-fitting clothes and show off your body. Because it&#8217;s uncomfortable! I want to be comfortable in my baggy clothes. So yeah it does intertwine with my music. It&#8217;s funny a lot of people call me loads of things like, I had to put on my Instagram how to say it because people call me bag, Baschet, Baggé So had to add the capital &#8216;E&#8217; to help people out.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">J:</span> Aw well it&#8217;s been lovely chatting with you BaggE, I&#8217;m looking forward to watching the &#8216;Stalker video when it&#8217;s out! thanks for chatting with me.</p>



<p><span style="text-decoration: underline;">B:</span> Thank you! You&#8217;re welcome. It was really fun.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p> 
BaggE’s latest music video &#8216;Stalker&#8217; will be out on the 12th March, follow her <a href="https://www.instagram.com/baggeofficial_" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>, or <a href="https://twitter.com/baggeofficial_" data-type="URL">Twitter</a> to stay posted.</p>



<div id="artistlinkwrap">
<div id="artistlink">
  <a href="https://open.spotify.com/artist/4ZO0hWTm3mUwCVF1BlELp8" data-type="URL" class="muslink spotify"><div id="muslinktext">Spotify</div></a>
  <a href="https://music.apple.com/us/artist/bagge/251099027" data-type="URL" class="muslink apple"><div id="muslinktext">Apple Music</div></a>
  <a href="https://www.deezer.com/en/album/178601442" data-type="URL" class="muslink deezer"><div id="muslinktext">Deezer</div></a>
  <a href="https://soundcloud.com/bagge99" data-type="URL" class="muslink soundcloud"><div id="muslinktext">Soundcloud</div></a>
  <a href="https://music.amazon.co.uk/albums/B08KZ922H5?tag=featurefmuk-21" data-type="URL" class="muslink amazon"><div id="muslinktext">Amazon</div></a>
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/channel/UC-FMvL6x2vM9KETP_b-5F4w" data-type="URL" class="muslink youtube"><div id="muslinktext">Youtube</div></a>
</div>
</div>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-video aligncenter bordertoponly  albumart"><video controls src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/VIDEO-2021-03-09-15-14-06.mp4"></video></figure>
</div>
</div>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with BaggE, follow her on<a href="https://www.instagram.com/baggeofficial_" data-type="URL"> Instagram</a>, or <a href="https://twitter.com/baggeofficial_" data-type="URL">Twitter</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../bagge/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Music&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; BaggE&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/VIDEO-2021-03-09-15-14-06.mp4" length="1915668" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Docu&#173;mentary / Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&#173;bow</title>
		<link>./../../../kamali/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=kamali</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joelle Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sasha Rainbow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap>
Kamali is a Bafta-nominated short film, about a kick-ass young skateboarder with a <span id=span1>...</span><span id=span2>beautiful story to tell. Kamali is a 7-year-old girl from a small fishing village in</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> Mahabalipuram, India. She is the only female skateboarder in her village, where a skate ramp was built right outside her house…<span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kamali/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;mentary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&shy;bow&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xzlXrVqMtNY" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<p>Kamali is a Bafta-nominated short film, about a kick-ass young skateboarder with a beautiful story to tell. Kamali is a 7-year-old girl from a small fishing village in Mahabalipuram, India. She is the only female skateboarder in her village, where a skate ramp was built right outside her house.  The film also follows the story of her mother, on a pilgrimage of self-discovery after leaving an abusive relationship. This short film directed by Sasha Rainbow&nbsp;is an insight into how India&#8217;s gender roles are changing for the younger generation. </p>



<p>Joelle: How would you describe the concept of the film?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sasha: Kamali is about a single Indian mother&#8217;s fight for her daughter&#8217;s empowerment through skateboarding. It&#8217;s about the cycle of empowerment disrupting the status quo for everyone involved.</p>



<p>J: How did you cross paths with Kamali?</p>



<p>S: I made a documentary music video for a British Band&nbsp;The Wild Beastswhich featured the new generation of female skaters in India. After seeing a picture of Kamali in a little dress, 6 years old, blasting down a ramp, I knew she had to be in the video. We tracked her down while we were in India and managed to convince her and her mum to leave their village for the first time and come to the big city of Bangalore, where they stayed with us and Kamali experienced her first real skatepark.<br><a href="https://vimeo.com/199716710" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://vimeo.com/199716710</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot2019-03-26at16.30.21-edited.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2011" width="665" height="413"/></figure>



<p>J: Can you tell us a bit about how Kamali got into skateboarding?&nbsp;</p>



<p>S: A skate crew&nbsp;called Hollystoked built a tiny ramp outside Kamali&#8217;s house when she was about 5.&nbsp;Because her uncle was a surfer, she was already playing on the board with him in the water, so I guess she was also attracted to the board on land. There they all share boards. One day pro skater Jamie Thomas was passing through the village and saw Kamali and&nbsp;ended up staying a few days, taught her to drop, and left her his board. The photo I first saw of Kamali was of this moment. The rest is history as they say!&nbsp;</p>



<p>J: What does Kamali symbolise to you and how can she inspire others across the world, regardless of age?</p>



<p>S: Kamali symbolizes hope for the future as an unquestionable example&nbsp;of what females can achieve when they&#8217;re allowed to play and explore their passions freely. Because, as we see in the film, this doesn&#8217;t just affect one person, it affects the whole community by changing the narrative of what can and can&#8217;t be done.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2017" width="661" height="373" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433.jpg 770w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 661px) 100vw, 661px" /></figure>



<p>J: What were some highlights on the set of filming Kamali, is there a moment that will stick with you? Did you also come across&nbsp;any challenges?</p>



<p>S: The whole experience of filming Kamali was a world unto itself. We were able to step into another person&#8217;s existence for a moment in time, in this case, a whole&nbsp;family&#8217;s. That&#8217;s unique and doesn&#8217;t happen every day. Often when you travel it&#8217;s very fleeting or can be superficial, but we got to stay long enough for the days to be their own mini existences, to get to know the locals and travelers to the even smaller villages and mooch around in the heat with good company, to the point that we almost felt like the camera was another extension of the group. It was tough not speaking the same language but that&#8217;s when I really understood how much communication is around body language and tone more than anything. It informed how we filmed and proved to be the truest guide. I often wonder what the film would have been like had I understood everything being said around me.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="756" height="472" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image-asset-edited.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-2013"/></figure>



<p>J: How is Kamali now, are you still in touch?</p>



<p>S: Kamali is growing up to be an amazing 10-year-old. She still surfs and skates and her English is fantastic.&nbsp;She has such a sweet, kind, intelligent soul.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m very excited to have a beer with her when she&#8217;s a bit older and ask what the experiences of her youth were like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>J: Having you got any upcoming projects?&nbsp;</p>



<p>S: I&#8217;ve switched documentary gears and I have been writing since lock-down, something I&#8217;d been hoping to do. I&#8217;ve got a mystery comedy set in Hollywood on the go and am working on a family comedy in New Zealand which I&#8217;m very excited about. </p>



<p>Thank You!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-1024x717.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2016" width="798" height="558" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-1024x717.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-768x538.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 798px) 100vw, 798px" /></figure>



<div id="footer"> 
Head over to <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/archive/in/entry/kamali-documentary-skateboarding-sasha-rainbow_in_5da5749be4b0058374e83151" data-type="URL">Huffington Post</a> for the full film. If you&#8217;d like to hear more from Sasha, she will be participating in an interview for International Women&#8217;s Day, which You can keep by following her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/itssasharainbow/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kamali/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;mentary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&shy;bow&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview / Phoebe Lang&#173;ley: From; Jordan</title>
		<link>./../../../phoebe-langley/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=phoebe-langley</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joelle Robinson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> We sat down with filmmaker Phoebe Langley Gussin on her latest <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> documentary ‘and Now What? - From, Jordan’. This short piece was commissioned by<span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> Roundhouse Theatre and is a time capsule made for a friend, Jordan, a 21-year-old male from South London at the ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../phoebe-langley/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Interview &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Phoebe Lang&shy;ley: From; Jordan&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure id="widevideo" class="wp-block-video"><video controls poster="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fromjordanposterimg.jpg" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/From-Jordan.mp4"></video><figcaption>From; Jordan / Phoebe Langley / 2019</figcaption></figure>



<p>We sat down with filmmaker Phoebe Langley Gussin on her latest documentary ‘and Now What? &#8211; From, Jordan’. This short piece was commissioned by the Roundhouse Theatre and is a time capsule made for a friend, Jordan, a 21-year-old male from South London at the beginning of his gender transitioning story. Her film is a soft and honest account of the experience of Jordan navigating transitioning in his hometown.</p>



<p><strong>P:</strong> My name’s Phoebe, I’m a filmmaker, but during COVID I’m a motion graphic designer and work a bit on podcasts with visual design and branding. I’ve been doing that for roughly a year based in South-east London.</p>



<p>It’s my first and only doc I’ve done. We shot in December last year [2019], which feels like a long time ago.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> How was the filming process, did it run smoothly?</p>



<p><strong>P:</strong> It was a little hard actually, I didn&#8217;t know what to expect. But it was funded, and I had mentorship within the Roundhouse. I had a mentor called<strong> Nia Childs</strong> who is also a filmmaker and does documentary-based work, it was really helpful to have her. It was quite a short turn around, we got awarded funding in October and had to show it in December.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong>&nbsp; Did you have an idea before you got the funding?</p>



<p><strong>P:</strong> I had the idea whilst doing a course with them, but it was definitely a huge learning process. I knew during production I wanted to work with people I already knew, as I felt it makes the process easier.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> Where did the subject matter come from?</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>Me and Jordan have been friends for years. We went to school together, so we already had a relationship and then we lost contact, going to different colleges. We then rekindled our friendship and spoke about how we wanted to document his transition, initially not to be shown, it was just for him. We didn’t think it was going to be commissioned or anything, so it’s nice.</p>



<p><strong>J: </strong>&nbsp;In the future would you keep with the same documentary style?</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>I think so yeah, it’s funny right after we screened it a lot of people were like what’s your next thing, but my heart was in this project for so long. I don’t want to make something for the sake of it, I want it to be more organic.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> Definitely, you can kind of tell when a story is close to someone a lot of love goes into it.</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>Making a film on someone else’s life, it’s important to remind yourself that it has to be a collaborative project, it can&#8217;t just be exploiting someone&#8217;s story, that’s not what a documentary is about. Speaking with Jordan he wanted to make this film because when he was younger there was no one on screens that he looked like or he in any way could resonate with so it was one of the main aims of the film. It&#8217;s important to establish that when going forward in making documentary, it’ll be a collaboration.</p>



<p><strong>J</strong>: What was the course at the Roundhouse, perhaps others could benefit from it too?</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>Yeah the course is amazing! I mean before it I was working in a chocolate factory, It really opened a lot of doors…It’s called the Bloomburg broadcast, hopefully it’s still running. It’s a 6 week course for 18-25 year-olds and all about the life broadcasting they do at the Roundhouse, for producing, editing, you learn so much it&#8217;s great.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> That’s amazing, when you have ideas that you really want to execute, having backing from an organization like the Roundhouse is great, and has allowed you to make such a lovely and polished piece. We love it!</p>



<div id="footer">To stay updated about future projects by Phoebe, follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/phoebe_langley/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/phoebe_langley?lang=en" data-type="URL">Twitter</a>. Interview by <a href=" ./../index.html" data-type="URL">Joelle</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../phoebe-langley/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Interview &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Phoebe Lang&shy;ley: From; Jordan&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/From-Jordan.mp4" length="265229693" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
