<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Film - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 29 Nov 2021 19:40:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Film - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Film / The Black Makers</title>
		<link>./../../../black-makers/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=black-makers</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 24 Nov 2021 15:47:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Making Numbers]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=4922</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Making Numbers is a creative group focusing on meeting makers in the community <span id=span1>...</span><span id=span2> and around the globe.  The Making Numbers team recently released a short <span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> film celebrating and showcasing 30 black makers from the UK …<span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../black-makers/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Film&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;The Black Makers&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/BSioah7Xikg" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<p><strong>“The black makers, trail makers, risk takers, money makers, life savers, game changers surpassing every expectation”</strong></p>



<p>Led by the multi-talented Rasaq Kukoyi, Making Numbers is a creative group focusing on meeting makers in the community and around the globe. Their&nbsp; positive platform not only aims to entertain but but also encourages people to have aspirations, take pride in what they do and have their voice heard.</p>



<p>The Making Numbers team recently released a short film celebrating and showcasing 30 black makers from the UK, talking about what they do &amp; their experience as a black maker in the creative industry&#8230;</p>



<p><strong>Film Credits&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Directed by @rasaq_kukoyi&nbsp;</p>



<p>Edited by @tompablo_&nbsp;</p>



<p>Videography @louisfoster_ @rasaq_kukoyi&nbsp;</p>



<p>Produced by @makingnumbers @rasaq_kukoyi&nbsp;</p>



<p>Assistant producers @julie_amariah &amp; @deedee.baiden&nbsp;</p>



<p>Spoken word @tatendax&nbsp;</p>



<p>Interviewer @mira.hxs&nbsp;</p>



<p>Music by @ekabeats @rasaq_kukoyi</p>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with Making Numbers, follow them on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/makingnumbers/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../black-makers/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Film&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;The Black Makers&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Docc&#173;umen&#173;tary / Dedic&#173;ated to Those Who</title>
		<link>./../../../dedicated-to/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=dedicated-to</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jul 2021 16:17:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Baghead Rosen]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Jules Retzlaff]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=4209</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> Hailing from San Francisco, Baghead is young producer whos beats and compositions create<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2>soundscapes reminiscent of the sampling gods. His latest album</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> ‘Dedicated to Those Who’ was released in conjunction with a film that explores the relation ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../dedicated-to/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docc&shy;umen&shy;tary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Dedic&shy;ated to Those Who&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/cWmX3Y5GnP8" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<p>Hailing from San Francisco, Baghead is young producer whose beats and compositions create soundscapes reminiscent of the sampling gods. His latest album ‘Dedicated to Those Who’ was released in conjunction with a film that explores the relation between community, revolution and artistry while highlighting the uniqueness and vibrancy of a city in danger of losing its soul.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>Where did the idea for this project come from? Did you always plan to release the album together with the short film?</strong></p>



<p>The project was always going to be attached to some visual elements, ‘Dedicated to those who’was a concept I thought of around 3 years ago. The beats I originally made didn’t make the final cut and instead were released on earlier projects.</p>



<p>My first thought was to shoot three separate videos for the beats on the album, then the director <a href="https://www.julesretzlaff.com/">Jules Retzlaff</a> had the idea to put the whole thing together into a movie.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="480" height="476" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/bagheadhi2.png" alt="" class="wp-image-4225"/></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p><strong>The film explores the uniqueness and vibrancy of the SF community, how has it felt to see your city change over the years due to gentrification?</strong></p>



<p>Watching San Francisco change over the years has been heart-breaking… but it’s also provided the passion and fire up our ass to speak up about the changes we see here. We felt that if we created a film that exposes the cruelty and lack of care for the people of San Francisco, while celebrating the beauty of the city that lies beneath all this tech and big money… we felt like that we could leave something that gives a visual experience, a way to feel our city.</p>



<p>So it sucks!&nbsp; It sucks to see our city change the way it has, but it’s good to recognise that even amongst these crazy changes and all the displacement there’s something beautiful here. It means a lot and is very powerful…regardless of how much we’ve lost.</p>



<p><strong>You say SF can be more Zuckerberg’s city than the People’s city, have you seen any resistance to the growing conformity and elitism in your town?</strong></p>



<p>There’s been a TON of resistance in the past few years. There was the <a href="https://eastbayexpress.com/from-frisco-5-to-frisco-500-equiptos-hunger-strike-is-galvanizing-a-movement-against-police-brutality-2-1/">Frisco 500</a> which is a movement against police brutality sparked by the killing of Mario Woods and the general treatment of people of colour at the hands of the SFPD.</p>



<p>&nbsp;There’s also been a lot of work against gentrification, such as anti-displacement and anti-eviction movements. There’s community work being done to help feed families which can’t afford the rising costs of living in an expensive city…. Folks like <a href="https://missionmealscoalition.org/">Mission Meals</a><strong> </strong>and <a href="https://www.podersf.org/">Poder</a> who are either feeding people or creating spaces where people can grow their own gardens etcetera. So yeah there’s a lot of community work going down in the city that stands against the corporate greed that blankets our city.</p>



<p><strong>Your music reminds me of the chop-god <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=-Sg-O6N0vfI">Knxwledge</a> and other sampling greats, who were your influences when developing your style?</strong></p>



<p>Yeah I guess I’m kind of a walking cliché in that sense. Knxwledge is one of my biggest influences… Madlib, J-Dilla. Early on when I first really got into hip-hop my top 5 was J-Dilla, Madlib, MF DOOM, RZA and Pete Rock. Nowadays I still love those folks but as you say I’m heavily influenced by Kxnwledge. I listen to a lot of Earl Sweatshirt and Mick Jenkins, that kind of Trap-Soul but still very sample heavy Hip-Hop.</p>



<p><strong>Who would you love to work with inside and outside of your genre?</strong></p>



<p>The first goal is to make the artists that I work with become the artists that musicians I would respond to this question with. My folks like Professor Gable, MC Paws, A1… there’s so many artists that I work with, and those are the people I look up to.</p>



<p>Looking at more established artists, I’d love to work with Larry June, Freddie Gibbs, Earl Sweatshirt<strong>. </strong>Outside of my genre people like <strong>SIR</strong> or <strong>Blast</strong>… soul and R&amp;B kind of guys. I’d also love to score films, I like putting music to visuals, putting my beats behind a video.</p>



<p><strong>What&#8217;s your process when working on a project?</strong></p>



<p>I usually lead with the name, <strong>‘Dedicated to Those Who’</strong> was a concept I thought of, and as I picked the name I tried to go deeper into what that name meant for me. From there I look through what I have, I’m always making new music and I’m always trying to bring my best music to a project, while using tracks that make the most sense in the concept that I’ve built. So I just sit there for days picking and choosing beats…</p>



<p>I’ll sit there and find all those things that make sense to me inside of the album… cutting and pasting where they should go, arranging all of these little pieces, kind of like creating a film. I’m influenced by albums like Madvillianyand Piñata, albums which feel like a film to me.</p>



<p><strong>What are you plans for the future, any new projects coming up?</strong></p>



<p>I’ve got a lot of artists that I’m working with at the moment…. me and A1 just released <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=1SskbQhV0Ac">a single </a>with more music on the way. And there are other artists which I don’t wanna jinx just yet!!</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img loading="lazy" width="640" height="640" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ab67616d0000b273f4c0a1d48599a3b7d49ab239.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-4227" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ab67616d0000b273f4c0a1d48599a3b7d49ab239.jpg 640w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/07/ab67616d0000b273f4c0a1d48599a3b7d49ab239-200x200.jpg 200w" sizes="(max-width: 640px) 100vw, 640px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<div id="artistlinkwrap" class="marginbottom">
<div id="artistlink">
  <a href="https://open.spotify.com/album/7K0fbfpLY5pAHEpeufulJB" data-type="URL" class="muslink spotify"><div id="muslinktext">Spotify</div></a>
  <a href="https://music.apple.com/ca/album/dedicated-to-those-who/1545287808" data-type="URL" class="muslink apple"><div id="muslinktext">Apple Music</div></a>
  <a href="https://www.deezer.com/en/album/193907252" data-type="URL" class="muslink deezer"><div id="muslinktext">Deezer</div></a>
  <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=iBt7_5_-qLY&amp;list=OLAK5uy_ms5cVshDnnwVD-mJ9YJPlu0V9B5rlzrxc" data-type="URL" class="muslink youtube"><div id="muslinktext">Youtube</div></a>
  <a href="https://music.amazon.com/albums/B08QTSRVM2?do=play&amp;ref=dm_ws_dp_ald_bb_phfa_xx_xx_xx" data-type="URL" class="muslink amazon"><div id="muslinktext">Amazon</div></a>
</div>
</div>
</div>
</div>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with Baghead&#8217;s work, you can follow him on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/baghead.osk/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../dedicated-to/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docc&shy;umen&shy;tary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; / &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Dedic&shy;ated to Those Who&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Docu&#173;mentary / Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&#173;bow</title>
		<link>./../../../kamali/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=kamali</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Mar 2021 19:01:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joelle Robinson]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Sasha Rainbow]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2008</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap>
Kamali is a Bafta-nominated short film, about a kick-ass young skateboarder with a <span id=span1>...</span><span id=span2>beautiful story to tell. Kamali is a 7-year-old girl from a small fishing village in</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> Mahabalipuram, India. She is the only female skateboarder in her village, where a skate ramp was built right outside her house…<span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kamali/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;mentary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&shy;bow&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="ytoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe loading="lazy" width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/xzlXrVqMtNY" frameborder="0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;width:100%;height:100%;" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div>



<p>Kamali is a Bafta-nominated short film, about a kick-ass young skateboarder with a beautiful story to tell. Kamali is a 7-year-old girl from a small fishing village in Mahabalipuram, India. She is the only female skateboarder in her village, where a skate ramp was built right outside her house.  The film also follows the story of her mother, on a pilgrimage of self-discovery after leaving an abusive relationship. This short film directed by Sasha Rainbow&nbsp;is an insight into how India&#8217;s gender roles are changing for the younger generation. </p>



<p>Joelle: How would you describe the concept of the film?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sasha: Kamali is about a single Indian mother&#8217;s fight for her daughter&#8217;s empowerment through skateboarding. It&#8217;s about the cycle of empowerment disrupting the status quo for everyone involved.</p>



<p>J: How did you cross paths with Kamali?</p>



<p>S: I made a documentary music video for a British Band&nbsp;The Wild Beastswhich featured the new generation of female skaters in India. After seeing a picture of Kamali in a little dress, 6 years old, blasting down a ramp, I knew she had to be in the video. We tracked her down while we were in India and managed to convince her and her mum to leave their village for the first time and come to the big city of Bangalore, where they stayed with us and Kamali experienced her first real skatepark.<br><a href="https://vimeo.com/199716710" target="_blank" rel="noreferrer noopener">https://vimeo.com/199716710</a></p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Screenshot2019-03-26at16.30.21-edited.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2011" width="665" height="413"/></figure>



<p>J: Can you tell us a bit about how Kamali got into skateboarding?&nbsp;</p>



<p>S: A skate crew&nbsp;called Hollystoked built a tiny ramp outside Kamali&#8217;s house when she was about 5.&nbsp;Because her uncle was a surfer, she was already playing on the board with him in the water, so I guess she was also attracted to the board on land. There they all share boards. One day pro skater Jamie Thomas was passing through the village and saw Kamali and&nbsp;ended up staying a few days, taught her to drop, and left her his board. The photo I first saw of Kamali was of this moment. The rest is history as they say!&nbsp;</p>



<p>J: What does Kamali symbolise to you and how can she inspire others across the world, regardless of age?</p>



<p>S: Kamali symbolizes hope for the future as an unquestionable example&nbsp;of what females can achieve when they&#8217;re allowed to play and explore their passions freely. Because, as we see in the film, this doesn&#8217;t just affect one person, it affects the whole community by changing the narrative of what can and can&#8217;t be done.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2017" width="661" height="373" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433.jpg 770w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Leisure-Sep2-21-x433-768x432.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 661px) 100vw, 661px" /></figure>



<p>J: What were some highlights on the set of filming Kamali, is there a moment that will stick with you? Did you also come across&nbsp;any challenges?</p>



<p>S: The whole experience of filming Kamali was a world unto itself. We were able to step into another person&#8217;s existence for a moment in time, in this case, a whole&nbsp;family&#8217;s. That&#8217;s unique and doesn&#8217;t happen every day. Often when you travel it&#8217;s very fleeting or can be superficial, but we got to stay long enough for the days to be their own mini existences, to get to know the locals and travelers to the even smaller villages and mooch around in the heat with good company, to the point that we almost felt like the camera was another extension of the group. It was tough not speaking the same language but that&#8217;s when I really understood how much communication is around body language and tone more than anything. It informed how we filmed and proved to be the truest guide. I often wonder what the film would have been like had I understood everything being said around me.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="756" height="472" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/image-asset-edited.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-2013"/></figure>



<p>J: How is Kamali now, are you still in touch?</p>



<p>S: Kamali is growing up to be an amazing 10-year-old. She still surfs and skates and her English is fantastic.&nbsp;She has such a sweet, kind, intelligent soul.&nbsp;&nbsp;I&#8217;m very excited to have a beer with her when she&#8217;s a bit older and ask what the experiences of her youth were like.&nbsp;</p>



<p>J: Having you got any upcoming projects?&nbsp;</p>



<p>S: I&#8217;ve switched documentary gears and I have been writing since lock-down, something I&#8217;d been hoping to do. I&#8217;ve got a mystery comedy set in Hollywood on the go and am working on a family comedy in New Zealand which I&#8217;m very excited about. </p>



<p>Thank You!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-1024x717.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2016" width="798" height="558" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-1024x717.jpg 1024w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3-768x538.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/Kamail_Poster_Sasha_Landscape_v7-3.jpg 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 798px) 100vw, 798px" /></figure>



<div id="footer"> 
Head over to <a href="https://www.huffpost.com/archive/in/entry/kamali-documentary-skateboarding-sasha-rainbow_in_5da5749be4b0058374e83151" data-type="URL">Huffington Post</a> for the full film. If you&#8217;d like to hear more from Sasha, she will be participating in an interview for International Women&#8217;s Day, which You can keep by following her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/itssasharainbow/?hl=en" data-type="URL">Instagram</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kamali/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;mentary&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kamali Film by Sasha Rain&shy;bow&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Doccu&#173;mentary / DJAO by Loïc Phil</title>
		<link>./../../../djao/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=djao</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 26 Feb 2021 20:36:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Chulu-Chinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Loïc Phil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1812</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> DJAO is a poignant short film depicting the life of a young migrant from the Ivory Coast named <span id=span1> ..</span><span id=span2> Mamadou. The film finds a balance between the weighted emotions</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> of Mamadou's life, whilst finding small moments of solace in his love of dance as a form of self-expression...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../djao/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Doccu&shy;mentary &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;DJAO by Loïc Phil&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="vimeoyo2" style="position:relative;"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/413128181?color=d42929&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;height:100%;" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>



<p>DJAO is a poignant short film depicting the life of a young migrant from the Ivory Coast named Mamadou. It expresses the struggles of his past and how he tries to navigate relocating to France, whilst bearing the weight of being undocumented. The film finds a balance between the weighted emotions of Mamadou&#8217;s life, whilst finding small moments of solace in his love of dance as a form of self-expression. We sat down with the director Loïc Phil to discuss the work behind the moving film.</p>



<p>Noah: So tell me about DJAO. How did you go about making it, how did this start?</p>



<p>Loïc: The original idea was to make some nice soft thing and I didn&#8217;t have many ideas. I wanted to make something about dance actually. I also had a friend of mine who was a part of an association whose goal is to build a network, linking people, a solidarity network. So the idea is if you are poor, or maybe a migrant, you don&#8217;t have commitments, life is hard&#8230; but it will be a lot easier if you have all your people around to help you. Even just a friend or people to advise you. The goal was to make solidarity among people. I asked if maybe we could make a documentary mixing dance and migration. So she told me that they had a workshop and they had made a show where migrants were dancing. There was one guy, Mamadou, I learned that he could dance and he had kind of a weird energy. So she gave me his contact and then we met and we talked. And then we decided to make the documentary.  It was really supposed to be more linked to dance you know? Like half dancing and the rest was supposed to be around migration.</p>



<p>N: And so then it morphed into more of a study about this particular person?</p>



<p>L: Yeah. So basically what happened is, so first it&#8217;s a stupid thing, but I think it it had lots of impact on the film. The first thing is that, during this period, there were lots of big strikes in France, where all the transportation was closed and then everything else was closed, so it was a shitty moment to organise parties for dancing. No-one was going to the parties because there was no buses or transportation. So that removed slightly the dancing part. The other thing that happened was, when we started to talk about the film he was waiting for his documents. And when you are waiting for the documents, you have paper documents that says you are illegal. At the middle of the pre-production his documents weren&#8217;t sorted, so he started to be defined as undocumented. So what started as &#8220;He can move wherever he wants&#8221;, &#8220;He can do whatever he wants&#8221;  turned to be &#8220;oh shit, we are stuck and we cannot move in the same way&#8221;, he couldn&#8217;t go out of the house. He was really scared of meeting the police. And so, it changed form, the shape of the film.</p>



<p>The last thing was, we met four or five times three, we drank coffee and he told me about his life, it was really intense and there was lots of things you can&#8217;t even imagine because he has such a crazy story. His history was way more important and way more powerful than just a dance, even if I wanted to make dance film, I couldn&#8217;t. The first time I saw him dance was during the shooting of the film. So naturally the dance came out and his history was in the movement, that&#8217;s how it happened.</p>



<p>N: Although you said it didn&#8217;t become a dance film, for me the the part of the film which triggered the most emotion was actually the dancing, like when they go to the club and listen to Ivorian music. That was the bit that really hit me. I think what was cool was that a lot of films are about a migrants pain and the struggle and they never show how they can still enjoy themselves, still have reasonable life where you can have fun and dance and drink. I thought that was a really powerful moment.</p>



<p>L: Thank you, that&#8217;s great. I think the topic of the film is not even about migration, it&#8217;s like a sub topic. The real topic is you&#8217;re carrying stuff, you know bad stuff, everyone has shitty experiences, sadness.. pain.. maybe your girlfriend broken up with you, maybe something happened to your family. Everyone carries something you know? We are all doing things&#8230; to escape. And so the story of Mamadou is the story of a guy who is trying to be released from some shitty things in his life and is trying to create steps, trying to move past times where he was stuck. Sometimes when we spoke you could tell his mind drifted to his past. So he is moving away from his past you know, from what is bad in his life.</p>



<p>Dance was the link, the bridge between pure presence and home. When you dance, you are present, you are drawing the present moment and you are living it fully &#8211; and at the same moment, for him, dance was representing his native country, listening to Ivorian music, he was thinking about his origin and not in a negative way, not about the police, murder or of his migration. He was thinking about his nature and simply enjoying it. The purity of his home, not just the bad memories.</p>



<p>N: That&#8217;s such a good point. Even listening to you explain it to me makes me already see it in a new light. How long did the film take to make, what was the process of that?</p>



<p>L: So as I said there were the strikes in France. Things were kind of slow, the pace and the progression of the film. Instead of just seeing him in like two weeks, it took us like maybe a month and a half to talk, because it was all so slow in France. I had to cycle an hour to go see him and yeah, at the same time he was kind of scared. A big stress was when he found that he couldn&#8217;t have his documents. There was maybe three weeks where he was not really talking to me, was super afraid to go out. He was speaking about going back to Ivory Coast&#8230;it was super, super hard for him. So, yeah, I would say two, two or three months of progression. And then, it was, three days of shooting.</p>



<p>N: Are you still speaking to Mamadou? Are you still in contact?</p>



<p>L: Yeah! We still talk to each other&#8230; on my phone sometimes I call him and stuff, but it&#8217;s difficult right now because everything is closed in France, so we have nowhere to meet. We had to talk a lot before the film, to get him comfortable and confident because it was a big film set. I wanted him to forget the camera.</p>



<p>N: Well congratulations it really worked, I thought you would&#8217;ve spent a lot longer than you did shooting, for him to be that comfortable.</p>



<p>L: To create that we had to go to lots of places, maybe one hour in one place, then move on&#8230;. to give the impression that it was over a longer period. So if you look at the film there is many different scenes that are super short. There were many different settings to give the feel that it was a long time.</p>



<p> The last thing I just wanted to say with DJAO&#8230; it was just super important to involve Mamadou, we can&#8217;t do these kind of films without that. If you want people to be be intimate with you, if you want people to give you access to some places, if you want to be people to be comfortable with you and to make the film, you have to make them the centre of the creative process.</p>



<p>N: So were you incorporating his ideas and opinions throughout?</p>



<p>L: Exactly, from the beginning the contract was &#8220;WE are making a film together&#8221;. So it&#8217;s your film. I&#8217;m just putting it into my city, my point of view of you, but it&#8217;s yours, your film. I think it&#8217;s super important to do that because if I didn&#8217;t do that, it&#8217;s just one random guy filming another guy with my subjectivity. If you give them ownership, people will get more involved and give you access to their real life and won&#8217;t play a role. So now I&#8217;m just a tool, you know. I think it was important for this part of the creative process.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with Loïc&#8217;s work, follow their<a href="https://www.instagram.com/loicphil_/" data-type="URL"> Instagram</a>.</div>



<p></p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../djao/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Doccu&shy;mentary &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;DJAO by Loïc Phil&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Docu&#173;ment&#173;ary / Spencer Mac&#173;donald: Scarlet Medusa</title>
		<link>./../../../scarlet-medusa/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=scarlet-medusa</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 08 Feb 2021 14:57:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Spencer Macdonald]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1455</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap>At the edge of a coastal tourist town in Japan, an aging scientist works to unlock the biological<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> secret of immortality held in the life cycle of a tiny jellyfish</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4>. Watch Spencer Macdonald's short film "Scarlet Medusa" and read below to find out about his filmmaking process ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../scarlet-medusa/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;ment&shy;ary &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Spencer Mac&shy;donald: &lt;br&gt;Scarlet Medusa&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<div id="vimeoyo" style="position:relative;"><iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/449242504?color=d42929&amp;title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0" style="position:absolute;top:0;left:0;height:100%;" frameborder="0" allow="autoplay; fullscreen; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen=""></iframe></div><script src="https://player.vimeo.com/api/player.js"></script>



<p><em>At the edge of a coastal tourist town in Japan, an aging scientist works to unlock the biological secret of immortality held in the life cycle of a tiny jellyfish&#8230;&#8230;Watch Spencer Macdonald&#8217;s short film &#8220;Scarlet Medusa&#8221; above and read below to find out about his filmmaking process.</em></p>



<p>Some years ago I read an article in the&nbsp;New York Times&nbsp;about an immortal jellyfish and an eccentric Japanese scientist who has dedicated his life to determining how to harness its power for humanity and himself. So many of my interests were tied together in this subject and I thought: “a film needs to be made about this”. So I pitched the idea to&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/avocadosandcoconuts/">avocadosandcoconuts</a>, who agreed very generously to produce it, and we set off to japan about two years ago to make the film.</p>



<p>As with most film projects, I embarked with the goal of making a masterpiece. In this case, one that would tie together immortality, our relationship with the natural world, mysticism, the deep sea, space, etc… Surely an easy task.</p>



<p>I labored over the edit for months, never quite getting the visceral feeling in my body that I expect when I dedicate that much time into an edit. Many times I even reconsidered what I was doing making films in the first place. Eventually I came to realize I had to finish the film to let that part of me go. What a tremendous release that was.</p>



<p>I look at the completed film now, and although it is not exactly what I set out to make, I realize that in the process of making it, I have laid the foundation for the type of films that I will make in the future.</p>



<p>I wasn’t sure I wanted to share this film with everyone. I often get overly protective and hyper critical of my work because it is challenging to think that others might perceive it as a reflection of me. But, in the end it is refreshing to see something I worked so hard on being well received out in the world. It was great to see the film premiere on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/nowness/">Nowness</a>, and get featured by some platforms I respect including&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/directorslibrary/">Directors Library</a>.</p>



<p>I’m forever grateful to everyone involved who dedicated their time, talent and resources (<a href="https://www.instagram.com/littleburde/">littleburde</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/kitonga/">kitonga</a>,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/drewkass/">drewkass</a>, Chris Martin,&nbsp;<a href="https://www.instagram.com/chef.mowgli/">chef.mowgli</a>, and many more).&nbsp;</p>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with Spencer’s work, follow him on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/spenceymac/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a> or <a href=" https://vimeo.com/spencermacdonald
/" data-type="URL">Vimeo</a>, and check out his <a href=" http://spencemac.com/work data-type=" url"="">website</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../scarlet-medusa/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Docu&shy;ment&shy;ary &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Spencer Mac&shy;donald: &lt;br&gt;Scarlet Medusa&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview / Phoebe Lang&#173;ley: From; Jordan</title>
		<link>./../../../phoebe-langley/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=phoebe-langley</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Mon, 18 Jan 2021 00:59:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Film]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Joelle Robinson]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=844</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> We sat down with filmmaker Phoebe Langley Gussin on her latest <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> documentary ‘and Now What? - From, Jordan’. This short piece was commissioned by<span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> Roundhouse Theatre and is a time capsule made for a friend, Jordan, a 21-year-old male from South London at the ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../phoebe-langley/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Interview &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Phoebe Lang&shy;ley: From; Jordan&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure id="widevideo" class="wp-block-video"><video controls poster="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/fromjordanposterimg.jpg" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/From-Jordan.mp4"></video><figcaption>From; Jordan / Phoebe Langley / 2019</figcaption></figure>



<p>We sat down with filmmaker Phoebe Langley Gussin on her latest documentary ‘and Now What? &#8211; From, Jordan’. This short piece was commissioned by the Roundhouse Theatre and is a time capsule made for a friend, Jordan, a 21-year-old male from South London at the beginning of his gender transitioning story. Her film is a soft and honest account of the experience of Jordan navigating transitioning in his hometown.</p>



<p><strong>P:</strong> My name’s Phoebe, I’m a filmmaker, but during COVID I’m a motion graphic designer and work a bit on podcasts with visual design and branding. I’ve been doing that for roughly a year based in South-east London.</p>



<p>It’s my first and only doc I’ve done. We shot in December last year [2019], which feels like a long time ago.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> How was the filming process, did it run smoothly?</p>



<p><strong>P:</strong> It was a little hard actually, I didn&#8217;t know what to expect. But it was funded, and I had mentorship within the Roundhouse. I had a mentor called<strong> Nia Childs</strong> who is also a filmmaker and does documentary-based work, it was really helpful to have her. It was quite a short turn around, we got awarded funding in October and had to show it in December.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong>&nbsp; Did you have an idea before you got the funding?</p>



<p><strong>P:</strong> I had the idea whilst doing a course with them, but it was definitely a huge learning process. I knew during production I wanted to work with people I already knew, as I felt it makes the process easier.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> Where did the subject matter come from?</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>Me and Jordan have been friends for years. We went to school together, so we already had a relationship and then we lost contact, going to different colleges. We then rekindled our friendship and spoke about how we wanted to document his transition, initially not to be shown, it was just for him. We didn’t think it was going to be commissioned or anything, so it’s nice.</p>



<p><strong>J: </strong>&nbsp;In the future would you keep with the same documentary style?</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>I think so yeah, it’s funny right after we screened it a lot of people were like what’s your next thing, but my heart was in this project for so long. I don’t want to make something for the sake of it, I want it to be more organic.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> Definitely, you can kind of tell when a story is close to someone a lot of love goes into it.</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>Making a film on someone else’s life, it’s important to remind yourself that it has to be a collaborative project, it can&#8217;t just be exploiting someone&#8217;s story, that’s not what a documentary is about. Speaking with Jordan he wanted to make this film because when he was younger there was no one on screens that he looked like or he in any way could resonate with so it was one of the main aims of the film. It&#8217;s important to establish that when going forward in making documentary, it’ll be a collaboration.</p>



<p><strong>J</strong>: What was the course at the Roundhouse, perhaps others could benefit from it too?</p>



<p><strong>P: </strong>Yeah the course is amazing! I mean before it I was working in a chocolate factory, It really opened a lot of doors…It’s called the Bloomburg broadcast, hopefully it’s still running. It’s a 6 week course for 18-25 year-olds and all about the life broadcasting they do at the Roundhouse, for producing, editing, you learn so much it&#8217;s great.</p>



<p><strong>J:</strong> That’s amazing, when you have ideas that you really want to execute, having backing from an organization like the Roundhouse is great, and has allowed you to make such a lovely and polished piece. We love it!</p>



<div id="footer">To stay updated about future projects by Phoebe, follow her on <a href="https://www.instagram.com/phoebe_langley/" data-type="URL">Instagram</a> or <a href="https://twitter.com/phoebe_langley?lang=en" data-type="URL">Twitter</a>. Interview by <a href=" ./../../../tag/joelle-robinson/index.html" data-type="URL">Joelle</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../phoebe-langley/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Interview &lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span id=hspan3&gt;Phoebe Lang&shy;ley: From; Jordan&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/01/From-Jordan.mp4" length="265229693" type="video/mp4" />

			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
