<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Hope Oloye - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 23:24:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Hope Oloye - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>POC:STEM / Hope Oloye</title>
		<link>./../../../hope-oloye/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=hope-oloye</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Mar 2021 19:10:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[POC:STEM]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Chulu-Chinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hope Oloye]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=1975</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap>"Hope is a PhD student studying the Neuroscience behind the perception <span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> of music and sound. When not looking at people’s brains, Hope also is the </span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> Founder and Director of Thinking Black, a social enterprise aiming to empower and amplify young black ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../hope-oloye/index.html">&lt;span&gt;POC:&lt;br&gt;STEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Hope Oloye&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Hope is a PhD student studying the Neuroscience behind the perception of music and sound. When not looking at people’s brains (I forgot to ask if she’s ever touched one and what they smell like, sorry everyone), Hope also is the Founder and Director of Thinking Black,&nbsp; a social enterprise aiming to empower and amplify young black voices through education and mentorship. In a wide-ranging discussion, Hope touched upon how money can affect people’s perception of what is “Human” and how the effects of discrimination can effect everything from healthcare to Artificial intelligence.</p>



<p><strong>Tell me about yourself, how did you get to where you are now?</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>I’m from Newham in East London and went to a school that used to be pretty bad….but then got turned around by a “Super-Headteacher”. At 6<sup>th</sup>-form I got pulled aside one day and was told that I should apply for Biology at Oxford University, but I knew that my parents wouldn’t let me study anything but Medicine, Engineering or Law. So my teacher had to pretty much convince my mum that going to Oxford to study Biology was actually pretty good ! After a bit I then switched to neuroscience.</p>



<p>Once I graduated I went to New York &nbsp;where I was a junior research associate in a lab. It was a really cool experience, I helped PhD students set up and run their experiments and had a team of undergrads working under me too which was fun.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="923" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope2020-923x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1977" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope2020-923x1024.jpg 923w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope2020-768x852.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope2020-1384x1536.jpg 1384w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope2020-1320x1465.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope2020.jpg 1846w" sizes="(max-width: 923px) 100vw, 923px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>The research was looking at the neuroscience behind implicit bias, my project was looking at perceptions of economic scarcity and seeing if this perceived scarcity increased a subject’s tendency to discriminate against black people.</p>



<p></p>



<p><strong>How does one set-up an experiment like that ?</strong></p>



<p>We would tell a subject “Due to the economic crash, we’ve reduced the amount of money in a particular fund”. I would then use photoshop to merge people’s faces to create varying levels of features associated with black people. The subject would be presented with the different faces and let them decide how much of the money they would allocate to the different people.</p>



<p>The subjects were placed in an fMRI scanner (used to measure brain activity) while making these decisions. Essentially it was found that the area of the brain that associated with response to faces had a different pattern of activity when looking at black faces when the scarcity manipulation was run. This activity matches what is seen when people are presented with things that are “human-like” or not quite human. The overarching&nbsp; takeaway was that when there is a perception of economic scarcity, white people tend to de-humanise black faces.</p>



<p><strong>Were the subjects of the experiment only white ? It would be interesting to see how black people would react…to see whether the de-humanisation comes from not growing up around people of different races, or if it’s due to the way black people are generally perceived in society.</strong></p>



<p>Yeah, but this is the thing. It was frustrating as it only told half the story and within that we only tested university students, which are obviously a very particular subset of people… white, wealthy, quite liberal…and then make these sweeping statements. I kept asking of we could run the experiment on black people… but unfortunately hit a dead end. It is quite scary how talking about&nbsp; money can affect the way you perceive people, and literally see them as less human.&nbsp; <strong>&nbsp;</strong></p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="768" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1010-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1983" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1010-768x1024.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1010-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1010-1320x1760.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1010.jpg 1537w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>And what about now? What’s your PhD project about?</strong></p>



<p>My PhD is in auditory neuroscience, the science of sound and music and how we perceive them. I work with the Ecological Brain Project (https://ecologicalbrain.org/about/), which tries to conduct studies in real world settings. So instead of having experiments where subjects are in a massive scanner making decisions on how big a circle is, we try to look at people in natural settings making more realistic decisions.</p>



<p><strong>How was your experience studying at Oxford ?</strong></p>



<p>It was&#8230;weird. I met amazing people and neuroscience was interesting and I loved it. But there is a whole lot of white people and not much else. I experienced lots of microaggressions… things like security asking for my ID when I was 10 steps behind a white person who was allowed to go unbothered…or confusing me with the one other black girl in my college and giving her my mail. Just lots of little things that made me feel really visible.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p><strong>So did you feel quite exposed there ?</strong></p>



<p>Exactly! Like I was walking around naked the whole time. Oxford gets lots of tourists and they would sometimes take pictures of me. Once the ACS (African Caribbean Society) was doing a photoshoot for a campaign, and we had a massive group of tourists with their cameras snapping away….</p>



<p>I successfully ran for JCR president (head of the undergraduate student body) so I could “change Oxford from the inside” and worked to write in legislation, start committees and funds, which is how <strong>Thinking Black </strong>was created.</p>



<p><strong>How successful were your attempts after reaching this position of Power ?</strong></p>



<p>I felt that as I was one of the only black people in my college, I had a responsibility to use this position to help other black students, it wasn’t just a box-ticker for my CV and looking back, I think it was successful. We set-up loads of mental health initiatives and wrote in legislations to help students suspend their studies if they were struggling for different reasons. One of the things I’m proud of is helping to set-up a scholarship for asylum seekers living in Britain.</p>



<p>However, there were lots of things where they (the governing body of the college)dragged their heels and slowed down these changes. They know that you’re only in this position for one year, and it seemed that sometimes they were just hoping for me to give up and move on.The people who run the college are mainly white men who deny or at least feign ignorance when told that the college had a race problem. They would say things like “No-one’s ever raised an issue before”…Look around ! It’s because you all look the same! That’s the problem!</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>What is Thinking Black ?</strong></p>



<p>Thinking Black is an educational project for young black students with the goal being to support and uplift young black voices, which I founded while studying at Oxford. We’re trying to provide skills training to black students, lessons in writing, public speaking and lectures in art history in an effort to empower them to communicate in lots of different forms and give them the confidence to do so.</p>



<p>I’m a neuroscientist but I love other things like art and reading, and these are skills, which can be employed in any setting. As a young Nigerian I never considered a more creative career as being something I could do, or even why it would be hobby that was worthwhile doing. I think that through the act of doing these kinds of subjects you can learn so much. The education we provide is centred around black academics and content that relates to black people.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="714" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope3-714x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1985" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope3-714x1024.jpg 714w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope3-768x1101.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope3-1071x1536.jpg 1071w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope3-1320x1893.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope3.jpg 1429w" sizes="(max-width: 714px) 100vw, 714px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>For example if you look at the way that black people are depicted in art in the past couple of centuries, you can start to unpack the ways that black people are depicted in modern times too. It is kind of arty but we do science stuff too. We also need to talk about race in health science, race in AI and how climate change effects black and indigenous groups.</p>



<p><strong>Definitely, I think now more than ever race is involved in science. You mentioned AI and healthcare, the possibility of people encoding racial bias into an algorithm which could be used to identify criminals is insane (</strong><a href="https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03186-4"><strong>https://www.nature.com/articles/d41586-020-03186-4</strong></a><strong>), while there is a mountain of evidence of how black people can be discriminated against when accessing healthcare.</strong></p>



<p>There are so may devastating things that make this obvious, such as increased maternal mortality in ethnic minorities. How race can affect how people are treated… there are obviously sometimes very good reasons for it but it definitely needs to be assessed and re-examined. When you look at the history of medicine, some of these ideas and theories can be traced back to Eugenics.</p>



<p><strong>When you say you didn’t consider more creative subjects “As a young Nigerian”, do you mean in a sense that it was your upbringing that prevented you, not the fact that you are black and would therefore have less opportunities than your white counterparts.</strong></p>



<p>I think its both. Obviously the classic lack of representation and role models growing up does not help, but it was also definitely the Nigerian and possibly generally immigrant family attitude of wanting financial security for their children. My dad literally sat me down and said I shouldn’t consider certain types of jobs as “black people won’t flourish”, he said what I need is education and security. That’s why they love vocational jobs, once you get that qualification, that degree, nobody can take that away from you. I think it comes from being protective and a fear of their children failing due to the odds being stacked against them, and us as children internalise that fear.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="768" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1-1-768x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1993" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1-1-768x1024.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1-1-1152x1536.jpg 1152w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1-1-1320x1760.jpg 1320w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/hope1-1.jpg 1537w" sizes="(max-width: 768px) 100vw, 768px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p><strong>What do you have on at the moment and what’s next for Thinking Black?</strong></p>



<p><strong>&nbsp;</strong>We just finished our year 12 writing project, where they had a batch of lectures and seminars and then wrote up their essays. We had different modules on health and equality, racial justice, climate change, art and culture and black feminism… it was really cool. &nbsp;</p>



<p>We’ve got funding from my Oxford College to fund prizes and competitions and are expanding into different subjects and ideas. We’re working towards researching wider inequalities between students of different races, and it would be amazing to present the findings to different educational bodies so that they could use that sort of data to make real change, in a sense we’re working towards making projects like Thinking Black obsolete!</p>
</div>
</div>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with Hope and her work, follow her <a href="https://www.instagram.com/hope_myname/" data-type="URL"> Instagram</a>, along with <a href="https://www.instagram.com/thinkingblk/" data-type="URL"> Thinking Black</a>. You can also check out their website<a href="https://www.thinkingblack.co.uk/" data-type="URL"> here</a>.</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../hope-oloye/index.html">&lt;span&gt;POC:&lt;br&gt;STEM&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Hope Oloye&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
