<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kimberly Hoyle - SUM</title>
	<atom:link href="./index.html" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<description>SUMweekly</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 18 Mar 2021 19:16:23 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.9</generator>

<image>
	<url>./../../../wp-content/uploads/2020/12/cropped-SUMKINGZ-01-32x32.png</url>
	<title>Kimberly Hoyle - SUM</title>
	<link>./../../../index.html</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Inter&#173;view / Kim&#173;berly Hoyle: Scot-Ish?</title>
		<link>./../../../kimberley-hoyle/index.html?utm_source=rss&#038;utm_medium=rss&#038;utm_campaign=kimberley-hoyle</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[farrantjames97]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 14 Mar 2021 13:51:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Articles]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Noah Chulu-Chinn]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Kimberly Hoyle]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">./../../../index.html?p=2192</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[<div id=spanwrap> If you’re from a city like London, you can forget that not every part of the UK<span id=span1> ...</span><span id=span2> and Europe is such a melting pot of cultures and ethnicities. School trips outside of</span><span id=span3> ...</span><span id=span4> the capital can be stark reminders that in many parts of the western world, the presence of a ...</span></div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kimberley-hoyle/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Inter&shy;view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kim&shy;berly Hoyle: Scot-Ish?&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you’re from a city like London, you can forget that not every part of the UK and Europe is a melting pot of cultures and ethnicities. School trips outside of the capital can be stark reminders that in many parts of the western world, the presence of a person of colour can still garner curiosity and on some occasions genuine hostility.</p>



<p>Originating from Edinburgh, Kimberley Hoyle moved to London in 2016 to pursue a career in the performing arts, experiencing a massive change in her local demographics as a result (8.3% of the Edinburgh population are non-white, compared to 40.2% of London’s population). We sat down with Kimberley to hear about how her experiences differed from that of a Londoner, and how the recent BLM movement allowed her to be better equipped to look back at her childhood with a more critical and informed gaze.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns collapse-above-right">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>Noah: Hey! So tell me a bit about yourself, what are you doing at the moment? </p>



<p>Kimberly: Ha well right now I’m doing ab-so-lute-ly nothing… but if it wasn’t for Covid I’d be auditioning, taping, trying to get a performing job. I grew up in Edinburgh and moved to London in 2016 after doing a year at a performing arts school just outside of Glasgow. I wouldn’t really put myself down as being just a “dancer”, but that’s what I grew doing and have most experience in at the moment.</p>



<p>My Dad grew up in Edinburgh and has family from England, while my Mum is originally from Nigeria and move here when she was around 14. Growing up in Edinburgh was fine for me, I never envisioned myself moving away so young. My sister was always the more confident one who was going to be the singer, I was shyer… just plodding along.</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img width="683" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly1-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2196" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly1-683x1024.jpg 683w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly1-768x1152.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly1.jpg 828w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>N: What was it like being a mix-raced child growing up, I can’t imagine you were one of many?&nbsp;</p>



<p>K: So there really weren’t many non-white kids around me, I’m pretty sure me and my sister were the only children of African heritage in primary school, until around the age of 8 when a mix-raced girl called Katie joined. The fact that I know her name (she wasn’t in the same year) kind of shows how that there really wasn’t anyone else that looked like us.</p>



<p>In High School I honestly can’t remember if there were any black or mix-race pupils, but each time I come back to Edinburgh now it seems more and more diverse. In my head I wonder if it was really was like that when I was young&#8230;in school, you just stay with the same group of friends in the same area, maybe there were other people like me but I just never realised. It’s only when you reach 17 or 18 that you start to go out and explore a bit more of the city, but I only had a year of that until I moved down to London.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="683" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly6-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2198" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly6-683x1024.jpg 683w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly6-768x1151.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly6.jpg 828w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>N: Were you conscious of the fact that you were the only person of colour around in your school?<br><br>K: I think it was easy to ignore until I was about 14 or 15. If you had asked me a couple years ago, I would have said that I didn’t experience any racism and school was generally fine for me. But after educating myself in recent years I can say that I definitely did experience prejudice, maybe I did feel hurt after things were said or done, maybe I just pushed it down as I was the minority, and these things were being said by my friends and peers.&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The BLM movement helped me understand what words like micro-aggressions and colourism meant, and after posting about it I did have friends from home who reached out to have a discussion about their part in not only being racist but also not calling it out. Some assured me that they would never allow their children to get away with the things that they said to me, which I think is much better than apologising for the racist joke they said 5 years ago when they were 16.</p>
</div>
</div>



<p>N: I think it’s hard at that age to turn around and say to your friends that their joke was racist, you don’t want to make your hurt obvious and call them out for it. I definitely still struggle to have a voice and call people out if they’re not my close friends.</p>



<p>K: I’m not sure how badly I was affected by it all and I wouldn’t say I had a bad childhood because of my race or anything, I&#8217;m still incredibly proud to be Scottish. I know people that have experienced a lot of racism and had a shit time, I wouldn’t say that’s me. I can definitely remember specific times where I was genuinely hurt, comments like “You’re fit for a black girl” and “When you go black you never go back” of course affected me and made me feel uncomfortable.</p>



<div class="wp-block-columns">
<div class="wp-block-column">
<p>I can’t speak for every person of colour who went to my school before or afterwards, and I can’t speak for everyone who has been through the Scottish school system, but my personal experience was generally positive…apart from the occasional “joke”.</p>



<p>There was a thing about a hoodie. I was really into gymnastics when I was younger, and you know Jackie Chan, he’s got all the moves and is big in Karate or whatever. For my leavers hoodie I had “Blackie Chan” printed on the back&#8230;because it was a friend’s nickname for me.<br><br>N: I know you implied that adults weren’t really complicit what you experienced and that it was your friends jokes that made you feel uncomfortable. but for me that shows that adults were definitely aware of what you were experiencing. Surely your teacher saw that hoodie, they printed it for you after all?</p>
</div>



<div class="wp-block-column">
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img loading="lazy" width="683" height="1024" src="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly4-1-683x1024.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-2203" srcset="./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly4-1-683x1024.jpg 683w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly4-1-768x1152.jpg 768w, ./../../../wp-content/uploads/2021/03/kimberly4-1.jpg 828w" sizes="(max-width: 683px) 100vw, 683px" /></figure>
</div>
</div>



<p>K: That is true, a lot of the names that were handed in were not allowed by the teachers. Maybe It was because the name was from me, it was my submission, so they thought it wouldn’t be their place to tell me not to have such a racist name printed? I’m not sure what their thought process was but looking back I do think that it shouldn’t have been allowed.</p>



<p>This is the first time I’ve really looked back and spoken about growing up in Edinburgh, looking back on it with a more informed lens. With my friends who spoke to me during the BLM movement, I always tried to say that if I can take control and educate myself, so can they. Not being around people of colour isn’t an excuse to not learn about their experiences in our country. You’re in a bubble regarding any issue, both physical and digital, but all the relevant information is out there… you might just need a little nudge in the right direction.</p>



<div id="footer"> 
To keep up with Kimberley and her work, follow her on<a href="https://www.instagram.com/kimberleyhoyle/?hl=en"> Instagram</a>.
</div>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../kimberley-hoyle/index.html">&lt;span&gt;Inter&shy;view&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan2&gt; /&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span id=hspan3&gt; Kim&shy;berly Hoyle: Scot-Ish?&lt;/span&gt;</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="./../../../index.html">SUM</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
